Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God, our regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday,
as we find it written in Paul's letter to the Romans, the 12th chapter, particularly the 21st verse.
Be not overcome of evil, but overcome evil with good.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, our strength and our Redeemer, dear friends,
you Christian friends who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Station WMRN was just three years old at the time.
It was then that I had a burning desire to broadcast our Sunday morning worship service
so that the sick and the shut-ins of this community might share in that experience with us.
We investigated the matter quite thoroughly.
We discovered, first of all, what it would cost to broadcast the service,
and then to find out also whether the time was available.
Then, when we realized that this was a possibility,
it was the late Raymond Roker, a member of our congregation,
that came to my house early one Monday morning and handed me $500
and said, let's get started and let's see what happens.
The first broadcast went out from this church on the last Sunday in January in the year 1943.
Today, as you and I know, is the last Sunday in January of the year 1963.
Twenty years have come and gone since that first broadcast from this Christian congregation.
And I suppose most of us have been saying, well, what shall we do today?
Shall we do something different than what we have done in the past twenty years?
And I'm sure the thing for us to do today is to do what we have done each Sunday,
and that is to turn to the Word of God, to pick our text there,
and to bring the Word of life as it has been brought from this pulpit for the last twenty years.
You recall that we have been taking our text from the twelfth chapter of Romans for the past two Sundays,
and in this twelfth chapter, the Apostle Paul has been reminding us
that we have seen and we have tasted of the mercies of God,
and to be sure, we have said that we have, because we have been to Bethlehem,
and we have seen the Christ child, the gift of God to this world,
and we have seen Christ as the epiphany light, not only for the Jewish world,
but also for the Gentile world as well.
And then you recall that two weeks ago, Paul said to us,
now that we have seen and we have tasted of the mercies of God,
Paul said, let us be transformed, let us be new men and women,
let us be changed men and women, let our lives be different from the lives of worldly men.
And then last Sunday in the twelfth chapter of Romans,
Paul was talking to us again about the grace and the mercy of God,
assuring us that by the grace of God, you and I have been given talents,
different talents to be sure,
but talents nevertheless.
And so the call last Sunday was this, on the basis of God's word,
let's use to their full the talents that God has given us,
even though they are different from the talents that God has given to any other individual.
And today in the concluding verses of the Romans, the twelfth chapter,
St. Paul speaks to us in the word of God and he calls on us and he tells us
that we who are Christians, we who have tasted of the mercies of God,
he says, be not overcome of evil, but overcome evil with good.
We may say, what's he talking about?
Well, the fact that we are not to be overcome by evil,
we know exactly what he means by this evil in its context.
And this evil we find is this that he has special reference to,
the evil of a spirit of revenge in our hearts.
Paul says, do not let a spirit of revenge conquer you.
Do not let a spirit within you that means to get even with everybody who has done you wrong.
Do not let a spirit of revenge within you whereby you say,
I'm going to repay an evil deed with an evil deed.
Paul says, do not let that kind of an evil conquer you.
But he says, you conquer that evil, you conquer that spirit of revenge in doing good,
in repaying an evil deed with a good deed.
Mind you, Christian friends, this is the call of the word of God,
that you and I are to see to it that a spirit of revenge,
a spirit of sweet revenge shall be conquered in us
and that we shall do it in this way,
that we shall repay an evil deed, not with another evil deed,
that we shall repay an evil deed, not by doing nothing,
but by doing something,
and that is by doing a good turn.
We may say to ourselves this morning, that's ridiculous.
When you think about it, we say, yes, Christians,
you mean to say that I am to repay an evil turn,
a bad turn with a good one?
Do you mean to say that that is my obligation as a Christian?
We may say to ourselves, that's ridiculous, that is utterly silly.
We may conclude why it's silly because you've got everything to lose
and you haven't got a thing to gain.
We may say to ourselves, what good is it to repay an evil deed with a good deed,
that I am to go out of my way to conquer the desire within my heart
that I'm going to return a man tit for tat and that I'm going to do him a good deed
in exchange for something evil that he has done for me?
We may say, that doesn't pay.
We may also say, if that's Christianity, I don't want any of it.
We may say, if that's Christian psychology, that's for the birds.
That is not for me because somehow or other, isn't it strange,
when we are told that we are to overcome evil with good,
that we are to stifle a spirit of revenge
by a real deed of kindness to somebody who has harmed us,
we say, well, you're going to lose everything
and you can't gain a thing.
I wonder if on this 20th anniversary of radio broadcast
and as we turn to the word of God,
whether we can't just look at it for a moment and see,
whether this isn't Christianity at its best
as we apply it into our practical Christian life,
whether this isn't the very finest thing
that when God Almighty says to you and me,
overcome evil with good,
repay a bad turn with a good one,
do something and let it be something positive,
something fine and something good.
You and I have everything to gain
and really nothing to lose.
What is there to lose?
When in the first place, God would remind us of this,
that God repaid a very evil deed,
a very bad turn with a real good turn
in the Garden of Eden.
Do you remember?
Let's go back to the creation of the world
and go back to the Garden of Eden
when the Lord God, when he had brought into existence
this universe by the power of his word
and God had decreed that this universe
was going to be created for a being
that he was going to call man,
that God was going to put on this earth
a creature called man,
that God might love that creature
and that that creature in turn might love him.
And so we read that the Lord God formed man
of the dust of the ground.
God formed our bodies
and what a marvelous form it was
and not after his image
because God doesn't have a body
but God breathed into man's nostrils,
now nose holes, the breath of life
and man became a living soul.
We are made in the image of God
because God is a spirit,
God is a soul
and God made you and me a soul
and God made us with free will
that we might choose to love him
or that we might choose not to love him.
And there was a greater creation
that God had also made
and they were the angels
and some of those angels with free will
had chosen not to serve God.
And our God then,
he created man that man might love him
and that man might live in righteousness
and holiness
and that God might love man.
And when the test came,
what happened in Eden?
You and I know that our parents,
when they were tempted of Satan,
they chose not to love God
with all their heart, soul and mind
and they chose therefore
to be gods themselves
and they disobeyed God.
It was a dirty deal
and a dirty trick
that man gave God
in exchange for God's good turn.
But what did God do?
Was there a spirit of revenge in God
that he gloated and he said,
Oh, I'm glad you did it.
There is a spirit of sweet revenge in me.
I am tickled to death,
Adam and Eve,
that you sinned
because now I can pounce on you
and I can make your life
as miserable as I possibly can.
Did God gloat over it?
Did God return it tit for tat?
When you stand in Eden's garden
and the Lord God turned to them,
what was it?
He returned in exchange
for that evil turn.
God gave them a good turn
because when God spoke to Satan
and Adam and Eve,
the first gospel was proclaimed.
In Genesis the third chapter,
the 15th verse,
when God says,
And I will put enmity between thee and the woman,
between thy seed and her seed.
It shall bruise thy head
and thou shalt bruise his heel.
And the whole Bible
is an unfolding of that glorious verse
that when God says,
I'll give you another chance.
There was a good turn.
God said,
From you Eve will come
the seed of the woman,
the Savior and the Redeemer
who would come and suffer
and die for the sins of the world.
And in him you will have life
and everlasting salvation.
There was a glorious good turn
given by God in Eden
for an evil turn.
And therefore you say,
Well, we've got everything to lose
and nothing to gain.
Oh, friend, that isn't true.
Here is Christianity at its best
because when you and I
are going to conquer
a spirit within us
whereby we have filled,
our hearts filled with revenge,
and we're going to again
exchange a man tit for tat,
and we're going to even the score
regardless of what it means,
when we realize that God
exchanged a real good turn
for an evil one,
then and only then
can we have the joy
when we do likewise
that the faith within you and me
is a living faith.
It's not a debtor
than a doornail faith.
Many a man can get up
and assent to the creed.
Many a man can say
that he believes in God
as Father
and in Jesus Christ
and he believes in the Holy Spirit.
But you know and I know
that unless that faith
shows itself in your life
and mine,
unless you and I
can look and say,
Here is a faith
that is active,
unless,
let's put it right down
to brass stacks
unless you can look
in your life
and I can look at mine,
that there is a conquering
within our own hearts
of a spirit of revenge
whereby we repay
an evil deed
with a good one,
whereby we go out
of our way
to do a kindness
to somebody
who has injured us.
You and I
have no evidence
that our faith is living,
that we have been
blood-bought in Jesus Christ
and that we have been
saved unto eternal life.
Show me a Christian
who is willing again
to repay an evil deed
with a good one
and I'll show you one
who can say my faith
is living
and I know I have been
saved from hell
and damnation
and I know that
in the blood of Jesus Christ
shed on Calvary,
life and eternal salvation
have become,
I know,
and I ask you this moment,
what do you lose?
Listen,
this is Christianity
in its finest hour
in its practical application.
This is Christianity
in its very finest dress.
God Almighty assures
you and me,
says we are to overcome evil,
a spirit of revenge
and to overcome it
by doing good.
We must repay
an evil turn
with a good turn.
That's Christianity
and you have everything
to gain
and nothing to lose
and that's why
this is the 20th anniversary
of the broadcasting
of the word of God
and on this day
we ought to say to ourselves
if that's what God wants,
that's what God
shall get from my life
and when we have determined
that we are going to
conquer evil
in our lives,
a spirit of revenge
by in every case
when somebody
does us a dirty trick
that we shall respond
with a good deed,
then and only then
can you and I
ever avoid
having the spirit
of revenge
conquer us.
Old Paul says,
don't let a spirit
of revenge
conquer you.
I wonder how many of us
in church
or on the radio
have really allowed
a spirit of revenge
to conquer us.
How many of us
are dominated
by a spirit
of revenge?
I'll get even
if it's the last thing
I ever do
and we gloat over it
and I'll get even
with a dirty deal
that somebody
has given me
and as long as
there's breath
in my body
I'll pay him back
coin for coin
and I'll give him
the same deal
that he has given me.
How many of us
are complete slaves
of again
a desire for revenge?
It's tragic.
Look at the life
of Moses
what he paid.
Moses had a hot temper
and remember
when he was out
one day
and he saw
an Egyptian
whipping a Hebrew
and Moses again
allowed his temper
to flare
and there was
a spirit of revenge
and he killed
a man right on the spot
and threw him
in the gutter
and he covered him up.
He thought nobody
saw it
but the next day
when two Hebrews
were arguing
and Moses tried
to quiet them
the one Hebrew
said you're going
to kill me
or you're going
to kill us
like you killed
that Egyptian
yesterday.
Moses had to flee
for his life
and don't forget
he spent 40 years
out in the Midian desert.
Why?
Because there was
a spirit of revenge.
Oh you read
in the papers
you wonder
how in the world
can a father
and a mother
how can they
take a little infant
child and just
beat its literal
brains out?
How can they
take a little child
because it cries
in a spirit
of revenge
whip it
so it's black
and blue
and fracture
it's scald
and you read
it every week.
Why?
Because there are
people whose
spirit of revenge
controls them
who are slaves
and how many
husbands
because a wife
leaves them
for good reason
or for not
good reason
will turn around
and kill the children
kill the wife
and the father-in-law
and the mother-in-law
go out with no end
because revenge
seems sweet.
Her wives
doing the same thing.
What a price
and what a tragedy
and yet men say
revenge is sweet
revenge is costly
and it is tragic.
Let's get also
down in every congregation
oh this happens
to every minister
many a time
I'm called
to see somebody
and I'm told
that the person
is a Lutheran
and I say
I don't know you
where did you belong?
Then you get a story
something
I belonged
about 40 years ago
to a Lutheran church
but the minister
said something
that hurt my feelings
or somebody
did something
real or imaginary
and so I withdrew
then you see
a person
lying on a sick bed
and on a death bed
been filled
and conquered
with a spirit
of revenge
living their lives
in revenge
and in resentment
shriveled souls
that have done
nothing miserable
then there's also
the member
that because
of a spirit
of revenge
if he thinks
he isn't getting
a just deal
he stays away
from church
and he hopes
that everybody
notices it
because that goes
with this gloating
of revenge
and God pity
if you don't
notice it
then he gets angry
because you don't
notice his spirit
of revenge
how silly
can you and I
get with a
shriveled up soul
oh the shriveled
souls we find
in the name of
Jesus
because men
have allowed
a spirit
of revenge
I'll get even
to conquer
their lives
and the tragedy
of it all is
you lose
your eternal life
shriveled souls
lying on sick beds
ready for death
whose lives
have counted
for nothing
because revenge
seems so sweet
it's the most
damnable bitter
taste
that could ever
come to your
soul and mine
this is Christianity
at its best
strange what
creatures we are
that we say
revenge is so
sweet that if
this is Christianity
that I must
return an evil
turn with a good
one that it's
not for me
that I've got
everything to lose
and nothing to gain
oh it isn't so
it's Christianity
at its best
in its finest
hour
why
God Almighty
says you've
tasted of the
mercies of God
and God says
overcome evil
with good
mind you
I am to overcome
that spirit
of resentment
within me
of a vengeance
and the spirit
of revenge
not by
repaying an evil
deed with
another evil
deed
or not even
by saying
well I'll just
do nothing
that isn't it
God says
by doing
something
something that
is good
you just
don't sit
like a bump
on a log
you do
something
and you do
kind
it's
Christianity
at its best
you have
nothing to lose
and everything
to gain
why
because in the
second place
God reminds
you and me
that he will
repay every
evil turn
that any man
has ever done
against you
and me
you know
sometimes we
may get the
wrong idea
when Paul
says
dearly beloved
he says
avenge not
yourselves
but rather
give place
to wrath
he says
let God
take care
of this
thing
because God
says
and Paul
quotes the
Old Testament
he says
God says
vengeance is
mine
that belongs
to me
that's in
my field
that's my
prerogative
I will
repay
I'll take
care of
this
you know
sometimes we
may get
the idea
well I'm
not going
to take
revenge
I'm going
to let
God do
it
and then we
picture God
as a revengeful
God who has
a taste for
blood
who gloats
will you
bear this
in mind
that God
said this
as I live
saith the
Lord
God swears
by himself
because there
is no one
greater by
whom he
could swear
but God
takes an oath
and God
says
as I live
I swear
by my
existence
that I
have no
pleasure
in the
death of
the wicked
don't let
any man
ever tell
you that
God has
a spirit
of revenge
that God
gloats
in seeing
the soul
lost
don't let
any man
ever tell
you I'm
going to
let God
take care
of this
and boy
oh boy
when God
gets through
with somebody
in his
spirit of
revenge
he can do
a lot
worse
things
than I
that
isn't
true
God's
vengeance
is his
justice
and God's
yes
it's an
eye for
an eye
and it's
a tooth
for a tooth
but it's
a justice
that is
administered
in sadness
it is a
justice
that would
rather
administer
grace
God
says
I'll
take
care
of the
wrongs
that men
have done
you let
me do
that
and God
says
that's my
prerogative
though the
mills of
God grind
slowly
they grind
exceedingly
fine
and God
reminds you
and me
that he
doesn't
balance
books
every day
you know
you and I
would like
to balance
them every
day
right now
if somebody
again
comes back
at us
with an
evil deed
we're ready
to repay
with the
same
thing
God
says
overcome
evil
with good
what's the
joy
what is there
to gain
listen
a God
who is
big enough
who promises
you and me
that he will
repay every
evil deed
that any man
has done
against us
and do it
in judgment
not in gloating
not in a
spiritual revenge
is a God
that gives us
this joy
that he is able
to keep this
promise
that he will
overrule
every evil
turn
in your
life
and mine
and make
it a good
one
you realize
that God
says
a reversal
will take
place
in your
life
if you
will
trust
me
in other
words
let's put
it
just like
this
when any
man
does you
and me
an evil
turn
he's actually
doing us
a favor
he is
actually
doing us
a favor
we express
it some
ways
like this
we say
a knocks
a boost
it is
as a
Christian
why
God
promises
that every
evil
action
of any
man
against you
and me
every
evil
word
any
kind
of
retribution
God
says
I will
overrule
it
for your
good
you and
I can
say
how can
you
overrule
an evil
turn
make it
a good
one
well I'll
give you
the greatest
reversal
that ever
took place
in human
history
stand at
Calvary
for the
moment
if you
want to
see a
reversal
if there
was ever
a dirty
deal
if there
was ever
a dirty
indignity
if there
was ever
a mean
turn
it was
the fact
that men
murdered
the son
of God
on no
basis
was there
any
justification
for
crucifying
Jesus
Christ
they
couldn't
find
anything
they put
him to
death
because
they hated
him
without
cause
he was
the
innocent
man
as the
world
still
says
that it
was the
greatest
life
that was
ever
lived
it was
the most
holy
life
and therefore
if there
ever
was an
evil
turn
that
was
it
and yet
God
reversed
that evil
turn
and made
it a good
one
why
because
you and
I
stand
at
Calvary
and we
say
it was
an
evil
turn
but
God
has
reversed
it
because
there's
the
hope
of the
world
there
is
the
place
where
Christ
bought
and
saved
you
and
me
from
hell
and
damnation
there
is
where
he
bore
the
equal
of
eternity
in
hell
greater
reversal
ever
existed
and that's
why
in your
life
and mine
when we
think
that someone
who has
done us
an evil
deed
has done
something
that God
almighty
can't
reverse
look to
Calvary
there was
the greatest
reversal
that
Calvary
again
is the
reversal
of an
evil
turn
to a
good
one
it's
your
hope
and
mine
for
eternal
life
and
for
everlasting
salvation
God
reversed
it
take
the case
of
Joseph
talk
about
reversal
you can
see it
in his
life
he had
ten
brothers
that put
him down
in a
bottomless
hole
it was
waterless
and they
were going
to allow
him to
starve
to death
and to
thirst
to death
then they
decided to
sell him
into slavery
which they
did in spite
of his
pleas
down into
Egypt
a man
by the
name of
Potiphar
bought him
as a
slave
put him
in his
home
Potiphar's
wife fell
in love
with him
rather than
sin with
her
what
happened
Joseph
ended up
in jail
there he
was in jail
for several
years
until finally
some dreams
came to
Pharaoh
and one
of the
men who
had been
in jail
with
Joseph
remembered
that he
could
interpret
dreams
and God
what
reversed
the
indignities
in the
life
of
Joseph
so that
by means
of
Joseph
who
became
the
prime
minister
in
Egypt
many
souls
were
saved
in
the
famine
that
hit
the
land
reversal
oh your
life and
mine
may not
be as
dramatic
as that
as
Joseph
but we
can know
this
that here
is
Christianity
at its
best
there
isn't
anything
to lose
there
is
everything
to gain
when you
and I
conquer a
spirit
of revenge
in doing
good
in repaying
an evil
turn with
a good
one
God
says
I'll
overrule
every
indignity
for your
eternal
welfare
and let's
let God
do it
God's
big enough
to do it
and on
this 20th
anniversary
when we
talk about
what do
you do
on an
anniversary
well again
you do
the same
thing you
have done
throughout
20 years
you turn
to the
word of
God
and the
word of
God
speaks to
you and
me
and says
we are
to overcome
evil
with good
there ought
to be a
determination
then that we
say this
that as a
Christian
this is
Christianity
at its best
since you've
got everything
to gain
nothing to
lose
since it
actually
pays
there ought
to be a
determination
that in
your life
and mine
this shall
be the way
of life
as a
Christian
we are
going to
see that
we repay
an evil
turn
not with
another evil
turn
that we
repay an
evil
turn not
by doing
nothing
but by
doing
something
and that
positive
a good
deed
and when
we do
that
then we
are going
to begin
to realize
that it
does make
a difference
what people
think
it's strange
again Paul
says this
that we are
to prove
all things
and we are
to show
ourselves
good in
the sight
of men
sometimes
we as
Christians
say I
don't care
what people
say
isn't it
strange how
many of us
with a
spirit of
revenge
we're going
to get
even
we still
claim we're
Christians
and we're
going to
come to
it doesn't
make any
difference
but listen
friend it
makes a
tremendous
difference
what people
think
because again
if people
can look at
you and me
as a Christian
and say
here is a
spirit of
revenge
here is a
gloating
here is one
who is
filled again
with sweet
revenge
who is
conquered
by that
kind of
an evil
what do
you think
you and I
can do
in the cause
of peace
in the world
Paul puts
it this way
he said
if it be
possible
as much
as lieth
within you
live peaceably
with all
men
oh we're
praying for
peace
and we
want peace
but what
must you
and I
do before
we have
a right
to pray
for peace
Paul says
if it be
possible
as much
as it
depends
on you
the big
thing is
there's
something
in this
thing
of peace
that depends
on you
and it
depends
on me
what can
I do
if it
depends
on me
the thing
that I
can do
and that I
must do
regardless
of what
the other
fellow does
is this
that I
must conquer
a spirit
of revenge
by returning
good
instead of evil
that has been
done
you and I
have no right
to pray for peace
unless we are
willing to tell
God
I on my part
I'm doing my
part for peace
because I am
conquering a
desire in my
heart for
revenge
and I
repay
an indignity
with a good
deed
with a kind
praying for
peace
aren't we
oh when I
was in Geneva
and we stopped
at a place
and there was
a legend
Woodrow Wilson
the founder
of the League
of Nations
where is the
League of Nations
it's gone
isn't it
the United
League Nations
was in session
at the time
talking about
the Laos
controversy
and I heard
Adlai Stevenson
give his
matchless address
before the
United Nations
in New York
when our
president had
declared what
we had to do
in the case
of Cuba
and what
was the
address
to stand
up there
and to
honestly
have to
say
this is
the reason
why we
have had
to do
what we
are doing
not in
a spirit
of vindictiveness
but because
the Soviet
Union
has lied
to us
the Soviet
Union
has told
us
that there
are no
missile bases
and we
know
that there
are
here
the
pictures
we
had to
stand
what's
wrong
listen
the greatest
peace
plan
that has
ever
come to
this
earth
is this
peace
of
practical
Christianity
overcome
evil
with good
and therefore
again there
can be no
peace in
this world
until it
starts in
your heart
and mind
and it
starts
where as
far as
we are
concerned
this shall
be the
rule of
our
Christian
experience
that we
are going
to overcome
evil
a desire
in our
heart
to get
even
tit
for tat
to give
a man
his own
coin
back for
what he
has given
us
and instead
of repaying
him with
an evil
turn
to repay
him
with a
good
turn
that
is the
answer
to the
peace
problem
and until
the world
knows it
it shall
be embroiled
in wars
and there
will be
rumors
of wars
20th
anniversary
of radio
and we
say what
does God
say today
God says
conquer evil
with good
God says
conquer
this desire
of revenge
and conquer
it by
doing good
by repaying
an evil
turn with
a good
turn
by doing
something
and we
can say
well that's
ridiculous
that's
silly
that won't
work
friends
if Christianity
is ever at
its finest
in its
practical
application
it's right
here
because
God Almighty
also reminds
you and
me
that when
we repay
an evil
turn
with a
good
turn
somehow
or other
if anything
does
that has
a way
of heaping
coals of
fire
on the
heads
of our
enemies
remember
as a
child
in Sunday
school
when I
first
memorized
this
verse
when Paul
said
if your
enemy
hunger
feed him
if he
thirst
give him
drink
for in
so
doing
thou
shall
heap
coals of
fire
on his
head
I
wonder
what in
world
coals of
fire
what does
that mean
maybe some
of you
children
wonder
what does
it mean
coals of
fire
well again
we begin
to read
what are
the coals
of fire
oh it's a
beautiful expression
isn't it
if there
if there is
anything
that will
heap
coals of
fire
on your
enemy
and mine
it's
this
that when
he finds
that we
are not
returning
tit for
tat
but we
are going
out of
our way
to do
him a
kindness
for an
evil
thing
that he
has done
us
then we
heap
coals of
fire
which is
an expression
for we
make him
blush
you know
God made
human beings
with the
ability
to blush
animals
don't
blush
do they
and this
blushing
is of a
particular
kind
it's the
blushing
that a
man does
when he
is thoroughly
ashamed
of himself
if there
is ever
a way
to make
an enemy
of yours
and mine
ashamed
of himself
if there
is ever
a way
to make
him feel
down inside
that he
is the
greater
sinner
it's
when we
give
kindness
in exchange
for an
evil
turn
do you
ever
think of
Joseph's
ten
brothers
what a
scene
that must
have been
you know
when they
came down
to Egypt
and they
were after
food
and they
did not
know that
the emperor
the prime
minister
rather of
Egypt
was their
brother
and when
again he
had given
them food
and he
lined them
all up
and they
came down
with
Benjamin
and Joseph
was there
and he
was speaking
to them
an Egyptian
and an Egyptian
was interpreting
to them
in the Hebrew
language
he hadn't
spoken any
Hebrew to them
because they
thought he
was an Egyptian
and finally
he ordered
the interpreter
and everybody
out of the room
and he couldn't
stand it any
longer
and he looked
at those
brothers
and he said
I am
Joseph
and he
spoke to
them in
Hebrew
and he ran
up and he
threw his
arms around
them and he
kissed them
those men
that again
wanted to
kill him
can you
imagine
ten men
that ever
blushed more
in life
than his
ten brothers
Benjamin
was not in
or he didn't
have to blush
can you
imagine
the coals
of fire
that were
heaped
on those
men's
heads
ten of
them
when they
stood there
and here
was a brother
kissing them
and loving
them
and forgiving
after the
dirty deals
that they
had given
him
oh again
they turned
to him
and they
just couldn't
believe it
could they
they admitted
they were
the big
sinners
if there's
ever anything
that'll make
a man ashamed
of himself
and come to
his senses
it is again
when we can
return an evil
deed with a
kindness
and we can
cause a man
to blush
within
and it
comes from
within himself
that he says
I'm the
greater sinner
just like
King Saul
told David
he said
I sin
more than
you
and then
you talk
about joy
what's there
to lose
listen
the joy
that if a
man turns
and comes
to Christ
there is
this joy
that we've
had a part
in it
do you know
of any
greater joy
than to see
an enemy
because we
have gone
out of our
way to
treating
with kindness
because we
have conquered
a spirit
of vindictiveness
within our
own soul
do you know
of any joy
that is greater
than to see
somebody turn
to Christ
and supposing he
doesn't
there is still
this satisfaction
that his blood
isn't on your
soul and mine
you and I
don't want any
soul loss
because ours
was a case of
tit for tat
regardless of
what the injury
was regardless
of how justified
we may feel
that a spirit
of vindication
and vindictiveness
is justified
on our
part
oh again
this is
Christianity
in its
finest hour
it is applied
Christianity
to the
Christian
it is
psychology
in its
most glorious
beauty
and that's
why today
yes
20 years
ago today
the first
service went
out over the
air
and today
as again
we dedicate
ourselves
that we are
going to
conquer
within ourselves
a spirit
of revenge
of getting
even with
others
we are going
to do it
by repaying
an evil
turn with
a good
turn
then we
ought to
today
we're ready
to thank
God
for the
privilege
that we
have had
of broadcasting
every Sunday
there were two
things I had
in mind
when we went
on the air
the first
thing was
certainly a
conviction
and that was
this
that if we
were going
to broadcast
as Emmanuel
Lutheran Church
it was going
to be done
without ever
at any time
asking for
money
or for
donation
over the
air
no time
did I want
anybody
who was
listening
to say
this is a
gimmick
all they're
interested in
is our
pocketbook
and thank
God
and credit
to you
as a
congregation
for 20
years
you have
nobly
supported
the radio
fund
of this
congregation
oh yes
gifts have
come in
to be sure
and far
be it
from me
to say
that they
have not
but no
gift
has ever
come in
but what
it came
from the
giver
who wanted
to give
not even
by innuendo
has it
ever been
inferred
that we
ever wanted
anybody to
send us
one nickel
because this
was to be
our gift
and our
privilege to
our community
and the other
thing was this
at no time
did I ever
want the radio
broadcast to
mean this
that you in the
church would
feel that you
were spectators
and that this
was a broadcast
no
as you know
for 20 years
the point of
view has been
I'm talking
to you
in the church
and the radio
audience therefore
is part of the
congregation
they are
listening
you are
not
spectators
you are
here as
worshippers
in God's
house
and as we
look back
over 20
years who
knew whether
it would
last I
didn't know
how long
it would
last we
were told
that within
two weeks
you'll find
out whether
the community
will accept
it or not
by the grace
of God it
has been
accepted
well there
have been
some very
fine experiences
to be sure
individuals who
have written
who have said
that I've
come to know
Christ
I have
gone to
the church
in my
community
individuals who
have written
have said
we've wandered
away from
God and
we have
heard the
word and
we've come
back and
we've gone
back into
church life
and we've
come back
to Jesus
Christ
I remember
the one
again the
one time
when I was
speaking about
suicide
by the grace
of God
and by his
providence
when after
that Sunday
I received
a letter
from a young
lady who
said life
came to me
to be something
unbearable
I didn't want
any more of
it
said I went
into the
kitchen
I turned
on the
gas
and the
stove
and I
had it
all on
I closed
the door
and I was
ready to go
I just
didn't want
life
and said I
didn't tune
you in
I just
happened to
have WMRN
on
and so
happened that
you came on
as a sermon
and you were
talking about
taking one's
life getting
so despondent
and so depressed
and you said
that no man
has the right
to take his
own life
and she said
there I stood
and I
wondered
and I thought
well here God
is talking to me
and I turned
the gas burners
off and she
wrote a very
fine letter
and said
thank you
by the grace
of God
that there is
still something
to life
and I am
still living
and some of you
who have said
this
you have said
well the last
sermon my husband
or my wife
heard on earth
came from the
church
they weren't
able to go
anymore
but we were
able to worship
together and we
sat at the radio
and we sang the
hymns with you
and we prayed
with you
and that's why
again there's
always been this
thrill that somewhere
in the sermon I
realize that because
I am talking to
some who may
never again hear
the word of God
who may be at
death's door
that there might be
some comfort
and some strength
and that they
might see the glory
of Jesus Christ
and that knowing
him they might
know that again
even though death
comes it's the
gateway to life
and to everlasting
salvation
that's the joy
of preaching
there's hardly a
week goes by
when I go out
to the hospital
somebody puts
my name down
I don't know
them and I
say to them
yes I'm estranged
and say well you
don't know but
you've been my
minister for 10
years 12 years
whatever the case
may be
I haven't been
able to go to
church and I
listen you're the
only minister I
know and so by
the grace of God
again we don't
know in its small
way what 20
years of broadcasting
the word of God
is done but we
do know this that
God's word never
returns void we
do know that only
eternity can tell
the story but for
this we do thank
God it's been a
privilege a privilege
to be sure to
warm hearts to
show men the
glory of Jesus
Christ and to
know this that
when God's word
is preached as
it certainly has
been from the
depths of my
soul my desire
to preach it
that soldier one
for Jesus Christ
and God's truth
marches on
if souls have
been warmed and
some eyes have
seen the glory of
God it's more
than pay is it
not and today on
the 20th anniversary
we owe to God
that we could go
out of God's
house today and
we could say I'm
leaving behind this
morning a spirit of
revenge there is no
gloating and I
promise the Lord in
my life from this
day on because I
have seen his
grace that whenever
anybody does me an
evil turn by the
grace of God I'm
going to repay it
not with another
evil turn not by
doing nothing but
I'm going to repay
it so God help me
by doing something
good may that joy
that enthusiasm in
Jesus be yours and
mine amen
Lord