Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written in Paul's letter to the Galatians,
our regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday in the fourth chapter, particularly the 31st verse.
So then, brethren, we are not children of the bondwoman, but of the free.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, the Lord of his church, dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
It was while St. Paul was on his first missionary journey that he came into the region of Galatia.
You recall that he was with Barnabas.
When they come up into that territory there in Asia Minor,
cities located there, Antioch and Pisidia, Iconium, Lystra, and Derbe,
Paul found a number of Jews up in that territory,
and he treats Christ to them as the Messiah and as the Savior,
and a number of Jews became Christians.
And then later on, this is what happened.
There came false teachers amongst these Jewish Christians,
telling them that they were not to put their hope of salvation in Christ and in him alone,
but that rather they were to go back to the law,
that they were to put their hope of salvation in doing good,
in trying to keep the Ten Commandments,
in trying to obey the law that God had given them.
And so it was that Paul, in order to refute this argument
and to keep them in Christ as the way of salvation,
he wrote this letter to the Christians up in the Galatian territory.
And this is what he told them.
He said, you who are being tempted to go back to the law,
to feeling that you're going to be saved by means of obeying the Ten Commandments,
he said, do you not read what the Scriptures say about the law?
And then Paul went on and he told them, he says,
remember how the Scriptures talk about Abraham who had two sons?
And I am sure that you recall that story.
You remember that God picked Abraham and told Abraham
that he was to be the father of a great nation,
and that in him and in his seed all the nations of the earth were going to be blessed.
But the problem was Abraham had no children, he had no son.
And time went on and he still didn't have a son
until finally his wife Sarah became rather impatient.
And she said to Abraham, Abraham, take this slave girl that we have.
Her name was Hagar.
And she said, have a child by her.
So Abraham did that.
And Hagar became the mother of a child from Abraham.
And as you know, they called his name Ishmael.
But again, because Hagar was a slave mother,
she was able to bring into this world only a slave son.
And that slave son, because he was a slave son, was cast out.
Now we know this, that later on what happened,
at the time when Abraham was 100 years old and Sarah was 90 years old,
then God came to the rescue and God blessed Sarah with the child.
And because Sarah was a free woman, not a slave woman,
therefore that son Isaac that was born of Sarah was a free son.
And he was not cast out.
He inherited the blessing as God had intended.
And so then Paul went on telling the Galatian Christians,
he said, now there is another meaning in this historic fact
that Abraham had two sons, the one by a bond woman,
a slave woman, and the other by a free woman.
He said, these two mothers represent the two covenants
or the two agreements that God has made with his children.
And then he went on to say, now Hagar, who was the slave mother,
she represents Mount Sinai.
She represents Mount Sinai where the law was given.
And then Paul makes this great point.
Just as Hagar, a slave mother, could produce only slaves to be cast out,
so Paul reminds him, remember Mount Sinai can produce only slave sons
who are lost sons, who are cast out.
And so then it follows that Sarah, who is the free mother,
she represents another mountain,
the other covenant that God has made,
the other agreement, and that agreement is Mount Calvary in Jerusalem.
And Mount Calvary, therefore, because that represents Sarah,
here is again the mountain that produces free children,
that produces saved souls.
And then it was that when Paul was pleading with the Galatians,
he calls upon them to rejoice, Galatian Christians,
rejoice that as Christians, that you are not sons of Mount Sinai,
slaves and lost souls.
Rejoice, he says, that you are sons of Mount Calvary,
that you are free, that you are saved souls, not lost souls.
And so through this same word of God, Paul speaks to you and me today as Christians.
And this is Laetare Sunday, the Sunday to rejoice.
And we are asked as Christians to rejoice in this,
that you and I as Christians are not sons of Mount Sinai.
We are not sons who are trying to save ourselves by means of obeying the law.
That we are not sons of Mount Sinai, therefore slaves and lost sons.
We are called upon today to rejoice that we are sons of Mount Calvary,
that we are free sons, that we are saved souls.
And I am sure that that leaves a number of problems within your mind and mine.
And we may say to ourselves, it's hard to believe
that we as Christians are to rejoice in the fact
that we are not sons of Mount Sinai and thus lost sons,
that we are sons of Mount Calvary and thus saved sons,
because we may say for the life of us, we can't understand why
sons of Mount Sinai are lost sons.
That's a hard thing to understand, isn't it?
We say to ourselves, why is it that a person who really wants to be good,
why is it that a person who is really sincere,
why is it the person that says,
I'm going to try to keep the Ten Commandments to the very extent of my ability,
why is it that a person that says,
I'm going to obey the Ten Commandments to the very best that I can do,
why is it that that person is lost?
Why is it that that person is a slave and is lost?
You and I say, isn't there a road to heaven from Mount Sinai
just as well as there is a road to heaven from Mount Calvary?
Isn't it possible that a person who wants to do what is right,
who wants to obey the Ten Commandments,
who wants to be a son of Mount Sinai?
Isn't it possible for that person to go to heaven
just as well as the person that stands at Mount Calvary,
who is a free son?
Isn't there a road that leads to heaven from Mount Sinai,
the law, as there is a road that leads from Mount Calvary?
Well, this morning, will you do this for me?
Let's imagine that we're all standing before two mountains.
Here is Mount Sinai that represents Hagar or the Ten Commandments.
Here is Mount Sinai where people are standing
who look at Mount Sinai and say,
I want a way to heaven from Mount Sinai.
I want to believe that I can be saved by doing the best that I know how,
by living a moral life according to the Ten Commandments,
by obeying the law.
And then here is Mount Calvary.
Here is Mount Calvary where, again, there are free sons
and here are the saved souls.
Will you just look at these mountains for a moment and listen to this?
You may ask,
Is there a road leading to heaven from Mount Sinai?
And may I say this,
and I hope to God I can write it on your hearts that you'll never forget it,
there is no road leading to heaven from Mount Sinai.
There is no road leading to heaven there.
There never has been.
There never will be a road to heaven from Mount Sinai.
Will you remember that as long as you live?
And here is Mount Calvary.
There is a road to heaven from Mount Calvary.
It is there.
There is only one road,
and it leads from Mount Calvary.
But there is a road there.
But may I write it on your hearts this morning,
there never is,
there never was,
there never will be
a road to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
And that's why Paul calls upon you and me this morning
to rejoice as Christians
that we are not sons of Mount Sinai.
We are not lost souls.
But as Christians,
we are sons of Mount Calvary.
We are saved souls
because sons of Mount Sinai are lost.
There is no road to heaven from Mount Sinai.
You wonder why?
Let's look for a moment.
Let's stand.
Don't forget we're standing before two mountains this morning,
Mount Sinai and Mount Calvary.
When we look at Mount Sinai,
bear this in mind,
that Mount Sinai demands perfection of us.
Mount Calvary gives perfection.
You may say that's strange
that there's no road to heaven
leading from Mount Sinai.
We may say why it was a wonderful incident
when God gave the law to Mount Sinai.
It really was.
When God gave the law to Mount Sinai,
to be sure,
it was a wonderful occurrence
that Moses had led the children of Israel,
you remember,
out of the land of Egypt
and they crossed the Red Sea
and they came to Mount Sinai in Arabia.
And there it was that God said,
Get ready.
And on that one day of days,
God spoke from the mountain
and it trembled in the earthquake
and there were storms again,
thunder and lightnings
and a cloud filled the mountain.
And the Lord God spoke.
But listen,
what did he say?
I am the Lord thy God.
It was a great day.
But listen,
when God at Mount Sinai
gave the Ten Commandments,
bear in mind
that it was a God of perfection calling
and it was a God who was saying,
I am the Almighty God.
walk before me
and be thou perfect.
Mount Sinai demands
nothing short of perfection.
And when you and I
stand at Mount Sinai this morning,
listen,
God says,
Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
I want to be first,
last and always in your life.
You must do my will at all times
and never fail in one point
because the law says,
whosoever shall keep the whole law
and yet offend in one point
is guilty of having broken the entire law.
We stand at Mount Sinai
and listen to what God says,
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain.
God says,
never use my name foolishly.
You must use it.
Never must you ever use it in vain.
I demand perfection,
not just your best.
I demand perfection.
And you and I stand
in the mountain
that's trembling.
God says,
remember the Sabbath day
to keep it holy.
God says,
you've got to worship me
and you've got to honor me
in perfection.
God says,
honor thy father and thy mother.
God demands perfection,
not just your best and mine.
God says,
thou shalt not kill,
till no hatred there shall be,
no hatred and ill will in your hearts.
God says,
I demand no less than perfection
at Mount Sinai.
Thou shalt not commit adultery,
not even one evil thought and desire.
God says,
thou shalt not steal honesty,
perfect absolute honesty
in all things.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor.
God says,
you must never lie
and then you must speak the truth
and speak it only in love.
I demand nothing less than perfection.
And God says,
thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's wife,
nor his man's servant,
nor his maid's servant,
nor his cattle,
nor anything that is thy neighbor's.
God says,
you dare not have
even one evil desire,
not one sin of jealousy,
not one sin of envy.
And you and I stand
and we say Mount Sinai
is a marvelous mountain.
But listen,
it demands perfection.
And when you and I
do not measure up to its demands,
it says you and I are guilty.
Every man that stands
at Mount Sinai,
which is the law,
stands as a guilty sinner
before God.
Having broken the law,
we all stand as lawbreakers.
Listen,
why is it
that those who stand
at Mount Sinai,
those who are ever so sincere,
those who are ever so good,
who stand at Mount Sinai
and say there must be a way
to heaven from Mount Sinai,
believing that that's the way
to heaven and eternal life,
but nevertheless,
they are lost sinners
and they are absolutely lost.
Why?
There isn't any road
leading to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
How could there be?
Because no man stands perfect.
But oh God,
when you turn to the other mountain,
to Mount Calvary,
now something's different.
There's a Christ
at Mount Calvary.
You notice there isn't any Christ
at Mount Sinai.
I never was,
never will be.
But there's a Christ
over here at Mount Calvary
and you and I look at him
and we say,
who is he?
Why, he's no less than God the Son.
He's no less than God,
a very God
and King of kings
and Lord of lords
who came out of the ivory palaces
into this world of sin.
And on Calvary,
yes, on the cross,
he was the one
who again,
he bore again
the law of God.
He fulfilled it perfectly.
In thought,
word,
in deed,
he stood before
the world of his day
and no man was ever able
to convince him
that he had sinned
and because he is
no less than God
when he kept the Ten Commandments,
he kept them for you and me.
When you stand
at Mount Calvary, sinner,
there comes some Christ
who says,
here is the perfection
that Mount Sinai demands
but can't give.
I give you my perfection
as the Son of God
because I kept
the Ten Commandments for you.
Isn't it marvelous?
And listen,
there's a road
that leads to heaven
from Mount Calvary.
There never was.
There is not
and there never will be
a road leading to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
And if I could write that
on your souls this morning,
listen,
today we ought to thank God
that as Christians
that we are not sons
of Mount Sinai.
We are not sons of Hagar.
We are not slaves,
condemned sinners.
We are sons of Sarah
standing at Mount Calvary.
We are free and saved.
And if we could say,
we are there,
why?
Knowing that there is no road
that leads to Mount Sinai,
then we ought to be able
to understand this more.
Well, then why did God
ever give Mount Sinai anyhow?
Many a man says,
well, if there's no road
leading to heaven
from Mount Sinai,
why in the name of goodness
did God ever give
the law at Mount Sinai?
Well, listen, friend,
that isn't the first
that God gave the law,
the law of the Ten Commandments,
why it was given
back in creation
when God wrote it
in man's heart
in the Garden of Eden.
But man lost it
when man sinned.
And here at Mount Sinai,
God repeated the law
and what was its purpose?
It was never intended
to be a way of salvation.
It couldn't have been
no more than God
ever intended
for Ishmael
to be the forerunner
of Christ.
God never intended
that Hagar
should ever give birth
to a slave son
and that Ishmael
should be the seed
from whom Christ
would come.
God never intended that.
God's intention was
that Sarah
should have a son
and that Sarah's son
Isaac should be
the progenitor of Jesus
and that he would
come from Isaac,
not from Ishmael.
No more than that.
But you say,
well, if the law
at Mount Sinai
was never given
to save,
that there's no road
to heaven,
what did God give it for?
Why, the Bible
answers it very simply.
The law, again,
by the law
is the knowledge of sin.
God gave Mount Sinai
for this big reason
that you and I
might stand
at Mount Sinai
and even though
we would come and say,
I'm going to try
to keep it,
to live,
that we would soon see
because it demands
perfection,
that we can't keep it,
that you and I
would begin to see
ourselves as lost
and condemned sinners,
that before Mount Sinai
we would see
that we're guilty,
that we don't measure up,
and that seeing it
in horror
we would race
from Mount Sinai
over to Calvary
to see the need
of a Savior.
You know,
if there was no
Mount Sinai,
you and I
would never have
any consciousness of sin.
We'd never realize
that we are sinners
and that we are guilty.
The law was given
to show us
our need of a Savior.
And yet isn't it strange,
I wonder how many
that I'm talking to
this morning
stand before Mount Sinai
and oh,
you get the greatest
comfort out of it.
You love it.
You stand there,
how many people say,
my religion,
my religion is to do good,
my religion is to keep
the law,
and oh,
you stand and you say,
oh,
I thank you Lord
that I'm a lot better
than other people are,
and you stand at Mount Sinai
and you've got the assurance
that you're saved
because again,
you are doing the best
that you know how.
Listen friend,
what can I tell you?
There isn't any road
to heaven at Mount Sinai.
How in the name of God
can you stand there
and get comfort
out of something
that tells you
that you're a guilty sinner?
You've got to
misinterpret the law.
How many this morning,
you're sincere,
oh heaven,
yes,
you're sincere,
but you're standing
before Mount Sinai
and you think
that you're saved,
but listen friend,
believe me,
there isn't any road
that goes to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
It was never intended
to save
and it'll never save you.
It'll never save me.
It can't.
It demands perfection.
There's no Christ there.
Will you remember that?
No wonder when Paul
wrote to the Galatians
and they were in danger
of leaving Mount Calvary
and they were going
back to Sinai
to base their salvation
on obeying the law,
doing what the law
would require.
And Paul wrote,
heaven forbid,
rejoice in the fact,
Galatians,
that because you're Christians,
that again,
you are not sons
of Mount Sinai.
You're not slaves.
You're not lost.
You're sons of Mount Calvary.
You're free.
You're saved.
And you and I may say,
well, oh why is it
it's so hard to believe
that somebody
that stands at Mount Sinai
who is so sincere
and tries to fulfill it,
it's so hard to believe
that they're lost.
Well, listen,
they're lost for this reason.
There just isn't any way
to heaven from Mount Sinai.
There never was.
There never will be.
Why?
Look at Mount Sinai again.
Mount Sinai not only
demands perfection,
but look,
Mount Sinai condemns you and me,
condemns us to hell.
Every last one of us.
Mount Calvary rescues us from hell.
Look at Mount Sinai.
If you're getting any comfort
if you're getting any comfort,
if you stand before Mount Sinai,
you and I,
and we say,
I'm trying to fulfill
what you ask.
I'm trying to keep the law
of Mount Sinai.
It says perfection.
You've got to be perfect.
If you are not perfect,
you're guilty.
And because you were guilty,
you were damned.
Mount Sinai hands out
only eternal death
and damnation
for your body
and soul and mine.
That's all it can give.
Why?
There's no Christ there.
Don't you realize
there is no Christ
at Mount Sinai?
It was never intended to save.
But, oh God,
when we stand at Mount Sinai
and we realize
that we're condemned,
that there's no difference
that all of us have sinned,
and because eternal damnation
is on it,
we rush from Mount Sinai
and we go over to Mount Calvary
and lo and behold,
there's a Christ there
and there's a cross there
and we stand before the cross
and we say,
here is hope.
Here is the God-man
who came from heaven
and came to this earth
and on the cross
he took the guilt
and the punishment
of the world
and in that death
he bore the equal
of an eternity
in hell for the human race
and he stands there
and he said,
if you trust me
and put your faith
and your confidence
in me as your savior,
I will rescue you
from hell
and bestow upon you
the blessing of eternal life
and everlasting salvation.
Marvelous, isn't it?
You can stand there
at Mount Calvary.
Listen, there's a Christ there
and there's a cross
but there isn't here.
Oh, if I could write it
on your souls this morning
you'd remember
as long as you live
there never was,
there isn't now
and there never will be
a road leading to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
I don't care how sincere
you are, listen,
if we could rejoice
that we're Christians
and because we are Christians
that we are therefore
not sons of Mount Sinai,
we're not sons of Hegel,
we're not Ishmaelites,
we're not lost and damned,
we are sons of Sarah,
free and saved,
then if we could rejoice
in that fact,
then we would expect in life
that we are going
to be persecuted
and we're going
to have barbshot at us
when we try to tell people
who stand at Mount Sinai
there is no road
leading to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
Isn't it strange
the people that stand
at Mount Sinai
and get such a comfort
out of it,
they love it.
Here's a mountain
that damns them
and they stand there.
Oh, how sweet you are.
I know I'm saved
because I'm so good
when Mount Sinai says
you're lost
and there's no road
leading to heaven
and yet some people
make themselves think
that there is.
And then you tell them
that there's no road
and what happens?
Same thing that happened
back in Abraham's home.
Why, listen,
just as soon as Hagar,
the slave woman,
knew that she was
going to have a child,
she from then on
started to thumb
her nose at Sarah.
Why, she simply
treated her with impudence.
Look who I am,
a slave woman.
I'm going to have
the child, not you.
And then she had
Ishmael, the slave,
and then later on
Sarah had her son
and Isaac grew up
and let me tell you
Ishmael gave Isaac
a dog's life
and Hagar gave Sarah
a dog's life.
They were mean
and they got to the place
where life couldn't
go on anymore
and Abraham said,
Get out!
Get out, Hagar!
Get out, Ishmael!
You will not inherit
as my son.
Isn't it strange,
even as I talk now,
how many stand
at Mount Sinai
and say to those
who stand at Mount Calvary,
don't you dare tell me
that there's no road
leading to heaven?
How many stand
and say,
Listen,
you know anybody
that says,
I don't belong to church
and I don't intend to?
You see,
not belong to church
means you don't need Christ.
You don't need Jesus
and the cross.
How many,
am I talking to somebody
that's more,
and you're already peed?
How many stand
at Mount Sinai
and say,
I don't belong
to your old church
and I don't think
I have to,
I'm just as good
as anybody that does?
Believe you me,
I can stand here
and I'll do the best
that I can.
How many of you say,
I belong to an organization
that's very religious
and I know that
if I do everything
that that organization
tells me,
I know that I'm going
to be saved.
Where you at, friend?
Aren't you at Mount Sinai?
Aren't you saying,
if I can do
what I've been told to do
and obey it,
fine,
I'm going to be saved?
Are you,
listen,
may I remind you
from the depth
of my heart,
the crescent
is not the cross.
It is not the cross.
It never was.
It never will be.
You may say,
I'm standing
and I'm doing
the best that I can.
I've got Christ.
I follow him
as an example.
Listen, friend,
you may bring Christ
to Mount Sinai,
but you can never
bring the cross there
and Christ
without the cross
is only an example
and you can't
follow him.
Believe me,
to be saved
following Christ
is an example.
You've got to be perfect
and you can't be.
Oh, my words
may hurt you
this morning,
but oh, listen,
I don't want
your blood on my soul.
some of you
to say,
I don't need the church
and I don't need Christ.
I'm going to stand
at Mount Sinai
and I've got
such a good life
and I'm going to stand
and I'm going to heaven
because believe me,
as God lives,
there's no road
to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
And I believe me.
If you're going to
stand there,
listen, friend,
for goodness sakes,
ask yourself,
do you have
the Christ of the cross
at the center
of your religion?
Do you know
what I'm talking about?
If you're at
Mount Sinai,
listen,
there isn't any road
to heaven,
there never was
and never will be.
You're on the wrong track.
It can't be.
Oh, you may be hurt,
but I'd rather
have you hurt
and examine it
and be saved
than to go out
of church
not being hurt
and standing
at Mount Sinai
and saying,
I thumb my nose
at the Christians
in the church.
I'm going this way.
Don't go this way.
It isn't a way.
Could I make it any clearer?
And listen,
when you can stand here,
remember,
we ought to thank God
that there is
a Calvary,
that there's a Christ
in the cross.
There is no Christ
and no cross
at Mount Sinai.
Will you believe me?
Oh, listen,
no wonder Paul says,
rejoice as Christians.
Rejoice that you're not
sons of Mount Sinai
lost and damned.
You're sons of Mount Calvary.
You're free
and you're saved.
And you and I may say,
well, it's so hard
to believe
that sons of Sinai
are lost.
I know it is
because people are sincere
and you want to do your best.
But listen,
it's just like this
and just that simple.
There's no road
to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
How in the world
can you be saved
by doing your best
when there's no road going?
There just isn't
because there's no Christ
and there's no cross.
And bear this in mind,
Mount Sinai
has no one to give us
who gives us power
to live a life
that is pleasing
in the sight of God.
Oh, you may say,
my life is pleasing
in the sight of God
when I stand at Mount Sinai.
Is it?
The word of God,
my Bible says,
without faith
it is impossible
to please God.
A man without Christ,
his life doesn't please.
Listen, fam,
this hurts.
You can give everything
you've got to the poor.
You can go out
and dedicate your life
to the help
of all human beings.
But listen,
if you're standing
at Mount Sinai
and there's no Christ
in your heart by faith,
your whole life
means nothing to God.
God will say,
depart from me,
I never knew you.
You can stand and say,
well, Lord,
don't you know me?
Well, I gave everything
I had to the poor.
I simply healed the sick
and I cast out devils
and I did wonderful things.
And Jesus will say,
depart,
I never knew you.
Oh, there's no power,
you see.
How in the world
could your life and mine
be pleasing to God
when we stand
at Mount Sinai
and we're staying
under condemnation
and we're damned to hell.
A damned soul
can't please God.
Is it clear?
Or am I talking
over your heads
this morning?
When you go
to Mount Calvary,
you and I stand there,
oh, listen,
we stand there
knowing that we're
not perfect.
We stand there
with guilt.
knowing we're condemned.
But there's the Christ
and the cross
and when we forsake all
and we take him,
when we put our trust
into our confidence
and say,
you died for me,
I want you,
the Christ who died,
he comes and lives
within you and me
and oh,
what a difference.
Then when he lives
within us,
he gives us power
so that our imperfect lives
do please God.
When we fail
and come short,
his righteousness
covers up our imperfections
so that our lives
do look pleasing
in the sight of God
even though they fail
and they come short
in so many things.
But you see,
the righteousness of Jesus
makes your life
and mind acceptable
and when he lives
in your heart
and mind by faith
he gives us power
that when temptations come
we can say no
and we can walk
in ways pleasing with him
and you and I
can find joy
in doing his will
to the best of our ability
but knowing
that it doesn't save,
knowing that his blood
and his righteousness
alone save.
Oh,
we ought to be able
to thank God.
Listen,
will you just remember this?
When you stand
at Mount Sinai
and oh,
there's something,
oh,
I know we like
to achieve our own salvation
if I'm going to be saved
I'm going to do it myself
but remember
from Mount Sinai
in Arabia
only slaves,
there's no road,
never was a road
going to heaven
but from Mount Calvary
a wonderful way
we ought to thank God today
that as Christians
we are not
sons of Sinai,
lost and damned creatures
but we are free
sons and daughters
of again
of Mount Calvary
because there's
the Christ and the cross.
We ought to thank God
that listen,
this covenant
that God made
at Mount Sinai,
how in the world
could it ever
in any way
repudiate the covenant
that God made
at Calvary.
You may say,
well,
didn't Sinai come first?
Oh, no.
Mount Sinai came
430 years after
God made it for Calvary.
You may say,
how is that?
Mount Sinai,
1500 years before Christ
in Calvary A.D. 33
but listen,
God made this covenant
with Abraham
2,000 years before
and with Adam
4,000 years B.C.
but it was fulfilled
of Calvary
that Christ
was going to come.
He was the Lamb
slain from the foundations
of the world
and listen,
because the great covenant
was made with Abraham
and Mount Sinai
came 430 years later.
Mount Sinai
could never repudiate
Calvary
or repudiate
the covenant
that God made
with Abraham
and what a joy then
as again,
Paul reminded them,
he says,
remember
that the children
of the childless mother
of the barren mother
shall be greater
than the children
of the one
that has a husband.
Isn't that true?
Look at the Christian church.
Look at the sons of Sarah.
Sarah was barren,
oh yes,
and only produced one son,
but look at the Christian church,
those who stand
at Mount Calvary.
Oh,
when you count the numbers,
how much greater they are
than the sons of Hagar,
than the Jewish people
today in the Ishmaelites
who do not stand
at Mount Calvary.
The Christian church
is immense.
It stands so marvelously great.
Sons and daughters
of Sarah
free
because there's a road
to heaven
that leads
from Mount Calvary
into heaven.
But you know,
there's a marvelous miracle
that can happen.
You may be standing today
and say,
I've been at Mount Sinai
all my life.
I've never understood
Mount Calvary.
I realize
that there isn't a road
going to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
But you know,
Ishmael had to be Ishmael.
But oh,
you and I,
if we're Ishmaelites,
we can be Isaacites.
By the grace of God,
we can walk over to Calvary
and we can say,
God,
I'm done with Mount Sinai
as the way to heaven.
I know that there's
no road leading there,
but I come to Calvary
and we can come
with all of our sins
and we can look up
at Christ and say,
Lord,
I put my trust in you
and we can stand
as free men and women.
You can go out
of church this morning
and you can say,
I'm on the road
to heaven.
I am saved
because Sinai
has condemned me.
There's no road,
but there is one road
and I'm on that road
in Jesus Christ.
Jesus said,
I am the way,
the truth,
and the life.
Why not let Jesus
save you and me?
Why can't we go on
the glory road
and sing with joy,
My hope is built
on nothing less
than Jesus' blood
and righteousness.
No merit of my own,
I claim,
but wholly lean
on Jesus' name.
On Christ,
the solid rock,
I stand.
All other ground
is sinking sand.
Could I write it
on your soul once more?
There is no road
that leads to heaven
from Mount Sinai.
There is one road
that leads to heaven.
Thank God there is
one road,
but it leads
from Mount Calvary.
God grant you
and me as Christians
to stand before
Mount Calvary
and thank God
for a Christ
and above all
with a cross.
Amen.
The peace of God
which passeth
all human understanding,
keep and unite
your hearts and minds
in Christ Jesus
unto life everlasting.
Amen.