The peace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written back in the Old Testament, in the book of Judges, the 16th chapter, the 20th verse.
And he wist not that the Lord was departed from him.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight, O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
Good morning, dear friends in Christ Jesus, you who are here in church, and you also who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
It is nice having you in church this morning, friends, and it is nice also to have you who are in the radio audience worshiping with us.
That text that I just read has to do with a man by the name of Samson.
And I'm sure that when I mention his name, Samson, that all of you say, yes, I know that man.
Samson, that's the strong man of the Old Testament, the man that had superhuman strength, and you are right.
That's the man we're going to talk about this morning.
This man, Samson, was known as a judge in Israel, or a deliverer.
God had appointed him to deliver Israel from the hands of the enemy, the Philistines.
This man, Samson, however, was a very peculiar man.
There lived amongst the Philistines a very wicked woman by the name of Delilah.
She flirted with Samson, and Samson flirted with her, and then Samson went to sin with her.
Now, he went to sin with Delilah for only one reason, and that was that he wanted to.
He deliberately wanted to go and sin with her, and that's what he did.
She, however, had been told by her own Philistine people that she was to find out the secret of this man's strength
so that they could overcome him and kill him, and thus overcome Israel.
She questioned him at length, and he lied to her, which he knew was wrong, but he did it anyway.
Then, finally, in a weaker moment, when she asked him again,
Wherein lies your strength, Samson?
Then he told her, he said, Before I was born, my parents dedicated me to the Lord.
I am a Nazirite. I have taken the Nazirite vow.
He said, No razor has ever touched my head.
My strength, therefore, is evident in my hair.
And so, when he was fast asleep, she had the Philistines come,
and they cut off the hair of Samson.
And then Samson awoke, and we read this tragic statement about him,
And he wist not that the Lord was departed from him.
Samson got up, and God had departed from him,
And the man didn't even know it.
What a tragedy.
God had abandoned Samson.
And there wasn't one inkling of awareness.
He wasn't conscious of it.
He didn't know it.
He was not cognizant of it.
But God was gone, and Samson didn't know it.
If we translate this into the New Testament,
God speaks to you and me this morning with regard to Samson.
And in New Testament terminology,
God says to you and me this morning,
The same thing that happened to Samson,
that God departed from him,
and he didn't even know it is exactly the same thing that can happen to you,
and it can happen to me.
You and I can lose Christ.
We can lose him and everything that we have in him.
The forgiveness of our sins,
Deliverance from hell and damnation,
And the gift of eternal life.
Mind you, friends,
You and I can lose Christ,
And not even be aware of it.
Not even have an inkling.
You and I can lose him and be the last man on earth to know
That we've lost him.
It is something that can happen to you and to me and to any Christian.
You and I may say,
Do you mean to say that I can lose Christ and not even know it?
That I can lose him unawares?
That I won't even have the least inkling that he's gone out of my heart and my life?
Do you mean to tell me that I can be a living, condemned person?
That I can be the last one to know it?
And that I can feel that I still have him, but that I may not?
Do you mean to tell me that I can lose Christ and not know it?
Yes.
Samson didn't know it, and God had forsaken him.
We may say that's impossible, but it isn't.
It is very possible because this thing can happen to you and me
for the same reason that it happened to Samson.
And we may say,
Why did it happen to Samson?
This is it.
Because Samson deliberately sinned.
Samson did that which he knew was wrong.
And therefore, you and I can lose Christ
and not have the least bit of inkling
the very demon that has gone out of our lives forever
and the thing that can do it.
The very demon that can do it
is that which we call deliberate, willful sin.
You and I may say,
Can deliberate, willful sin
cause me to lose Christ and everything that he's given me
and cause me not even to be aware of it,
not even to know it,
to be perfectly oblivious to it,
to be the last man in the world,
and to go on living in a fool's paradise
thinking I've got Christ when I don't have...
Yes.
Deliberate sin is the culprit that can do it.
And it can do it because,
in the first place, let's know this,
deliberate sin has a way of blinding you and me
to what we know,
and that is that deliberate sin
is very, very sinful.
You and I as Christians,
we're going to look at this thing
that we call deliberate sin this morning.
We're not talking about sins
that you and I commit every day,
sins of weakness where we don't give our consent to them.
We're not talking about the things
which we want to do but we don't,
and the things which we have left undone,
the things which we have done,
which we, again, did not will to do.
By deliberate sin, this is what we mean.
Deliberate sin is that sin
which you and I do because we want to do it.
that you and I don't have to do.
We know it's wrong before we do it,
but we choose to do it.
We say,
I do it because I want to do it.
And we say to ourselves,
you know how sinful,
how wicked that is.
When God says,
I am the Almighty God,
thou shalt have no other gods before me.
Deliberate sin says,
says you, God,
you mean to tell me
that I'm going to do your will all the time?
I am not going to do your will.
I'm going to do what I want to do.
And you make something of it.
God says,
thou shalt not take the name of the Lord,
thy God, in vain.
Deliberate sin says,
oh yeah,
I'll take your name in vain
any time I want to.
And when I choose to do it,
I know it's wrong,
but I'm going to do it anyhow.
And you make the most of it.
That's deliberate sin.
Deliberate sin means when God says,
remember the Sabbath day
to keep it hold of you.
And I say,
says you, God,
I'll go to church
when I want to go to church.
And when I don't want to go to church,
I'll not go to church.
And what are you going to do about it?
I will do what I choose to do,
what I like to do,
and you can do what you want to do.
God says,
thou shalt honor thy father and thy mother,
and you and I can say,
honor my father, mother,
I should say not.
I will not obey them.
I don't choose to obey them.
I know that I should,
but I'm not going to do it.
That's deliberate,
willful sin.
It means we know it's wrong,
but we do it for only one reason,
because we want to do it.
And that's why Samson did
what he wanted to do,
because he wanted to do it.
And when God says,
thou shalt not kill,
you and I may translate it into hate,
and say,
I'll hate who I want to hate,
and I'll keep on hating them.
I'll hate them because I want to hate them.
And you, God,
do something about it.
And God says,
thou shalt not commit adultery,
and you and I can say,
I live only once,
and I'm going to live just as immoral
as I want to live,
and as I choose to live,
and I'm going to do it
because I want to do it.
And God,
you try to stop me.
Thou shalt not steal.
I'll be just as dishonest
as I want to be.
My business is going to thrive,
and what do I care
whether I'm honest or not?
I choose to be dishonest,
and God,
you make the most of it.
God says,
thou shalt not bear false witness
against the neighbor,
and I'll lie about my neighbor
when I want to lie about him,
and I'll not speak the truth
in love about him.
I'll do as I plead.
And when God says,
thou shalt not covet
at the neighbor's house
or his wife
or his manservant
or his maidservant,
you and I say,
I'll covet whom I want to covet
and what I want.
I'll be just as greedy
and jealous
and hatred and avaricious
as I want to be,
and I'll choose to do that,
and God,
you make the most of it.
That's what I'm talking about
this morning.
I'm talking about
deliberate sin.
You and I know
how wicked it is.
Why?
Whenever in your life
and mine,
you and I do that
which we know is wrong,
whenever you and I say,
I do it because
I want to do it,
I don't have to do it,
but I choose to do it,
in that moment
we dethrone Christ.
We tell Christ,
Christ,
you're no longer my master,
you're no longer
the Lord of my life,
I am the master,
get out of here!
You know that
as well as I.
But you know,
it's a strange thing
whenever we embark
on a life of delivered sin,
whenever we say,
I know it's wrong,
but I'm going to do it anyhow,
that sort of blinds
you and me.
It blinds us
to the maliciousness
of this delivered
kind of sin,
and it makes us feel
that it's not too evil,
that Christ doesn't go out
of our hearts
somehow or other,
and therefore again,
this is a possibility,
and this can happen
to you and me,
that we can lose Christ
and lose everything
that he has given us,
and not even know it
and live in a fool's paradise,
because deliberate sin,
when it blinds us
to its evil,
it takes Christ
out of our hearts
and it blinds us
so that we aren't
even aware
that he's gone,
then it deceives us
and tells us,
oh, he's still there,
you're an important person,
you're an exception,
Christ wouldn't ever
leave you,
and we say,
oh, I still have Christ,
I can go out
and live in deliberate sin,
I can do as I please,
he hasn't left me,
I'm not aware
that he's gone,
therefore I still have him,
everything's all right,
he is my Lord,
oh yes,
that's what Samson thought,
but he wist not,
he didn't know
that God had departed
from him
and had abandoned him,
oh, if we could just
write this on our hearts
this morning,
it can happen to you
and it can happen to me,
I don't care who you are,
who I am,
this can happen,
it's a possibility
that can come into
your life and mine,
that you and I
can lose Christ
as our Lord and Savior,
lose every blessing
that we have in him
and not even be aware of it,
just not have
the faintest,
slightest idea
that he's gone
and live in a fool's paradise
and not have him,
and when we admit
that this thing
can happen to us,
then ought not this
be the time
to stop and to say,
what about this thing
of deliberate sin,
oh, you and I
sin every day,
not deliberately,
again, we sin in weakness,
we don't give our consent
to so many things
that we do
that are wrong,
but is there anything
in your life
and mine
that we do
because we choose
to do it
and we know
that it's wrong,
let's look at it,
how about it,
taking God's name
in vain,
how many of us
take his name
in profanity,
in dirtiness,
and we simply
besmirch God's name,
how many of us
do it
because we want
to do it,
how many of us
say,
I don't go to church
and I don't intend
to go to church,
is that in your life
and mine,
how many of us
say to ourselves,
honor my parents,
no,
how many of us
hate,
this morning
have got hatred
into our heart
and we feel
exceptional,
we're a different
person,
God says
he makes an
exception
and therefore
Christ still
lives in our,
may I tell you
he does not,
if there's hatred
in your heart
and mind
this morning
against anybody,
let me tell you
as sure as
God lives,
Christ is out
of your life,
he's gone,
you're living
death and
damnation
even though
you don't know
that's for you
and for me,
we're living
in immorality,
I don't care
who you are,
we're doing it
because we want
to do it
and if we're
doing it
because we
want to do it,
may I say
we're blinded,
Christ is long
gone,
you and I
can say not
only can it
happen,
it has happened,
it happened
to Samson,
to Samson
with Delilah,
that man
lived again
as a slave
to his passion
and to his lust,
he lived for
sexual immorality,
this man
Samson,
when again
he gave in
to Delilah,
he wished
not
that the Lord
had departed
from him,
if there is
deliberate sin
in your life
and mine
this morning,
let's not
pull any punches,
Christ is gone,
you and I
can shout
to the heavens,
oh he's in me,
I know,
I pray
and I go to
church
and I get
money,
yeah,
but it's
blinded you
and me,
he is not
in your heart
and mine
when there is
deliberate sin,
believe me,
that's the word
of God,
oh Samson,
we say to ourselves,
God says,
what happened to him
can happen to you
and me,
can it?
yes,
the,
again,
the little
trickster,
the one
that plays
the trick
is this thing
that we call
deliberate sin
and that deliberate
sin means this
that I know
it's wrong
but I do it
because I want
to do it,
because I get
pleasure out of it,
because it satisfies me
and bear in mind
that this thing
that we call
deliberate sin,
it can cause us
to lose Christ
and not have
the faintest idea
that he's ever
left us
to revel in the idea
and say to ourselves,
oh he still lives
in me
and he's gone
and not have
the slightest inkling,
not even feel
again that he's
ever left us,
you and I
can be living
in a fool's paradise,
the last one
in the world
to know it,
why?
Because in the second
place let's know
this thing called
deliberate sin,
this thing has a way
of blinding you
and me to something
else we know,
the damnable-ness
of deliberate sin,
how damnable
is
deliberate sin,
how damnable
in the sight of God
is it when you
and I deliberately,
willfully do that
which we know
is wrong
just because we
want to,
choose to,
well it's so
damnable that it
meant that God's
only son had to
come out of the
ivory palaces
into this world,
he had to become
a human being
without sin,
and he had to go
to the cross of
Calvary,
and he had to
take the guilt
of our deliberate
sin and its
punishment,
and he had to
bear hell
and damnation
for that sin
of deliberate
willfulness,
he had to die
for you and me
and bear hell,
the damnable-ness
of that sin
for you and me,
we had to be
died for,
now you and I
know that,
that it's damnable
to say to God,
I don't care,
I'm going to do it,
I know it's wrong,
but I'm going to do it
anyhow,
what happens
when we do it,
you and I know,
the moment in your
life and mine
when we do that
which we know
is wrong,
we take back
from Christ
the guilt and
the punishment
that he bore
for us,
and we put it
back onto
ourselves,
we say to Christ,
let me have it,
and we put it
onto ourselves,
and when you and
I take from
Christ the guilt
and the punishment
that he bore for us,
and put it back
onto ourselves,
he can't stay
in your heart
in mine,
that kind of
rebellion he can't
stand,
then he says,
you don't want me
anymore,
when you no longer
let me be your
savior,
and you take it
back on yourself,
I must abandon
you,
I must leave,
and this deliberate
sin,
it blinds,
you see,
it blinds because
it offers so much
joy and satisfaction
for us,
that it blinds us
to everything else,
and it blinds us
to this damnableness,
and so,
deliberate sin,
it takes Christ
out of our hearts,
and it blinds us
to the fact
that he's gone,
and then it
deceives us
into saying,
you're alright buddy,
just as long as
you use the magic
words,
I'm sorry,
every day,
he'll never leave you,
he'll always be with you,
oh you know
it's strange,
individuals who
live in deliberate
sin,
how many have said,
oh I ask for
forgiveness,
I tell him I'm
sorry every day,
I even cry about it,
I cry at night,
and I tell him
I'm so sorry
for the things
that I've done wrong
that I know are wrong,
and again,
you say,
well therefore
I know that he lives,
listen,
what good is saying
I'm sorry
and even a bunch
of tears
when tomorrow
you and I
if we're living
in deliberate sin,
we know we're going
to get up and do
the same thing
we did today,
what kind of sorrow
do you call that?
If that isn't
hypocritical sorrow,
I never heard of it,
that's the magic
word,
but you see,
deliberate sin,
it says,
did you say you're
sorry?
Oh,
if you said you're
sorry,
that's all you have
to do,
everything's okie-dokie,
oh,
okay now,
you're all set,
as long as you told
him today you're
sorry,
and if you can cry
a little bit,
that's a lot better,
that is in repentance,
what happens if
Samson can happen
to you and me,
and if we say
that to ourselves
this morning,
then it happens
through the trickery
of deliberate sin,
when in your life
and I,
we choose to do
that which we know
is wrong,
we don't have to,
but we do it
because we want
to do it,
that's the reason,
when we admit
that this thing
can happen,
that we can lose
Christ and everything
that he stands for
and everything he's
given us and not
have the slightest
inkling that he's
gone to be
absolutely unaware
of his being
taken from us
and absolutely
to feel to ourselves
that we have
no realization,
we have no sick
sense that he's
with us,
it can happen
through deliberate
sin,
it's a damnable
thing,
when this morning
you and I say
it can happen
to you and it
can happen to me
and no one is
immune,
then if we again
see deliberate
sin into our lives,
then this is a
good time right now
to repent
and to repent
as we should
repent,
what happened
to Samson?
When they saw
him in weakness
they tied him up
and the first
thing they did
they gouged
his eyes out,
they blinded him
you see,
they were smacking
themselves in revenge,
we'll blind
this weakling
and they put him
on display,
they took him
out and he
took the place
of the horses
and the mules
and the donkeys,
he ground out
the grain
and the threshing
floors,
they used him
as an animal,
a blind man,
but in that
blindness,
in that suffering,
Samson began
to realize
what he had
done,
he began
to realize
that because
of his life,
because of
the way he
lived,
what he did
that was wrong,
he came to
himself,
and it was
through suffering,
what about
repentance,
what do you
mean?
Ought not this
be the time
in your life
and mine
when we say
if there is
deliberate sin,
what is it?
What is the
deliberate sin?
To repent,
oh listen,
it's the hardest
thing in the
world,
if you and I
are hating
somebody this
morning,
the reason we're
hating is because
we want to
and we're getting
a thrill out of
it,
can you take it
out of your
heart this
morning and
me out of
mine if it's
there and can
you lay it at
the cross of
Christ and say
I'm sorry,
if you can,
it's the hardest
damnable thing
you ever did
in your life,
you might as well
cut your eyes
out,
there isn't
anything,
listen,
there is no
repentance without
suffering,
you mean to
tell me if
you've got
another woman
on the spring
and this is
going on and
this is the
day when you
say that's
deliberate and
I'm going to
stop,
do you mean to
tell me it's
easy?
You've never
done anything
harder in your
life,
you might as
well cut your
right arm off,
there is no
repentance without
suffering,
whoever told you
it was easy,
could we this
morning before
God and man
say this is
deliberate sin if
there is one
and lay it on
the altar and
say God I'm
done with it,
you might as
well cut your
heart out because
it hurts,
Samson had to
have his eyes
gouged out before
he came to his
senses,
then and only
then can we
know that it
didn't happen to
us,
that if Christ
left he's back
again,
because only
when we are
free from
deliberate sin
can we have
any assurance
that Christ
lives within
darkness,
there is no
assurance in
saying I'm
not conscious
that he's ever
gone,
he must live
within me,
you and I
can lose him
and lose him
and be the
last one in the
world to know
it through
deliberate sin,
and when
again we can
lay them at his
altar this
morning like
pulling teeth
and cutting out
an eye or
cutting off our
right leg or
an arm,
then we can
say again it
hasn't happened,
I have him,
then we'll not
have this
disillusionment,
imagine what it
means to die
and to say I've
got Jesus,
he lives in my
heart,
yes he does,
and yet here we
are as the old
hymn says,
deluded souls
that dream of
heaven and make
their empty
boast of inward
joys and sins
forgiven when
they are slaves
to lust,
what would it
mean to stand
before God
if you and I
would die and
say oh he
lives in me
and Jesus
look at you
and me on
the day of
the death,
I never knew
you,
I left you
years ago
and you
know it,
I left you
years ago
deliberate sin,
you drove me
out of your
life long ago,
can you imagine
any disillusionment
that would be
more horrible
than to think
we're saved
and to stand
before our
Lord and to
have him say
depart from
me,
I don't
know you,
I left you
years ago,
oh what
happened to
Samson can
happen to you
and me,
it's an ever
present possibility,
we can lose
Jesus Christ
every blessing
that we have
in him
and not
even know
it,
absolutely be
unaware of
it,
not be
mindful of
it,
have no
sense that
he's gone
and live in
a fool's
paradise and
say oh yes
I know that
he lives
and have him
gone long
ago,
why?
Because the
culprit is
deliberate sin,
not only
does deliberate
sin blind you
and me to
its sinfulness
and blind us
to its damn
ableness but
also this,
deliberate sin
blinds you and
me to the
horror of our
deliberate sins
but oh never
to the horror of
the deliberate
sins of others,
oh you know
talk about
deliberate sin,
something that
can do some
trickery in your
life and mine,
you see this
thing blinds,
when I embark
on a life of
sins again that
are deliberate
and again are
willful,
it blinds me
that I don't
see my sins
but oh God
do I see the
sins of others,
you know have
you ever wondered
about this,
just you have a
deliberate sin
in your life
and then you see
it in somebody
else and oh
you ought to
listen to yourself,
you can look
look at that
guy,
look at the
way he hates,
oh you never
got so much
righteous in
the initial life,
look at that
woman chaser,
guy that breaks
up a home,
look at that
guy that doesn't
care about his
kids,
look at that
skin flint in
business,
look at that
guy that would
take the pennies
off a dead
man's eyes,
what are you
doing?
You're
castigating him
and damming
him,
why?
Because you're
never any worse
on him and
it's down in
here,
we call that
in psychology
projection,
you see we
get relief,
take ours that
bother us and
throw our
deliberate sins
on somebody
else and
then just
wail into
them,
makes us feel
better,
we get them
told,
you see,
we make it
look like
they've got a
great big
plank and ours
is just a
little old
piece of
sliver,
that's
projection,
oh how it
can blind us,
and then it
blinds us in
this way when
it does that,
it takes Christ
out of our
hearts,
it blinds us to
the reality that
he's gone and
then it turns
around and it
deceives us into
saying we're
just so much
better than
others that
Christ would
never think of
leaving us,
if you want to
get a self-righteous
binge,
you and I can
get it in
deliberate sin,
then just
project it on
somebody else and
wail the tar out
of them and get
them told,
because again,
makes us feel
good down here
because there
is no blasphemy,
there is no
sarcasm so
great that when
it comes from
somebody who
is guilty of
delivered sin,
who sees the
same sin in
somebody else,
talk about
blinding us,
it can happen,
yes,
it happened to
Samson,
he again,
he wist not,
that the Lord
was departed
from him,
and if you
and I this
morning can
say it can
happen to
anybody,
we can lose
Christ and
not know it,
be the last
person on
earth to
know it
because of
deliberate sin,
therefore we
ought to do
this,
we ought to
every day in
our life turn
to Christ and
pray for
strength,
that when
deliberate sin
beckons that
he gives us
the strength to
say no,
it's wrong,
no,
give me strength,
I know it's
wrong,
I will not
do that which
I know is
wrong,
I don't have
to do that
which I know
is wrong,
I don't choose
to do that
which is
wrong,
well what
about old
Samson,
Samson when
his eyes were
out,
when they made
an animal out
of him,
he let his
hair start to
grow again,
and they say
what about
him,
well there
was a big
celebration
down in
Gaza,
the same
Gaza you're
reading about
today,
the Gaza
strip,
I was in
that neighborhood
too,
think of it
over 3,000
years ago
Samson was
in the city
of Gaza
and they
had a temple
there to
their Philistine
god,
Dagan,
in Gaza,
he had been
in that building
evidently when
he still had
his eyesight,
they're pretentious
temples if you've
ever been in
that area,
made out of
stone,
tremendous
buildings,
and a
little boy
let him
in,
he was
on display
and he
knew that
there were
two center
pillars that
held up
that magnificent
temple and
on the second
floor of that
day we were
told about
3,000 people
on the second
floor,
let alone those
on the first
floor of that
temple,
it was filled
with people,
and he asked
the little boy
to lean him
back so he
could lean
against the
two pillars
that kept
the second
floor of that
building and
the little boy
did,
then Samson
slowly put his
arms around
the pillars,
this man
repentant now,
he again,
his hair was
growing,
he had taken
back his
Nazarite vow,
and he prayed
to God,
he knew that
his life would
go too,
and he asked
God,
oh God,
give me strength
that I can
deliver Israel
from the
Philistines as
you want me
to do,
and God gave
him strength,
and he started
to pull on
those pillars
toward him,
and slowly
with the
strength that
God gave
him,
they tumbled
and the
roof came
down,
and oh
again,
the deaths,
the leaders
of the
Philistines
were killed,
and Israel
was killed,
and they say,
were Samson
saved,
how about
a man
when God
abandoned him
and he didn't
even know it,
we know it's
wonderful,
you go to the
New Testament
to find out,
we wouldn't
know if we
just had the
Old Testament,
to go to the
book of Hebrews
in the New
Testament,
the 11th chapter,
you've never
read it,
you want to
read that
chapter,
that's the
hall of fame
of the men
of faith
of the word
of God,
the 11th
chapter of
Hebrews,
and in the
11th chapter
of Hebrews
in the 32nd
verse,
we find the
writer of
Hebrews says,
and what
shall I more
say,
he says,
time would
fail me,
he's talking
about the
heroes of
faith,
time would
fail me,
he says,
to tell of
Jephthah,
and of
Baric,
Gideon,
and of
Samson,
Samson is
mentioned in
the hall of
fame,
in the word
of God,
yes,
he made it,
God came
back to
Samson,
because he
came back
to Samson,
if it should
be that we've
lost Christ,
and we aren't
even aware of
it,
oh,
to turn in
repentance for
deliberate sin,
it happened
to Samson,
but God
came back,
and Christ
will come
back into
your life
and mine,
when we
repent with
real suffering,
and ask him
for strength,
and then it
matters not
what comes in
life,
in the
emergencies of
life,
oh,
think,
how death
comes into
our home,
oh,
the clashing
of two
automobiles,
and there's
death in
the moment
of an eye,
or death,
we go in
the bedroom
and we find
a loved one
dead,
with no
time of
preparation,
you and I
can say,
how can I
be ready
for that
emergency,
that I'll
be given
no warning
over this,
but when
again I
know that
deliberate
sin has
been taken
to the
throne of
grace,
and that
therefore I
can know
that Christ
has not
been taken
away,
that I
still have
him,
then nothing
else matters
that we can
look forward
to an
eternity
with our
loved ones,
who again
have conquered
in this
thing of
deliberate
sin,
oh,
then we
can sing
and we
can know
it for
certainty,
I come
to the
garden alone,
while the
dew is still
on the roses,
and the
voice I hear
falling on
my ear,
the Son of
God
discloses,
and he
walks with
me,
and he
talks with
me,
and he
tells me
I am his
own,
and the
joy we
share as
we tarry
there,
none other
has ever
known,
and when
he tells you
and me
then that
we are his
own,
we can
believe it,
know it
for certainty,
when in
him we
have
conquered
deliberate
sin,
amen,
the
peace
of God
which
passeth
all human
understanding,
keep and
unite your
hearts and
minds in
Christ Jesus
unto life
everlasting,
peace