Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God, our regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday,
as we find it written in the first letter of Peter, the second chapter, especially the 21st verse.
For even hereunto were ye called, because Christ also suffered for us,
leaving us an example, that ye should follow his steps.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, our risen Lord, dear friends,
you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
This morning, the Apostle Peter, the big fisherman from up Galilee Way,
speaks to us through the word of God.
And the big fisherman says to us,
and it is Jesus' wish that you and I follow his steps,
that you and I walk in his steps,
that we follow his example.
When we say to ourselves,
what does Peter mean by that?
How are we to follow Jesus and to walk in his steps?
The Apostle Peter hastens to tell us
just exactly what he means,
for he says that Christ suffered for us,
leaving us an example,
that we should follow his steps.
In other words, Peter says,
what the Lord wants of you is this,
that you will walk in his steps,
you will follow his pattern,
his example in this matter of suffering,
the matter of enduring suffering
as Christians,
as followers of Jesus Christ.
In other words, Peter says,
this is what your Lord wants of you.
He wants you to walk in his steps
in this matter of suffering
because you are a Christian,
because you believe in Christ as your Savior,
because you want to live
as Christ wants you to live,
because you want to treat your neighbor
exactly as Christ wants you to do so.
And Peter says,
in that matter of suffering,
Jesus wants you to walk in his steps
to follow his example.
Then you and I say,
well, how did Jesus endure suffering?
What was the way in which he accepted
those things that came to him?
And again, the big fisherman from Galilee Way
gives us an example
and tells us exactly how that occurred
by telling us this,
that he, when he was reviled,
he reviled not again.
When he was suffering,
he threatened not.
Peter says,
this is the way your Lord suffered.
When they heaped all manner of ridicule on him,
he didn't throw it back into their faces.
When they reviled him,
he didn't revile back and retort in kind.
When they looked at him
and they insulted him,
he didn't turn insult against them.
When he suffered,
he didn't threaten them with vengeance.
He wasn't filled with bitterness.
He wasn't filled with resentment.
He didn't say,
I'll get even with you
if it's the last thing that I ever do.
And so Peter says,
this is what your Lord wants.
He wants you to walk in his steps.
He wants you to follow his example
with regard to this matter of suffering as a Christian.
He wants you to endure it patiently,
to endure it gently,
to endure it without any bitterness,
without any resentment,
without any spirit of revenge.
And say, Christian friends,
that's quite an order, isn't it?
You and I say,
do you mean to say
that Jesus wants me to walk in his steps,
that I am to follow his example
with regard to suffering,
that when again men inflict
all manner of abuse on me
because I'm a Christian,
that I've got to take it?
Do you mean to say
that I am to accept it in all patience,
that I am to bring it to myself gently,
that I am not to blow off the handle,
I am not to seek revenge?
Do you mean to say
that that's what I am to do?
And we say that's a big order
and the reason why it seems
like a big order to you and me is this.
We say that suffering
that comes to a Christian
is absolutely uncalled for,
it's absolutely undeserved.
And right you are, my friends, it is.
There is no reason in God's world
why a Christian ought to suffer
because he's a Christian.
There is absolutely no justification
for any suffering to come to a Christian
because he believes in Jesus Christ.
The world has no reason to do so.
You are so right.
It is absolutely unjustified.
It is absolutely undeserved.
It is uncalled for.
But the fact still remains
that when you and I are Christians,
there come sufferings to us.
And Jesus says,
walk in my paths
and accept that impatience
with no bitterness,
no resentment,
no spirit of revenge.
It is undeserved.
But Christ wants you and me to know this,
that this enduring of suffering
that is absolutely undeserved
and enduring it patiently,
it ought to be the thrill
of your Christian life and mine.
It ought to be something that we say,
this is what I want to do
more than anything else.
It ought to fill us with enthusiasm.
It ought to be the experience
of all experiences
in our Christian life.
And we may say,
how so?
Do you mean to say
that we ought to thrill
when we suffer as a Christian
and therefore there should be
no bitterness,
no resentment,
that we ought to gladly
walk in the paths of Jesus
and follow his example?
Exactly.
Because let's realize
in the first place this,
that it was by this very kind
of suffering
that Jesus our Lord
brought for you and me
our redemption
from hell
and from damnation.
Do you realize
that that's the kind
of suffering Jesus endured?
Did Christ deserve
what he got
the crown of thorns?
Did he deserve
to have men spit in his face?
to have men
to take the reed
and crack him in the face?
Did he deserve
to be scourged?
to be nailed to the cross?
Did he do something
that again would cause
men to do that justly?
And the apostle Peter,
the big fisherman,
says he was without sin.
Peter knew him
as a sinless one
who had lived in this world
without sin
because he was
the eternal son of God.
Peter said there wasn't
even any guile
in his mouth.
There wasn't any semblance
of sin in him,
not even to the point
that he tried by his words
to soft soap anybody.
Peter said he was
without sin
and yet it was
undeserved suffering,
it was innocent suffering
and the very fact
that Christ
brought it in patience
that there was no bitterness,
there was no resentment,
it means that
by that very suffering,
Jesus brought escape
from eternal death
and hell
for you and me.
We ought to realize
that had he been a sinner,
had he accepted this
with a spirit of revenge,
had he said,
I'm going to get even with you,
there would be no deliverance
from eternal hell
for the world.
But because he suffered
innocently
and because he did it
gladly and willingly,
when he went to Calvary's cross,
he bore your guilt
and he bore mine
and he bought the eternal punishment
of our sins
and in that sufferings and death
because it was undeserved suffering
and death
for him who was
the eternal son of God,
there was brought for you
and me deliverance
from eternal death,
soul and body in hell.
And therefore,
when we walk in his steps
with regard to this matter
of suffering as Christians,
we ought to say,
it's the thrill of a lifetime
because it's the evidence
in your life and mine
that your faith and mine
is genuine
and that in Jesus Christ
we do have deliverance
from eternal death
and eternal damnation.
We may say to ourselves,
how do I know
that I'm a Christian?
How do I know
that I'm saved?
that I have been rescued
from eternal death
and damnation?
You and I need to look
at our life
and let's look here
in the acid test.
How do we accept suffering
because we're a Christian?
Do we accept it in patience?
Do we accept it gently?
Or are you and I bitter?
And do we retort
with all manner of epithets
that are cast at us?
And do we have
a spirit of revenge?
Listen, friend.
If there is a spirit of revenge
in your heart and mine
because we are Christians,
there is no resemblance
between us and our Lord.
If you and I are Christians
and our faith is genuine,
there ought to be
some similarity
between Jesus
and between you and me.
And if all that we have
because we suffer
as Christians is bitterness,
we ought to say to ourselves,
my faith is a sham faith.
My faith is not
a living faith in him.
He endured it gladly
and it was innocent suffering.
But if all that you and I
have is a spirit of revenge
and I'll get even,
we ought to say to ourselves,
we are not Christians.
We are not saved.
We do not belong to him
because there is no similarity
whatsoever between Christ and us.
And that's why today
when the big fisherman says,
this is what your Lord asks,
that you walk in his steps,
and that means with regard
to your suffering as a Christian,
then we ought to say to ourselves,
this is the thing
that I shall determine to do,
that I want to walk in his steps.
I want to walk according to the example
that he has left.
I as a Christian,
I want to endure
what comes to me as a Christian
and I want to do it
without bitterness
and without a sense of resentment
and without a spirit
of getting even.
And when there is
that determination,
then we're going to realize this,
that in the Christian life,
listen,
this suffering is inseparable
with being a child of God.
Peter said,
for hereunto were you called.
How many of us realize
that with the Christian life,
there comes suffering?
How many of us this morning
have to say,
well, it's been pretty easy
so far as a Christian.
I don't think that I've suffered
anything particularly
being a child of God.
Haven't you?
When again,
suffering follows
being a Christian
as the morning follows the night.
Haven't you ever suffered
any ridicule from the world
because as a Christian,
you believe that Jesus Christ
was the eternal Son of God,
your Lord,
that he was born of a virgin,
that he arose from the dead?
Hasn't the world
ever laughed at you
for believing
that somebody dead
could rise again?
Hasn't the world
ever stood and made fun of you
because you believe
in the deity of Jesus Christ?
Hasn't the world
ever made fun of you
that you believe
that Christ is coming again?
Where have you been?
Perhaps the world
doesn't know
that you're a Christian.
You can't live a day
without paying the price.
Can you?
Do you mean to say
that you've never suffered
any ridicule
because you lived Jesus Christ?
You young people,
when it comes to a matter
of whether you're going
to be popular or not,
and when you've got to say,
I don't live that way
because I'm a Christian,
you mean to tell me
that you've never suffered ridicule
and somebody called you
a square
or whatever you're supposed to be?
what kind of a Christian are you
and what kind of a Christian am I
if we don't pay the price
of being a Christian?
If again there is
no ridicule
and no laughter
and no embarrassment
to you and me
as a Christian,
then pray,
God,
let's take a look
at ourselves.
We are mighty
poor examples
of a Christian.
The world doesn't know it.
Oh,
we don't deserve it.
You say,
why does the world
hate a Christian
when you and I say
I'm going to treat my neighbor
the way Christ
wants me to treat him?
And I'll turn the other cheek
and the world stands
and laughs and said,
why,
you're a big goof.
Talk about being a screwball
that you'll turn the other cheek
and let the other man
take advantage of you.
Do you mean to tell me
that you and I
have never suffered
for being a Christian?
But why does the world
hate a Christian?
Do you know why?
Let's put it down
in our hearts
and never forget.
Listen,
the world hates you
and me as a Christian
because we stand
as living memories
to a man of the world
that if what you and I
believe about Christ
is true,
that man knows
he's damned.
Don't forget that.
When you and I
stand and say
this is Christ
who is the only
Savior from sin,
bear in mind
that the man of the world
that looks at you
and me and says
if what that guy
believes
is right
then I'm lost
and let me tell you
when the world
looks at you and me
and the world knows
that he's lost
because he doesn't
have Christ
he hates you and me
with a vengeance
and don't ever forget it.
The only way
in God's world
you can ever keep
the world from hating you
is to make sure
that you don't let
the world know
that you're a Christian.
And listen,
you can't compromise
it either.
There isn't any
compromise
between heaven and hell,
between Christ
and the world,
between sin
and righteousness.
it just isn't there.
If you and I
can say this morning
as a Christian
it's been a pretty easy road,
for God's sakes
look in the mirror.
What kind of a Christian
are you?
am I?
That's why
the big fisherman
up Galilee Way
says this is what
your Lord wants.
He wants you to walk
in his steps.
He wants you to follow
his example
with regard to this thing
of suffering
because you're a Christian.
He wants you to bear it
even though
it is absolutely unjustified.
It is absolutely undeserved.
But bear it patiently.
No bitterness,
no resentment,
no spirit of revenge.
And you and I say,
why?
Because it's undeserved.
But listen,
it ought to be
the thrill of a lifetime.
It ought to be
that which inspires you
and me
beyond everything else
to say,
this is an honor.
It's an honor
to bear undeserved
suffering gladly
for Christ.
Why?
Because that kind
of suffering
in the second place
was exactly
the kind of suffering
that Jesus endured
whereby he became
the great good shepherd
and the overseer
of our souls.
What made him
the good shepherd
that he could say,
I am the good shepherd?
Did he not say
because the good shepherd
gave his life
for the sheep?
How does it come
that God raised him
from the dead?
How does it come
that as the good shepherd
he is the one
that sits at the right hand
of God,
the one that rules
the world,
the one who holds
the world
in the very hollow
of his hand,
the one who rules
the world
for you and me,
how does it come
that he's the good shepherd?
Isn't it this?
Because the suffering
that he endured
patiently
without bitterness,
it was undeserved suffering.
He didn't deserve
the deal he got,
did he?
And because he didn't,
he did it for you
and me.
In his own self,
yes,
in his own body,
he bare our sins
on the tree.
And because he is
the good shepherd
and the overseer
of your soul
and mine,
listen,
he is the one
that overrules
everything for your
good and mine.
We can't have
that conviction
that he overrules
good for us
unless you and I
can say,
I belong to him
and my faith
trusts this
that because
I shall endure
what the world
sends me
with joy
and it'll be
the thrill of my life,
only then
can you and I
say he is working
these things for good.
Does he as the great
good shepherd overrule
for good?
Did you ever see
the greatest reversal
that has ever taken
place in human history?
Bear in mind,
he died on the tree.
And listen,
when Peter uses
that word tree,
he uses it the way
they used it in that day.
The most horrible death
that could come to a man,
I mean the most
ignominious,
the most low type
of death
that could come
was death on the cross.
Jesus might have died
by being beheaded,
but that was honorable.
But to die on the cross,
anybody that died
on the tree
was known as one
who was accursed of God.
You were the lowest
type of humanity
that could exist.
You were really
an outcast
and he died
in the lowest form
of death
that could ever come
to a man.
They nailed him
to a tree.
And you talk about
the overruling
providence of God,
what happened?
They nailed him
to a tree.
But isn't it strange
that horrible,
detestable mode of death?
You're sitting in a church
that is laid out
in the form of a cross.
How in the world
could something
so detestable
as a cross
become a symbol of joy?
How does it come
that many of you
have lavaliers
and necklaces
around your neck
in the form of a cross?
Why?
Because that lowly,
detestable,
ignoble,
despicable death
was overruled
in the providence
of God
that it's become
the symbol of life.
That's why
as you sit here
this morning
there's the cross
on the altar.
Some churches
have the corpus,
the body on it,
which calls attention
to the death.
Some of us
have the body off of it,
which means that he died
but he arose again.
Either one
is perfectly all right.
Why is it that the cross
is a symbol
of honor and distinction?
Because it was
the greatest reversal
that has ever taken place
in human history.
You wouldn't wear
an electric chair
around your neck.
You wouldn't wear
a noose around your neck,
a gallows.
You wouldn't wear
a gas chamber.
But we wear the cross.
Why?
Because Christ,
the Good Shepherd,
has overruled
the most ignominious death
that ever occurred
for the redemption
of the world.
And listen,
it ought to be
the thrill of your life
and mine
when we walk
in his steps
to say again,
I count it an honor
and a distinction
to suffer for him
and to do it
without bitterness
because then we have
the evidence
that our faith
really trusts him
and that he's overruling
everything for good.
Listen,
nothing comes into your life
except by his permission.
We're talking about
the things that we bear
because we're a Christian.
Bear in mind,
this suffering
is because we're
a child of God.
Every man has suffering.
This kind of suffering
is what you get
when you believe in Christ.
And the other way
you can get rid of it
is to get rid of Christ.
Then you can lose it.
And that's why
we call it cross-bearing.
But when you and I
shall endure it,
it's the evidence
that Christ
has overruled everything
and what comes,
we can't do it
without bitterness
because we can say
the things that he has
allowed to come
into my life,
they are expanding
my capacity,
my faith grows stronger,
that in heaven
you and I
will be able
to enjoy
even with a greater
spiritual capacity
the things
which eyes
have not seen
nor ears heard
neither have entered
into the heart of man.
That's what it means.
That's why
the big fisherman
up Galilee Way
says your Lord
wants you to walk
in his steps.
He wants you to walk
in his way.
He wants you to endure
suffering as a Christian
the way he did.
It ought to be
the very joy
and the distinction
of our lives.
And if again
we would determine
that that's what
we're going to do,
that whatever comes
to us as a Christian,
when we love Christ
and we want to walk
in his way
and we want to treat
others the way
Jesus wants us
to treat them
and when the world
laughs and it ridicules
and it embarrasses us
that we can accept
it in all patience
and in all calmness,
then we ought to pray
God for strength
to do so
and counted a badge
of honor
and a badge
of distinction.
I'll never forget
when in Rome
last summer
I stood and walked
into the Colosseum.
Oh, the Colosseum,
what's it noted for?
Because there is
where Christians
who suffered
because they were
Christians
who gave their lives
because they believed
in Jesus Christ.
They went to their death
before lions
and they were pulled
to pieces
because there was
no bitterness,
there was no resentment,
no hatred.
Oh, the Colosseum,
while stands,
the Colosseum,
remember,
Rome shall stand
and when falls,
the Colosseum,
Rome shall fall
and when Rome falls,
the world.
But the Colosseum stands
as a glorious memorial
to the hundreds
of thousands
of Christians
that gave their lives
with no bitterness.
Why?
Because it was
a badge of honor
and distinction
that they could suffer
and die for their Lord.
There was no spirit
of revenge,
no spirit of getting even.
On the cross,
Jesus,
what did he say
about his enemies?
Father, forgive them.
They don't realize
the enormity
of what they're doing.
I stood outside
the St. Stephen's Gate
in Jerusalem
where they brought Stephen,
the first martyr,
out and they stoned him.
Was there any bitterness,
any resentment
when Stephen was being killed
because he was a Christian?
What did he do?
He prayed,
he said,
Lord,
lay not their sin
to their charge.
And he was given
a vision, wasn't he?
He looked up
and he saw Jesus Christ
stand at the right hand
of God
and again,
it meant something.
It was the thrill
of a lifetime
to walk in the way
of suffering
that God would consider him
to be of that value
and that God would give him
that glorious decision
to make
to again walk in his way
when it meant death.
The great fisherman,
from up Galilee way,
says to you and me
as a Christian,
let's walk in his steps,
let's walk according
to his pattern,
let's endure the suffering
that comes to us
because we're a child of God
and let's endure it
with all patience
and with all humility,
no bitterness,
no feeling of getting even.
Why?
Because, listen,
it's that kind of suffering
that Jesus endured
that also brought this about
that he put this whole thing
of judgment
into the hands
of his heavenly Father.
What did he do?
There was no bitterness.
When again those sufferings
came to Jesus,
he simply took this whole thing,
he put it into the hands
of his heavenly Father
who judges righteously.
Isn't that a marvelous thing?
Why?
Jesus realized
that at the time
that was not the time
for judgment.
This was the time
for grace.
when men could still be one
and therefore
this was not the time
for judgment.
And he had no spirit
of revenge.
He simply put it
into the hands
of his heavenly Father
who judges all things fairly.
But I want to call
your attention to this
that he put judgment
into the hands
of his heavenly Father.
Today, what are we reading?
We read not long ago
where somebody says
capital punishment
should be outlawed
because it's nothing
but revenge.
Now, we're not arguing
capital punishment
this morning,
but the big point
of that is this.
any kind of judgment
is revenge
according to that statement.
In other words,
in Merlin County
when Judge Paul Smith
in judgment
puts again
a punishment
on a criminal,
he is doing it
in revenge.
When Judge Ed Rousseau
in probate court
brings any kind
of judgment
against an individual,
then it's got
to be revenge
because it's judgment.
When Judge Hazen
brings judgment
against somebody
in Merlin City,
then it's got
to be revenge
according to
what we're being told.
Do you see
what's implied in that?
Don't let anybody
kid you.
You see,
it's like this.
If all judgment
is revenge,
then God surely
can never enter judgment
with you and me.
There can't be any hell
because that's judgment
and judgment's revenge.
God is a God of love.
Now underneath it all,
this is the thing.
Men are trying
to tell you and me
there isn't any hell,
there isn't any punishment
for sin,
there isn't any judgment
because if there's judgment,
God has a spirit
of revenge.
He's getting even.
Therefore, again,
you see what's...
Don't let anybody
ever tell you
that judgment
is revenge.
If judgment
is revenge,
then there isn't
such a thing
as justice.
When we say
justice is blind
because justice
is fair,
we lie.
There is judgment
and judgment
is fair
in the sight
of God
is not revenge.
Don't you let
everybody undermine you.
That's what the world
would like
to get you
to believe
that God
is a jellyfish
type of a God
of love
and that you
and I can spurn him
and slap his son
Jesus Christ
in the face
and you can get by
with it.
Well, listen,
friends,
you can't get by
with it.
When Jesus suffered,
he put the whole thing
into the hands
of God
who judges wisely.
There is judgment.
But because this is
the day of grace,
listen,
it ought to be
the thrill of a lifetime
to endure
without bitterness,
without complaint,
without a spiritual revenge,
that which comes
to you and me
because we're a Christian,
because we believe
in Christ,
because we want to live
the way he wants us to live.
We want to treat others
the way he wants us
to treat them.
We ought to realize this,
that it brings us assurance
and it's a thrilling thing
to know that
if ever we're going
to influence anybody
for Jesus Christ,
it's when you and I
suffer for him
without bitterness.
Listen,
let the world
look at a man
who is willing
to bear
any kind of persecution
for Jesus Christ
and if there's anything
that will wake
a man of the world
up,
it's that.
A man of the world
looks at a Christian
and he says,
if that man
is willing to suffer
for his faith
and he's willing
to do it
without bitterness
and no revenge
and he's not threatening
to get even,
there must be something
to what he believes.
If that man
is willing to die
for what he believes
about Jesus Christ,
if there's anything
that will impress
a man of the world,
it's that.
If that doesn't,
nothing will,
you know it.
Is there any
thrilling life
in knowing
that some way,
somehow,
you and I
in walking
in the steps
of suffering,
in walking
in the pattern
that Jesus
has left for us,
that if some men
are ever going
to be influenced
for Jesus Christ,
it will be
by your walking
in his paths
and mine.
Is there any
thrill in that
to know
that we might
save just one soul
from eternal perdition
when Jesus said
it would be better
for a man
never to have been born
than to be lost?
How about it?
It ought to mean
then today
that when the big
fishermen
tells us
what Jesus wants,
we ought to say
to ourselves
as we pray
for strength
that we want
to walk
in his ways
as Christians
and we want
strength
that when we
are ridiculed
and laughed at
and scoffed at
and even if
persecution
and all its
deadliness comes
that we might
be fit
to endure it.
You know,
sometimes we talk
about the age
of persecution.
Oh yes,
we think back
of the first
century,
but listen,
Christian historians
have tried to figure out
exactly about
how many Christians
from the first
century up until
now died
for their faith.
Do you realize
this,
that they have
figured out
that in the last
30 years,
think of it,
in the last
30 years,
more Christians
have paid
with their lives
than have paid
from the time
of Christ
up until
30 years ago.
Do you realize
that?
So that,
listen,
I want you to
remember that.
When you talk
about the age
of persecution,
listen bud,
we're living
in the age
of persecution.
Millions
have been put
to death
behind the
iron curtain
for no other
crime than
that they believe
in Jesus Christ.
There are
hundreds of
thousands
in the salt
mines
who are slaves
and will be
slaves to the
end of their
lives behind
the iron curtain
for no other
reason than
that they believe
in Jesus Christ.
Don't ever
forget it.
This is the
century of
persecution.
In the last
30 years,
may I say it
again,
more Christians
have died
and have been
persecuted for
their faith
than have been
since the
beginning of
Jesus Christ
and Christianity
itself.
Don't forget
that.
Therefore,
again,
we ought to
be ready for
it.
Oh,
it can come.
Remember when
I was in Rome,
I was walking
along and I
looked up and
saw a sign
on the street
and I was
taken aback
and it said
the Appian
Way.
Well,
you know what
that brings
a flood of
memories.
We've all
talked about
the Appian
Way.
Those of you
that have
studied Latin
in high school,
the Appian
here I was
on it.
When I saw
the sign
the Appian
Way,
my mind
began to
think of
something
that took
place on
the Appian
Way
according to
tradition.
That was
with the
big fisherman
himself.
Remember
the story
is told
in tradition,
it's not
in scripture
but about
Peter that
he was in
Rome and
Nero,
you know,
had set fire
to Rome
and I saw
Rome burned
and he blamed
it on the
Christians.
And the
Apostle Peter
was told by
his friends
to flee the
city of
Rome because
they were
persecuting
them and
putting them
to death,
this big
fisherman.
He started
down the
Appian Way
and I
thought of
him that
day,
the old
Apostle
Peter,
the old
fisherman
from up
Galloway
going down
the Appian
Way at
night,
fleeing the
city and
fleeing
persecution.
The story
is told
that as
he was
walking
down,
suddenly
there was
somebody
coming
towards
Rome and
he at
first couldn't
distinguish
the
features but
as the
person came
closer,
Peter looked
at him and
he suddenly
recognized him
and it was
his Lord.
And when
Jesus came
and passed
him,
Peter supposed
to look
at him and
he says,
Quo vodis
domine,
whither goest
thou,
master?
And then
Jesus looked
at Peter and
he said,
I'm going
to Rome
to be
crucified
again.
Then the
old horseman
himself,
the big
fisherman,
he turned
around,
he came
back the
Appian
Way and
he went
into Rome
and when
they were
ready to
kill him,
he said,
my Lord
was crucified
with his
head up,
but he
said,
I'm not
worthy to
die that
way,
you crucify
me with
my head
down.
Tradition
says then
that Peter
the big
fisherman
from up
Galilee Way,
he was
crucified
with his
feet up
in the
air and
his head
down
because he
was the
one that
had told
the Christians
of his
day,
go and
walk in
his ways.
Yes,
the big
fisherman,
he proved
it with
his life,
that the
thrill of our
life ought
to be this,
surely it's
uncalled for,
it's unjustified,
it's undeserved,
but the
thrill of being
a Christian
ought to be
this,
that Christ
would count
you and
me worthy,
that we
might suffer
for him,
that we
might have
within our
own souls
the assurance
that his
fellowship is
with us
and that he
is our
Christ.
We
beautifully
say it,
don't we,
in the
song,
my God
and I
go in
the field
together,
we walk
and talk
as good
friends
shouldn't
do,
we clasp
our hands,
our voices
ring with
laughter,
my God
and I
walk
through the
meadows,
you,
that's the
great glorious
feeling that we
have when we
are in fellowship
with him,
oh my God
and I,
oh yes,
this world
will pass
and with it
come and
trifles,
but oh God
and I go on
unendingly,
with his head
down and his
feet up from
the cross,
the big
fisherman from
up Galilee
way says to
you and me
this morning,
follow in his
steps,
follow his
amen.
The peace
of God
which passeth
all human
understanding,
keep and
unite your
hearts and
minds in
Christ Jesus
unto life
everlasting.