The grace be unto you and peace from God our Father ran from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God, our regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday,
as we find it written in the letter of James, the first chapter, the 18th verse.
Of his own will begat he us with the word of truth that we should be a kind of firstfruits of his creatures.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, the Christ of Christian mothers, dear friends,
you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also Christian friends who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Today is the second Sunday in May,
and it is the Sunday set apart in our country to be observed as Mother's Day.
Today is the day, therefore, when we honor our mothers.
Some of you, I notice, have the privilege of having your mothers in church with you this morning.
A very happy occasion, is it not?
Others of you, I know, plan to contact and to visit your mothers sometime during this day.
Some of you, some of you, some of you, have already sent gifts.
Others of you will contact mothers at a distance by means of the telephone.
And still others of us have on this Mother's Day, mothers of memory,
mothers who have been called from this world and who have entered the kingdom triumphant.
Christian mothers, I'd like to challenge you this morning.
I would like to challenge you and ask you this morning at this service
to take a look at your Christian children as God sees them.
Would you like to do that?
I would like to have you see your Christian children through the eyes of God.
That is my challenge to you today.
And you may say, well, how does God look at our Christian children?
And we find the answer in the Word of God in our text this morning
where we find James, the brother of the Lord,
telling this, that God of his own will begat us
or made us his sons or his children through the word of truth
that we might become or that we might be
a kind of first fruits of his creation or of his creatures.
God looks at your Christian children as a kind of first fruits of his creatures,
as a sort of first fruits.
And you may say, well, what does that mean?
To understand that, Christian mothers,
we've got to take a look at the Jewish harvest festival for a moment
and to realize what it meant when the harvest time came for the Jew,
when he cut the first wheat or the first grain of the field,
there was a great religious ceremony
because the first grain that was cut belonged to the Lord
and he presented it to God
because God looked upon the first fruits of the field
as being of a special sacredness to him,
of being something that meant more to him than all the rest.
It was something especially sacred
and something especially pure and good to him.
And in the same way, the first fruits applied to the womb,
the firstborn son.
Oh, the firstborn son was something special to God.
And therefore, as the first fruits of the womb,
God looked upon the first fruits, therefore,
as being of a special sacredness,
of a special value,
of being the very apple of his eye.
And therefore, I challenge you, Christian mothers, this morning,
would you look at your Christian children through the eyes of God
and see them as something special,
as being specially sacred,
of being of special, uncommon importance to God,
that they are especially near and precious to God,
the very apple of his eye?
Will you see your children as God sees them?
And yet you may say to me on this Mother's Day,
well, it's hard to believe
that my Christian children are the apple of God's eye,
that they are something really special,
that they are something really precious to him,
that they are really sacred to him
as the first fruits of the field,
that my children mean that much to God,
that they occupy that kind of an exalted position,
that they occupy that kind of status in the eyes of God.
You may say to me this morning,
well, that's a little bit too good to be true,
because you may say in all humility,
nothing extraordinary, nothing uncommon,
nothing spectacular has ever happened to my Christian children.
And yet may I say to you this morning,
as I challenge you to look at your Christian children
through the eyes of God
and see them as a kind of first fruits,
as a sort of first fruits,
something especially sacred,
something especially precious to God,
the apple of his eye,
for this reason that it is too good,
but it is too true,
because something extraordinary
has happened to your children.
Would to God that what has happened
to your Christian children
would have happened to all children.
God would like to have it happen to all.
But it has happened to your children,
Christian mothers,
to your Christian children.
And may I mention in the first place,
this is something extraordinary and uncommon
that has happened to your Christian children.
And God reminds you of this,
that your Christian children have been born again.
Oh, they were born once physically.
And oh, you Christian mothers,
you'll never forget that occasion, will you?
When you held for the first time in your arms,
your child,
especially the firstborn.
When you realized that unselfishly
you were willing to face death
so that you might become a mother,
and when you held that child in your arms
and you kissed the child behind the ear
and it smelt like narcissus and lotus blossoms,
oh, you thank God, didn't you,
that you had become a mother.
And yet, as a Christian mother,
you realized something that day.
You knew that it was a marvelous thing
that you were able to be the mother of a child
to be born, humanly speaking,
but you knew that your child
was born in a condition of sin.
You knew that it was subject to death
and because it came into the world
with the taint of original sin,
as all of us do,
as the Word of God declares.
And therefore, you knew this,
that Jesus says,
except a man be born of water
and of the Spirit,
he cannot enter into the kingdom of God
because that which is born of the flesh is flesh,
and that which is born of the Spirit is spirit.
You, as a Christian mother, knew this,
that there was another birth
that was necessary for your child,
and that was the spiritual birth in baptism.
And so you asked the question,
when is the next baptism, didn't you?
And then you and your husband,
you presented your child
to the Lord Jesus in baptism.
And in baptismal regeneration,
your child was born a second time.
And there was something marvelous
that took place in that moment
when the Holy Spirit,
by means of the Word of God and water,
came to your child.
There was kindled in the heart of your child
a living faith in Jesus Christ
as Lord and Savior.
Oh, it was not a conscious faith
that your child realized
what had taken place,
but Jesus Christ placed in that heart
a faith in Him.
And there came with that faith
then every blessing of the gospel,
every blessing that Christ Jesus
brought into the world
by His sufferings and death on Calvary.
It's a marvelous example
of the grace of God, isn't it,
that a child does nothing
but when the child is born again in baptism
because Christ Jesus went to the cross
and bore the guilt
and the punishment of the world's sin,
there is given to every child in baptism
the forgiveness of the taint of original sin.
There is given to that child
the forgiveness of eternal death and damnation.
And there is given to every child in baptism
eternal life and everlasting salvation.
Mother, something extraordinary
has happened to your Christian children.
They were born a second time in baptism.
They came to a living faith in Jesus Christ
and they were made joint heirs
with Him of eternal life.
And therefore, when you realize
that that's the extraordinary thing
that has happened
and, oh, God is no respecter of persons
and God doesn't love one child more than another,
but it is God's will
that all children might have Christian mothers
and that Christian mothers
might present them to Him
and that they might be born again
so that God could look at all children
and say,
they are the sort of firstfruits.
They are special.
They are something especially precious.
They are something especially dear and near to Him.
They are the apple of His eye.
And today I would challenge you, Christian mothers,
will you continue to look at your children,
your Christian children,
through the eyes of God?
And as you live each day with them,
will you say to yourselves,
my Christian children,
they are a sort of firstfruits.
They are especially dear and precious to God.
Something extraordinary has happened to them.
And if you do that,
I can assure you this,
you're going to thank God
for the privilege of being a mother.
Oh, there are some mothers
that resent being a mother.
Maybe some of you would say,
I must confess that when I was carrying
this child of mine under my heart,
that there were times when I was selfish
and I wished that I were not going to be a mother.
You may have confessed again
to say I deeply regretted
and I even didn't want the child.
And again, I murmured and complained against God.
But oh, you Christian mothers,
you can say that God has long ago forgiven me
for such emotional things
that I thought in the days
when I was carrying beneath my own heart,
my unborn child.
But how many of you, again,
when you look at your child
and say, think of it,
my child is a sort of a firstfruits of God.
Something special,
something precious,
the apple of his eye.
What a privilege
to be a mother.
You know, this morning,
my heart aches for a certain mother.
She's on her honeymoon
down in South America.
She's an heiress.
She inherited four million dollars.
She turned her back on a husband.
And that a person might do
if husband and wife can't get along.
They might separate.
Mind you, I didn't say divorce.
But this mother that I'm thinking about
this morning,
for whom my heart aches,
she turned her back on four children,
the oldest of which is only twelve.
And she married a man 17 years her senior.
This is Mother's Day.
And I can't help but think of her this morning.
I wonder now that the bloom
and the enthusiasm
of some of the honeymoon is worn over.
I wonder how she feels
when she could turn her back
on four children
that she brought into this world
and would give them up
for someone who should not be her husband.
I wonder what she will say someday
when those four children look at her
and say,
you didn't love us enough
that you cared to rear us,
you gave us away.
And this mother has aspirations
for the White House.
When you and I look at the White House today
and we see a Jackie Kennedy,
we are proud of motherhood, aren't we?
And I feel certain
that if this nation ever has to choose,
it will choose a Jackie
rather than a happy
to be in the White House.
My heart aches for her
for any mother
that could give up her children
for her own selfish happiness.
I challenge you, Christian mothers,
that if you can look at your children
through the eyes of God
and you can see them
as sort of a firstfruits of God's creature,
something special to God,
and listen,
you'll be proud of motherhood
and if they should ever turn away from you,
yours will be the satisfaction
that at least you did your best.
Oh, you may be a stepmother,
you may be a foster mother,
or you may be a grandmother
who has taken the place of a mother,
and your efforts may not be appreciated,
but if you have looked at those children
through the eyes of God
and you have seen them
as God has seen them
as being a kind of firstfruits,
the apple of his eye,
you may have no regrets,
even though again
they would turn against you.
I challenge you, Christian mothers,
this morning,
on this Mother's Day,
that you would say,
I will look at my children,
my Christian children.
I will try to see them
with the eyes of God,
to see them as God sees them,
and God sees them
as sort of a firstfruits.
Oh, they are something special.
They are his prized possession.
They are sacred to him.
They mean the apple of his eye
because something spectacular
has happened to your Christian children.
Not only this,
that they have been born again,
but God would remind you and me,
your Christian mothers,
especially in the second place,
that your children
have had the Holy Spirit
come and abide in their hearts.
You know,
something spectacular
also happened on the day
when you Christian mothers
presented your children for baptism.
When faith in Jesus Christ
was engendered
in the heart of your child,
the Holy Spirit
moved in too.
The Word of God says,
Know ye not that ye are
the temples of God,
and that the Spirit of God
dwells within you?
Christian mothers,
do you know
that your children's bodies
are the temples
of the living God?
And you and I
may stand with our mouths open
and we may say,
How can it be
that God could dwell?
He personally,
the Holy Spirit,
in the heart
and in the very soul
of all individuals
who have been baptized.
Well, you see,
the nature of gamut,
we make our God so small
that we fail to understand
His magnitude
and His bigness.
But James says,
He is the Father of lights,
the God who by the fiat
of His Word
brought into existence lights
the suns and the moons
and the stars.
He is that God
and that Holy Spirit
dwells in the heart
of your children by faith.
Oh, sometimes,
oh, there have been days,
haven't there,
when you'd say,
and my children
have the Holy Spirit
dwelling within them.
Oh, you've seen
the trying days, haven't you?
And you finally
got them to sleep.
But didn't you ever
walk into the room
at night
and when the moonbeams
were shining in the room
you looked at the face
of a tussled little boy
and you rubbed
his hair back
and you looked
into his face
and you saw
the image of God,
didn't you?
And you thanked God
and you thought,
my, God is oozing out.
God is there.
You saw it.
Oh, Tommy lad,
Tommy lad,
though you're scarce
the way you're owed,
you've seen the image
of God, haven't you?
Something spectacular
happened in baptism
and that Holy Spirit
that dwells in the hearts
of your children
by faith,
that Holy Spirit
would guide them
into all truth
so that living
in the ways of God
they should not lose
eternal life.
That's what the Holy Spirit
is doing in their hearts
by faith
lest they would lose
the great blessings
that became theirs
when they were born again
by water and of the Spirit.
and that's why
this morning
Christian mothers
I challenge you
will you look
at your children,
your Christian children
through the eyes of God
and every day
that you live
when you look at them
will you say
why they are
a sort of a first fruits.
They are something
special to God.
My children
as Christians
they're sacred,
they're precious.
Oh, they're so dear
to God
they're the apple
of his eye.
And if you can look
at them like that
every day
and I challenge you
to do so
then you're going
to play your role
as Christian mother
with dignity.
Oh, what a role
you may say
just a Christian mother.
Is that it?
Just a Christian mother?
Do you know
of any role
do you know
of any career
that is comparable
with taking
a child
that belongs
to God
the first fruits
of all his creatures
a sort of
a special blessing
especially sacred
and especially
near to God
and training
that child
in the word
of God.
Do you know
of anything
that could tax
anyone
any greater than that?
You are
the greatest teacher
that your child
will ever have.
Whether you're going
to be the best teacher
or not, I don't know
but you're the greatest
because you're there first
and what you teach
your child
will never forget
and whatever you tell
your child
will believe it
because you
his mother said so.
And what have you done
as Christian mothers?
Oh, you've played
your role well.
You taught your children
how to pray
that they might feel
the nearness
of God with them
and you taught them
the word of God
and you brought them
to Sunday school
to church early in life
that they might
realize and know
what it means
to worship God
to hear the word
of God
and to allow
that word of God
to sow itself
within their own hearts
because
this is the temple
of God
to come in
to worship.
Last summer
it was my privilege
to be in Scotland
on Sunday.
We were in Glasgow
and when Sunday came
I wanted to go
to a Scotch Presbyterian church
and I looked up
the largest one
I could find
and we worshipped
there that morning.
The minister's name
was Reverend Bob Allen.
It was quite an experience
because I saw
an old ritual
that is carried out
in the Scotch Presbyterian church.
Carried out every Sunday.
The pulpit is rather high.
Besides the minister
and the chancellor
they have a man
who is called a beetle
which means a man
of secondary importance
as regards offices
in the church.
But when it came time
that Sunday morning
for the sermon
and the pulpit
rather high
the man called the beetle
got up from his place
he walked over
to a platform
and he picked up
the Bible
and he held it
very reverently
and carefully
and he climbed
the stairs
into the pulpit
and he opened
the Bible
and he laid it
in the pulpit
and then the beetle
turned this man
and he walked
down the stairs
and he walked over
to where the minister
was seated
and he motioned
for him to stand
and he took the minister
by the arm
and he brought him back
and brought him
up the stairs
into the pulpit
and stood him
in front of the word
of God
and then the beetle
gentleman
walked down the stairs
and took his place.
It's an ancient ritual
in the Scotch
Presbyterian church
and it has
a beautiful meaning
and the meaning
is simply this
first the word
of God
is placed
in the pulpit
and then comes
the minister
reminding him
that as he stands
in the pulpit
he is expected
to declare
the word of God
and only
the word of God.
You Christian mothers
play your role
well
you bring
your children
to God's house
that they might
here meet God
and through
the human clay
of a minister
that they might
confront him
and know
his nearness
that yours
may be
this satisfaction
that even
if sometime
in life
your children
may turn away
from God
there may be
something
left there
that you
gave them
that will
bring them
back.
I think
in my own
life
of a professor
I had
in one of my
courses in college
he was a very
brilliant man
his attitude
in the classroom
was anything
but what you
would want
but it was
out of the
classroom
and he would
speak vehemently
and with
blasphemy
against the
word of God
and he ridiculed
it
and it was
beneath the
dignity of an
educated man
and yet the
man came
from a
Christian home
but later
in life
in meeting
that same
professor
it was a
joy to know
that something
that a
Christian mother
had implanted
in his heart
brought about
a change
oh yes
he was a
PhD from
the University
of Chicago
but he came
back to a
living faith
in Jesus
Christ
and it was
all because
he had had
a Christian
mother
who had
inculcated
in him
the word
of truth
and he
realized
that he
had spoken
out of
turn
and he
came back
to a
living faith
oh you
Christian
mothers
I challenge
you this
Sunday
on Mother's
Day
that you
might say
I'm going
to see
my Christian
children
through the
eyes of
God
and I'm
going to
see them
as a
sort of
a first
fruit
something
special
really
uncommon
his
property
and his
possession
most sacred
the apple
of his
eyes
and you
ought to be
able to
see that
it isn't
too good
to be true
because something
extraordinary
has happened
to your
Christian
children
not only
have they
been born
again
not only
has the
Holy Spirit
come to dwell
in their
hearts
by faith
but also
God would
remind you
Christian
mothers
this
that God
has taken
your Christian
children
under his
wings
remember when
Jesus cried
over Jerusalem
and he said
oh Jerusalem
Jerusalem
how often
would I have
gathered thy
children together
even as a
hen gathered
her chickens
under her
wings
you and I
have seen
the side
of the hen
with the chickens
under her wings
it's a beautiful
thing isn't it
and God
Almighty
the God
of lights
with whom
is no
variableness
nor shadow
of turning
the God
who by the
magnificence
and the
power of his
word brought
a universe
into existence
tells you
mothers that
when baptism
your children
became his
he shelters
them
under his
wings
the God
Almighty
who sees
that nothing
shall happen
to them
beyond his
power
that nothing
shall ever
happen except
by his
permission
the God
who promises
to protect
your children
and mine
so that he
will overrule
every evil
for good
so that
they will be
able to live
until they
have fulfilled
the plan
and the mission
which God
has intended
for them
in giving
them life
oh something
extraordinary
has happened
to your
children
mothers
yes they
have been
endowed
with an
immortality
in this
world
to fulfill
a mission
God has
provided them
with talents
and abilities
and God
has assured
you that
when they
shall fulfill
that mission
for which he
gave them
life
they shall
complete it
to his honor
and glory
and therefore
because it's
too good
and it is
true
something
wondrously
has happened
something
extraordinary
something uncommon
has happened
to your children
therefore on this
Mother's Day
I challenge you
will you continue
to see your
Christian children
through the eyes
of God
and look at
them and say
why they're
a sort of
first fruits
they're something
special
they're especially
precious
they are especially
dear and near
to God
they mean
something
they're the apple
of his eye
just like the
first fruits of
the field
and the first
fruits of the womb
and I challenge
you if you look
at them like that
then early in life
you're going to
light the spark
in their lives
so that they
can fulfill
the plan
for which God
has given them
life
oh for children
to have
Christian mothers
who will say
Tommy lad
or genie
what are you
going to be
going to do
with your life
how are you
going to live it
do you realize
that there's a
reason for you
to be alive
what are you
going to do
how are you
going to spend
your days
to show your
love for God
how are you
going to live it
with your talents
and abilities
that you can
in this world
leave it a little
better
that you can
impress people
that you are
living out of
love for God
and make it easier
for someone else
to love your
Christ
oh I think
back
about 11 years
ago when I
stood at my
own mother's
grave
and I think
back to the
days when I
was a child
my mother
lit the spark
rather early
in life
to her there
was nothing
like the
Christian ministry
no one
ever said
one word
against the
Christian ministry
as regards
my mother
oh she was
not highly
educated
she had just
finished the
eighth grade
high school
was beyond
the reach
of many
in those
days
but to my
mother to be
a minister of
Jesus Christ
meant far more
than to be
president of
the United
States
but it was
lighted early
not only in
my own heart
but in my
brother's
so it
wasn't a
forced
thing
but again
this thing
can you
give your
life
in the
service of
Jesus Christ
just about
11 years
ago the
four of us
children we
stood at my
mother's grave
over in
Hammond Indiana
and Oak Hill
Cemetery
right near
South Chicago
where she
grew up
and spent
most of the
years of her
life there
in East
St. Louis
and I
remember as
we four
children stood
at her
grave
and my
father's
grave
alongside of
hers
there was
a sense
of gratitude
that we
four children
felt
and that
was that
they didn't
leave us
too much
as regards
earthly things
because they
didn't have
it
but all
four of us
could stand
at the
grave and
say but
mother and
dad did
leave us
this
they left
us a
Christian
faith
because we
are children
of God
and they
left us
a heritage
that even
time cannot
erase
and I
remember there
also came
this feeling
in her grave
that day
that I
had no
regrets
you know
there's one
thing that a
Christian mother
wants more
than ever in
life
she wants
to be loved
by her
children
she wants
to be
wanted
she doesn't
want to
feel like
a fifth
wheel
like she's
in the
way
she wants
to have
her children
rise up
and call
her blessed
isn't that it
Christian mothers
I could stand
at my
mother's grave
and we
four children
could say
we to the
best of our
ability we
let them know
we love them
and we took
care of them
because it was
a joy
and we
had no
regrets
and we
left her
grave
and the
four of
us went
to our
different
ways
we kissed
one another
goodbye
and my
older sister
left for
East St.
Louis
Illinois
my younger
sister for
Collinsville
Illinois
my brother
then to
Richmond
Indiana
and I
came back
to Marion
Ohio
having stood
at the grave
of a Christian
mother
yes
but one
who again
taught us
something
one who
wanted to
be loved
my heart
aches for
many of you
Christian mothers
today
who aren't
loved
whose children
do not
rise up
and call you
blessed
who don't
seem to
care
but I
challenge you
Christian mothers
who are still
training your
children
will you
look at them
every day
as being
a sword
of first
fruits
as something
special
in the sight
of God
something
just so
precious
and so
wonderful
that again
as you
train them
for life
that you
might have
the joy
someday
that they
will rise
up and
call you
blessed
I'd like
to ask
you as
your children
walk the
glory road
can they
sing in
the cross
of Christ
thy glory
towering
o'er the
wrecks of
time
all the
light of
sacred story
gathers round
its head
sublime
because
you told
them about
the cross
of Christ
oh if
they have
known
Christ
from you
and if
you can
see them
tussled
heads
to be
sure
as a
sword
of first
fruits
as something
special
as the
apple
of God's
eye
I wish
for you
today
that your
children
rise up
and they
call you
blessed
I wish
you a
blessed
Mother's
Day
Amen
The peace
of God
which passeth
all human
understanding
keep and
unite your
hearts and
minds in
Christ Jesus
unto life
everlasting
you