Grace be unto you and peace from God our Father and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God for this Sunday as we find it in our epistolary lesson.
Read there in Paul's letter to the Romans, the 11th chapter, especially the 33rd verse.
Oh, the depth of the riches, both of the wisdom and knowledge of God!
How unsearchable are his judgments and his ways past finding out!
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
Oh, Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, our Lord and Savior, dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Today, as I have mentioned, the Christian Church is celebrating Trinity Sunday.
This is the Sunday set aside so that Christians may take a look at their God and ask themselves,
who is God?
Is God a God worthy of praise and adoration and thanksgiving?
Trinity Sunday brings to an end the festival half of the church year.
We divide the regular church year into the festival half and also the non-festival half.
You remember this church year began in the Advent season,
and in the Advent season we prepared ourselves for the great festival of the blessing of Jesus coming into the world, his birthday.
Then, you know, came the Epiphany season, when we celebrated the festival of Epiphany,
when the Gentiles came and they found that Christ was also their Lord and their Savior.
Then we went into the Lenten season and there came Palm Sunday, when our Christ rode into Jerusalem.
Then came Good Friday, the very anniversary when he suffered and died for the sins of the world,
followed by Easter, the festival of the resurrection.
Forty days later, then came the Ascension, which we celebrated.
Ten days after the Ascension came Pentecost, the outpouring of the Holy Spirit,
the festival that we celebrated last Sunday.
Today now comes the festival of the Trinity.
This is a bit different from the other festivals, in that it does not commemorate any one great fact in history.
But this is a festival of the Christian church when we pause and we take a look at our God,
and we look at him and we ask ourselves, what is God like?
Is God worthy of our praise?
Is he worthy of our love?
Is God worthy of our obedience?
And this morning we are going to have a little Jew from Tarsus up in Cilicia answer the question for us.
When we look at Paul, who was also the great war horse of the Christian church,
and we ask him, Paul, is God worthwhile?
Is God a God who is worthy of our love and of our honor and of our praise?
The little Jew from up in Cilicia way would answer you and me,
God is a great God, and God is worthy of our love,
and he is worthy of our praise and worthy of our thanksgiving.
And all because this is what Paul found in him.
And he goes into this doxality, he says,
Oh, the depth of the riches, both of the wisdom and knowledge of God,
how unsearchable are his judgments and his ways past finding out.
In simple English, Paul of Tarsus says,
God is a great God.
God is worthy of your love and of your admiration,
because look at the riches of his wisdom and of his knowledge.
Oh, it is so deep, says Paul, the depth of it.
It is so immense.
It is so limitless.
It is absolutely so unlimited.
It is deeper than the ocean itself.
It is so vast.
It is absolutely so immense
that the best that we can do is only to scratch the surface of his intellect.
We can only grope.
We can never fully understand it.
We can never fully grasp it.
We can never fully digest it.
And so on Trinity Sunday,
Paul would say to you and me,
God is a God worth knowing.
Consider the riches of the depth of his wisdom and of his knowledge.
It is deeper than the ocean.
It is vast.
It is limitless.
It is immense.
And yet you and I on Trinity Sunday,
in looking at those words of Paul,
we may say to ourselves,
well, we'd like to believe that God is a God worth knowing
because of the depth of his wisdom and of his knowledge.
But we say, look at the world.
Look what the world says about the wisdom and the knowledge of God.
Isn't it so that the world looks at you and me as Christians and says,
you Christians are always talking about the depth of the knowledge and the wisdom of God.
You're talking about its immensity.
You're talking about its vastness.
You're trying to say that you cannot ever fully comprehend it.
And yet the world says the wisdom of God is nothing but nonsense.
The world says it's only foolishness.
It is ridiculous what you Christians call the wisdom and the knowledge of God.
Well, if God's wisdom and knowledge are ridiculous,
if, again, these things are foolishness,
if these things are nonsense,
then you and I would have to say that God is not a God worth knowing.
And yet Saul of Tarsus says, oh, the depth of the riches of his wisdom and of his knowledge.
Could it be possible that when the world hears of the riches of God's wisdom and understanding,
that the world, in calling it nonsense, does not realize that the wisdom and the knowledge of God are a higher wisdom,
a wisdom that the world has never dreamed of?
Perhaps as we look at the wisdom and the knowledge of God,
that you and I will see that here is wisdom and here is knowledge
that is so far above the wisdom of the world,
that no man of the world, regardless of his intellectual acumen,
regardless of his attainments,
has ever even dreamed of this kind of wisdom and this kind of knowledge.
This morning on Trinity Sunday, let's look at the wisdom and the knowledge of God.
Let's see whether it isn't a higher wisdom,
whether it isn't something that the world of intellect has never even dreamed of or thought of.
Would you like to see some of the wisdom of God and have it mentioned
that the world calls nonsense, but only because it has never even thought of such wisdom?
Here's the first thing.
The wisdom and the knowledge of God has revealed unto us that God is one God,
and yet at the same time he is three persons.
Today is Trinity Sunday.
Today is the Sunday when we stop and we look at our God and we say,
We have one God.
Here, O Israel, the Lord our God is one Lord.
And yet at the same time, this one God reveals himself as having three persons,
as being three persons.
God the Father, God the Son, and God the Holy Spirit,
and that these three are one, and yet they are distinct.
There is not three gods, there is one God.
And yet three persons in the world stand and say,
See, that is nonsensical.
That doesn't make sense.
That is foolishness.
That is ridiculous.
And yet you and I stand and we say to the world,
Look, is there any religion that is man-made that has a three-in-one God?
Is there any human mind that has ever conceived that God could be one God,
and yet at the same time three persons at the same time?
The world, if it's going to label the Trinity as being something nonsensical,
would have to prove that the world thought of it first,
and that the world discarded it as being absolutely unfit for human intellect.
And yet there is no Trinity in any other religion.
There are a multiplicity of gods, but not one God in three persons,
God the Father, God the Son, and God the Holy Spirit.
And so to the world, God says,
Here is knowledge, here is wisdom that is above the knowledge and wisdom of the world.
Here is wisdom that no human being has ever thought of.
And think of the wisdom of God in revealing himself as one God in three persons
that you and I cannot accurately understand,
that you and I cannot fully comprehend to be sure,
because who knows the mind of God?
Who has ever given advice to God?
And then, who has ever given something to God
that God in turn must give us something back?
And our God reveals himself in this wisdom and knowledge that is above human wisdom,
that again the world has never dreamed of that he is an eternal God.
That God is without beginning and without ending.
No human being has ever dreamed that God could be like that.
That there was never a time when God didn't exist.
There never will be a time when God will not exist.
That God is all-powerful.
That God can do anything.
God has revealed that he, God the Father, God the Son, and God the Holy Spirit,
that again God knows everything.
There is in God all knowledge.
Nothing is hidden from his eyes.
That God is a God of perfect wisdom.
That God uses his knowledge in the very best possible way
that God never makes any mistakes.
Oh, what a God he is.
That God is everywhere present.
All of God all over at the same time.
The world stands and says,
that's nonsense because we cannot comprehend such a God.
And yet the world must look up at a wisdom that is a higher wisdom.
No man has ever dreamed that God could fill heaven and earth.
God a person.
God, God the Father, God the Son, and God the Holy Spirit.
That everywhere at the same time it defies the imagination of man.
And yet here is wisdom.
When Paul of Tarsus saw it, he says,
Oh, the depths of the riches, both of the wisdom and knowledge of God.
God is a holy God.
No human being ever conceived of a holy God.
Look at the gods of all man-made religions,
and they are gods like unto men.
They are gods that are sinful.
They are gods, again, guilty of the same things,
the same transgressions as are human beings.
But here is a God who is holy without sin.
Here is a God who reveals himself as a righteous God.
A God that is always fair.
He never plays favorites.
And then our God has revealed something about himself
that no human brain has ever conceived,
and that he is a God of love.
Again, I challenge you,
go into any religion on the face of this earth.
Go into any religion.
You can spot it as a man-made religion,
apart from Christianity,
because no religion has the word love in it.
There isn't a human being on the face of the earth right now.
I care not his intellectual attainments,
who has ever dreamed that God could love him.
God has revealed himself as a God of love.
This is the God who, again,
has a depth of wisdom deeper than the ocean itself,
so immense, so inexhaustible, so limitless,
that you and I stand and say,
he's a God worth knowing,
because he's also a God who is trustworthy,
a God who keeps his promises.
And the word of God reveals
that in this wisdom and in this knowledge of God,
God tells us that God the Father created the universe,
that he created it for himself,
and it exists by his guidance and strength,
and that it shall accomplish the goal for which God did create it.
Paul could only say in his doxology,
for of him and through him and to him are all things.
God created the universe out of nothing.
He spoke by the power of his word.
And the world says that's foolishness.
And yet our God, here is a wisdom that is above human wisdom,
that God brought something out of nothing,
that God sustains this universe,
that he, by his laws,
which are nothing but the expressions of his will,
that God keeps this universe intact,
and that it shall be for him,
for the honor and glory and praise of his name.
That's the God that the little Jew up in Tarsus and Cilicia saw.
And that's why when he looked at the immensity of God,
he says, oh, the depth of the riches.
How deep the riches of the wisdom and the knowledge of God!
How unsearchable are his judgments and his ways past finding out!
This wisdom of God, is it nonsense?
Is it foolishness?
Is it something ridiculous?
Or again, is it heavenly wisdom that is above the wisdom of mankind?
And because on Trinity Sunday,
you and I see the depth of God's riches
in his wisdom and in his knowledge,
and we say to ourselves, it is immense,
and we can never completely grasp it.
We can only skype the surface.
Therefore, when Trinity Sunday comes,
and this is the Sunday when we honor God,
we ought to say, God is a God worth knowing.
And when we honor him as our God,
then we begin to realize that he is the only true God.
You and I have never seen God, have we?
And yet, how can we know that he is the only true God?
For the very obvious reason,
that in this wisdom and in this knowledge
which God has revealed about himself,
you and I find a God that we have never dreamed of,
a God that you and I can never even hope exists,
and yet a God that is perfect in all things
that you and I would never add one thing to him.
And when we realize that he is the only true God,
what does it mean for us today?
Doesn't it mean this,
that we can face the future without worry and without fear
and without questioning God's guidance into our life?
Oh, sometimes when sickness and adversity come to us,
we say, why did God send it to me?
And we look at our lives and we say,
yes, I know that I'm a sinner,
but I have never deliberately offended God.
I have worked in his kingdom.
I have tried to be a child of God to the best of my ability.
And why has God allowed these things to come?
But when you and I see the immensity of God's wisdom and power,
and we know that nothing happens in our life
except by his permission,
and we look at little Saul from Tarsus,
and we realize that there was the man,
the great war horse of the Christian church,
who knew what it was to have a thorn in the flesh,
and who knew again that God's grace was able to sustain him,
he realized that he couldn't understand the wisdom of God in his life,
but he knew this, that God was not punishing him,
and he knew that God was correcting him,
making of him what God wanted.
He realized that God was refining his life
as God refines your life and as he refines mine,
that in the refinements that come,
God can see his image in your life and mine.
We can face the future unafraid without worry,
without questioning and asking
why God allows things to come into your life and mine,
because we can stand on Trinity's Son and say,
he's a God worth knowing.
Look at the depth of his wisdom and knowledge.
It's deeper than the ocean,
it's immense, it's vast,
and a God who is that big,
in the great revelation of his knowledge and of his will,
is a God that is bigger than any need that arises in my life,
and you and I can have that joy and that peace
which the world cannot give
and which the world doesn't understand.
Today, it's an unusual festival.
It doesn't commemorate any event,
but this is the festival of the Trinity
when we take a look at our God
and we look at him and we say,
is he a God worth knowing?
Is he a God that I need in my life
or can I live without him?
And when Saul of Tarsus,
the little Jew from up Cilicia way,
looked at him,
he could only burst out and say,
oh, the depth of the riches,
both of the wisdom and the knowledge of God.
How unsearchable are his judgments
in these ways past finding out?
Paul said, let me tell you,
God is a God worth knowing.
He's worthy of honor and praise.
Look at him because his wisdom and his knowledge,
they're vast, they're deeper than the ocean.
Again, they are immense,
and you and I cannot ever completely understand
or grasp.
We can only look and see.
Why?
Because have you ever seen the wisdom of God?
What God has revealed,
the things that we know
that the world calls nonsense,
but only because the world doesn't realize
that it never dreamed of.
Here's the second thing.
The wisdom and the knowledge of God
have revealed that God's Son,
Jesus Christ,
atoned for the sins of the world.
The world looks and says,
you Christians,
when you talk about Christ and Calvary,
you're talking nonsense.
You're talking something that is foolishness.
You're talking something that is so ridiculous
that it is not worthy for the intellect of man.
And yet you and I look at them and we say,
when a man looks at Calvary
and a man rejects Calvary,
and when a man looks at the cross of Jesus Christ
and rejects him because it's foolishness,
that man must be able to say that he thought of that,
that he thought of a Christ and of a Calvary,
that he rejected it
because it was not even something
that was in keeping with the human intellect.
But I ask you,
go into any religion on the face of the earth
and you'll find two things absent.
There will be no Christ
and there will be no cross.
There will be no Savior.
And yet you and I stand
and we look at this wisdom of God
and we say,
who was this Jesus on the cross?
And the Word of God says,
he was very God,
a very God,
King of kings and Lord of lords.
In your intellect and mind we say,
but how could one man
atone for the sins of the world?
And again we look at him
and God answers,
because he was God,
because he was no less than uncreated God,
the Son of our great Trinity,
he was of more value than the human race.
And then our minds say,
but how could he,
when he died on the cross,
bear the equal of an eternity
in hell for the human race?
And as we stand at Calvary again,
just to scratch the surface
and we hear him cry out,
my God, my God,
why hast thou forsaken me?
We realize that he was forsaken of God,
but between God the Father
and God the Son,
there was laid on him to,
again,
too high for your mind
and mine to understand,
there was laid on him
an eternity in hell
for all men
and on the cross
in that suffering and death.
Someway, somehow,
he bore its equal for you and me
because he was God.
And we stand and the world says,
it's nonsense,
it's foolishness,
but there is no Christ,
there is no cross
in the human wisdom
of mankind.
And therefore,
there is this glorious assurance
that in the wisdom of God,
not only did the Son,
Jesus Christ,
bear the guilt
and the punishment
of the world,
but in his righteousness,
there is life
and salvation
for all men.
The world says,
how foolish
to have a substitute,
that in the blood,
in the merit
of one person,
there could be life
and salvation
for the world.
Listen,
if that is foolishness,
then man must have
thought of it first
and man must have
rejected it.
But man has never dreamed
of a Christ,
of a Savior,
who could be so big
and yet a human being,
born flesh of our flesh
and bone of our bone
only without sin,
who could bring life
and salvation
for the world.
That's the kind of a God.
And is it any wonder
that Saul of Tarsus,
who realized his sin
and the enormity of it,
he looked at God
and he says,
God is a God
worth knowing.
And when he met God
on the Damascus way,
he realized
that God is someone
that is worthy
of praise and thanksgiving.
Look at his wisdom.
Oh, it's deeper
than the ocean.
It's immense.
It is inexhaustible.
It is limitless.
And that's why
on Trinity
we ought to say,
God is a God
worth knowing.
I need him in my life.
And therefore,
I shall repent
and put my trust
in Christ
as my Lord
and as my Savior.
We've all been reading
and again been aware
of the fact
that the Pope,
the head of the Roman Catholic Church
has recently died.
In the providence of God,
I had wished
that he might have lived
so that the ecumenical conference
might be reconvened
this fall,
which he was intending to do.
A man of peace
has died to be sure.
I had wished
for an ecumenical conference
because,
say what you will,
Christendom
is still divided.
And it is divided
on a very basic
and fundamental
and important issue.
And that is
the way to heaven.
Let's not forget it
and all of the movements
and the unions
of Christians
that the fundamental basis,
how do you go to heaven?
I had wished
and I still hope
that there will be
an ecumenical meeting
because in the Roman Catholic Church
today,
there are two commissions
that are studying
in that very problem.
One studying
the answer of the church
and the other group
studying the answer
of the word of God.
What does
the word of God say?
The word of God
says that the way to heaven
is Christ
and Christ alone,
Christ and his merits
without any merit
or worthiness
in your life
and mine.
Therefore,
if the way to heaven
is Jesus Christ,
then if you and I
repent and put our trust
in him,
then there comes to us
that peace
which the world
cannot give,
a peace that will never
question our eternal salvation.
And yet,
isn't it strange
on that basis
how many of us
even as Protestants
do not understand
what it means
to be saved
by Christ alone
or by grace alone.
Just a moment,
if you know
what it means
to be saved
by grace
or if I do,
it ought to mean
this to us,
that on the day
of our death,
and you see,
you've got to die alone
and so do I.
This thing isn't
a matter of
determining
who's going to have
the greatest following.
It is a matter
so important
that when the day
comes that you die
and you die alone,
that I die
and that I die alone,
that you and I
know the way to heaven.
That will be
the only thing
that matters.
If you and I
understand
what it means
to be saved
by grace
or by Christ alone,
it should mean
this on the day
of your death
and mine
when we're ready
to go into death alone
without human help.
It ought to mean
this that we say
something like this,
Lord, I've done
a lot of fine things
in life
in your kingdom.
I have done
a lot of good things.
I have done them
out of love
and out of appreciation
for my salvation
in Christ.
We ought to be able
to say,
Lord, I've given
my life for you.
I have been
the kind of a steward
that you would want
me to be
to a certain extent.
But if you know
what it means
to be saved by grace,
we ought to say,
but Lord,
these things end
right here.
Now, Lord,
since I am ready
to face death,
I leave all
of the fine things
that I have done
in life right here.
They shall stay
right here
because they will
do me no good
when I take
the next step
into eternity.
To be saved
by grace
means that then
we turn in the spirit
of this little Jew
from Tarsus
and that we say,
but Lord,
I know that I am
the chief of sinners,
even as Paul
admitted it,
and I know that
all of these things
that I have done,
they don't save me.
They are an expression
of my love.
I know that as regards
my salvation,
these things
are filthy rags
because they are
selfish at best.
They are not perfect,
but I know
a righteousness
that is perfect
and that's the
righteousness
of my Christ
and my Lord.
Then if you and I
really know
what it means
to be saved
by grace,
then we will stand
and face death
and we will say,
Lord Jesus,
I leave here
every decent thing
that I have ever done
for you because
from here on
it won't do me
a bit of good.
I rest my hope
and faith simply
means a simple trust.
If you don't know
what I am talking about,
I put my trust
and my confidence
in heaven,
in you,
Lord Jesus Christ,
in your goodness,
in your merit,
in your righteousness,
what you earn
for me on Calvary
and I die
in that trust
and in that faith
and in that confidence.
That's what it means
to be saved
by grace.
Do you know that?
How many of us
belong to organizations
that talk about Christianity
where again,
Christianity
and salvation
seems to be
a human achievement?
May I just say
to you today,
watch your soul.
When death comes
to you and me,
we're going
in it alone.
And if you don't
know the Christ
who says,
I am the way,
if you don't understand
what it means
to be saved
by grace alone
without human achievement,
my heartfelt prayer
is you don't get out
of this church
this morning.
You aren't ready
to die
until you know
the story of grace.
This is Trinity Sunday
and thank God
the wisdom
that the world
calls foolishness,
the wisdom
that the world
says is ridiculous
because the world
wants human achievement.
Thank God
that our God
is a God
worth knowing
because he has
made known
wisdom and knowledge
that no human being
has ever dreamed of.
That like the malefactor
on the cross
who didn't have
one decent thing
in his favor
but who could turn
in a real
childlike trust
and say,
Lord Jesus,
remember me
when you come
into your kingdom
you and I
aren't ready
to make that
journey alone
because we are
on the wrong way.
That's Trinity Sunday.
When again
the little Jew
from Tarsus
who had met
that Lord
and who knew
that he was
chief of sinners
looked at God
and said,
oh,
what a God
we've got
worthy of again
of our love
and of our honor.
What did he say?
Oh,
the depth of the riches
of his wisdom
and knowledge.
Do you want to know
some wisdom
and knowledge
that has been revealed
that is above
the wisdom
of the world
not only
that our God
is one God
and yet three persons
not only
that Jesus Christ
God's Son
atoned for the sins
of the world
but God
the Holy Spirit
makes dead men
alive again.
The world says,
you Christians
in talking about
the Holy Spirit
coming to a man
and making a man
that is dead
alive again
how ridiculous
and how foolish
can you get?
and you and I say
but isn't it
a strange thing
when the Holy Spirit
came on Pentecost
that by means
of his word
that he can penetrate
into a human heart
that we are all
born dead
we are born
without the knowledge
of God
you and I
by nature
don't even know
who God is
you and I
have no fear
in love of God
we don't even know
who he is
to fear in love
you and I
are born
with concupiscence
we're born
with a downward
bent to hell
and you know
and so do I
we're all born
going down
to the barnyard
that's the way
we're born
because we're
spiritually dead
we love them
we don't love God
then isn't it strange
that this Holy Spirit
the third person
of the Trinity
through the word of God
comes and makes
dead men alive again
what's the world
going to do
it can yell
all at once
to and say
this is ridiculous
this is crazy
but look at the
kingdom of God
look at the hundreds
and millions
of who have stood up
and said
we've been born again
of water and the spirit
we have come into
a living relationship
with God
we have learned
what it means
to trust in Jesus Christ
and we have been
born again
we are twice born men
men that have gone out
and given their lives
for Jesus Christ
and the world says
you're crazy
and you're fools
and you and I say
oh the depth
of the rich
is both of the wisdom
and the knowledge of God
and oh it's such
a marvelous wisdom
because the Holy Spirit
assures you and me
that he works
with all the power
that is needed
on any man
to bring any man
to life
when a man
has come into this world
being born dead in sin
there isn't anybody
within the sound
of my voice
who if he allows
God the Holy Spirit
through the word
to come into his heart
but what that spirit
will make him alive
any man within
the sound of my voice
right now
who is going to be lost
on the last day
and repudiated
is going to be lost
because he said
no to the Holy Spirit
it is not because
the Holy Spirit
did not work effectively
in his heart
it is because
a man repudiated it
and said it's nonsense
it's ridiculous
it is only something
to laugh at
and that's why
on Trinity Sunday
oh it's a strange festival
it's the time
when we look at God
you and I
ought to give him
our thanks
and say I can't live
without him
he is worthy
of my trust
and then we ought
to thank him
that he has called us
why did God
ever call you
why did he ever
call me
if there was ever
a time when I felt
humble and wondered
that same question
it's when I was
down in Egypt
and I was down
in Luxor
450 miles
south of Cairo
I saw filth
and poverty
and ignorance
the likes of which
I never realized
existed in this world
people living
in the tombs
with the dead
groveling
in dirt
and in sand
blinded
nothing to eat
ignorant
dirty
filthy
when I stood
in that squalor
I said to myself
I wonder why
God ever
called me
in Jesus Christ
I wonder why
I was born
in a Christian home
in America
I wonder why
I was born
where I was born
and not over here
and I had to say
to myself
I didn't deserve it
and neither do you
nor does any man
why were you
and I
born
where we're born
and why
the other man
in the squalor
where he finds himself
when you and I
look and we grasp
at the very knowledge
and the wisdom
of God
we say
God must have
called us
for a purpose
and when Paul
realized
and said
why did God
call me
remember when Paul
said he appeared
to me as one
born out of due time
the Greek word
is fetus
the little Jew
said God
appeared to me
as a fetus
as an unborn
premature child
something that's
horrible to look at
I'm a fetus
why did God
ever call me
and then he said
but he did call me
and I owe a debt
of gratitude
to the world
I'm going to share
this God
I'm going to pay
my debt of gratitude
I'm going out
and I'm going to
tell men
about Jesus Christ
we're sitting here
an American
we've got some
of the grandest
blessings that
God Almighty
ever gave
and some of us
sit on our hands
and we've never
said to ourselves
why did God
ever choose me
why am I saved
and we don't
turn our hand
to sharing it
with someone else
when are we
going to say
here is a wisdom
the world
can laugh at it
can call it
nonsense
the world
can say it's crazy
but oh
Saul of Tarsus
yes the great
war horse
he said
I'm not ashamed
of the gospel
of Christ
why it's the
power of God
to salvation
to every man
that believeth
he says
and to the Jews
I know a stumbling
block
and to the Gentiles
it's foolishness
but to them
that are called
the power of God
and the wisdom
of God
today
have your eyes
seen the glory
can you say
mine eyes
have seen the glory
of a great God
and I can't live
without him
can you go out
on the glory road
and say I love
to tell the story
of unseen things
above
of Jesus
and his glory
and his love
I love to tell
the story
because a note
is true
it satisfies
my longing
as nothing else
can do
I love to tell
the story
it will be my
theme and glory
to tell the old
old story
of Jesus
and his love
Trinity Sunday
is God
a God worth having
oh he is
look at his
wisdom and knowledge
look at its depth
deeper than the ocean
limitless
vast
so much
that you and I
can never
completely understand it
but oh
when we have
experienced it
in our lives
the wisdom of God
and the power
of God
amen
the peace of God
which passeth all
human understanding
keep and unite
your hearts and minds
in Christ Jesus
unto life
everlasting