Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the Word of God, the regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday,
as we find it in the first letter of John, the fourth chapter, part of the sixteenth verse.
God is love.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, the Christ of Christian fathers, dear friends,
you who are here in God's house this morning, and you also, Christian friends,
who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Today, as you know, is the first Sunday after Trinity.
It is the Sunday that begins the non-festival half of the church year.
You recall last Sunday we celebrated Trinity Sunday,
and that Sunday marked the end of the festival half.
That means from now on to the end of this church year,
we shall number the Sundays after Trinity,
today being the first, and we will find that there will be 24 Sundays after Trinity
in this non-festival half of the church year.
Today, however, is not only the first Sunday after Trinity,
it is also Father's Day, since it is the third Sunday in June.
And our text for today is very appropriate for the occasion.
Speaking to us in the word of God is John,
the beloved disciple, the disciple whom Jesus loved.
And John, in speaking to us in the word of God,
says this about our God,
God is love.
We may say to ourselves here in church this morning,
what does that mean?
If we could just bring that down to where you and I live
and make it simple, it means this.
The fact that God is love in your life and mine,
therefore that means that if the very heart of God is love,
if the very core of his essence is love,
then it simply means that in your life and mine,
God ever yearns and longs for our eternal salvation,
never for our eternal loss,
regardless of what our attitude may be towards him,
regardless of how we treat him.
That's what it means when the word of God says,
God is love.
It means that you and I can snub our nose at God if we want to.
It means that you and I can be very hostile.
It means that you and I can treat him as the very dust under our feet.
It means that you and I may turn in rebellion against God,
but God still yearns and longs for our eternal good,
never for our eternal loss.
The one thing that God hopes will never happen to you or me
is that you and I would lose our soul.
That's what it means when the word of God says,
God is love.
And somehow or other you and I this morning may say to ourselves,
that sounds just a little bit too good to be true.
Do you mean to say that we can trample God underfoot,
that you and I can thumb our noses at God,
that we can ridicule him,
that we can laugh at him,
and that God still yearns,
that from the depths of his soul he desires our eternal good
and never our eternal harm,
that it makes no difference how we react to him,
it makes no difference how we treat him,
that he still longs and wants us saved.
We may say,
Oh, that can't be like God.
God can't be like that.
Because, you see,
you and I feel we can't be like that.
And how in the world could God be a God like that?
But on this Father's Day,
as we look at God,
and the word of God says that he is love,
his very heart,
the essence of his being is love,
not only is God that kind of a God,
whoever aims for our eternal welfare
and never for our loss,
regardless of how we treat him,
not only is God that kind of a God,
but he has demonstrated that kind of love to us,
and he's proved it.
Look at this in the first place.
God promised a Savior to us
when we were his enemies.
Don't forget that.
God, out of love
and out of the omnipotence that was his,
he brought this universe into being,
not only to show the glory of his very being,
but also that he might demonstrate his love,
and he created man in his own image,
and he put man, Adam and Eve,
our first parents on this earth,
that God might love them
and that they might in turn love him.
And what happened?
When God created our first parents
and created them in holiness and in righteousness
that they might serve him in love,
they chose not to love him,
and they disobeyed,
and they did that which they knew was wrong.
When they ate of the tree
that God told them not to eat of,
and they became God's enemies,
and then when you go to the Garden of Eden,
what happened?
When Adam and Eve realized that they were naked
and they ran and they hid themselves,
God called, did he not,
and said, Adam, where are you?
It was the first call of love to God's enemies.
And because our first parents were the world,
therefore they were you and they were me.
And because, again, God said, where are you?
There was the love of God,
and when God spoke to Satan
and to Adam and Eve that day,
he said, and I will put enmity
between thee and the woman,
between thy seed and her seed.
It shall bruise thy head,
and thou shalt bruise his heel.
God promised that from Eve
would come the seed of the woman,
a Savior,
who again would bring life and salvation
while we were his enemies.
God is a God of love,
and he demonstrated in the very Garden of Eden
when sin came into the world.
And not only did God demonstrate it in promise,
but God fulfilled that promise,
and he sent the Savior in spite of the way
his children treated him.
Did you ever read the Old Testament
and see just what a response
God's children gave him in response to his love?
Did you ever say,
well, how could God be a God of love?
How could God love and desire our salvation
and never our loss?
How could God be a God who would say
that the one thing I never want to have happen
is that you'd be lost
in spite of the way you treat me?
Now look in the Old Testament.
Here, Adam and Eve had sons, Cain and Abel,
and from Abel was to come the Christ,
and Cain killed Abel.
You'd have thought God would have said,
that's enough, I'm through.
And yet God raised up another son, Seth, didn't he?
And you come down to the time of Noah.
And in the time of Noah,
God gave the people,
because they were so wicked,
120 years to repent.
And God loved them.
And yet in spite of 120 years of entreaty,
the world turned against God,
and they forced God to bring destruction.
Even though God's love continued,
his love was not abated.
God still loved them,
and a million times desired their salvation
rather than their loss.
But because it was unrequited love,
it was an unresponsive love to God,
there came punishment.
But the love of God saved Noah and his wife,
and the three sons and their three wives.
Then you go on down to Abraham,
who dwelt in the home of idols.
God's people were forgetting him.
And God chose Abraham,
and brought him from the land of Ur of the Chaldees
into the land of Palestine.
And God told him that he would have a son,
and from that son would come Jesus Christ,
the Savior.
And again, Abraham and Sarah couldn't wait,
and they didn't believe.
And so there was the incident with Hagar,
and with Ishmael being born.
But finally God gave them a son because God loved.
And then there came from Isaac and his wife,
Rebekah, there came Esau and Jacob.
And Jacob couldn't wait for the birthright.
He had to get it by intrigue.
And he had to flee for his life.
But the love of God was there.
And finally Jacob came back,
and then they sold Joseph into slavery.
And they came on down into Egypt,
and they were down in Egypt over 300 years.
And God raised up a Moses,
and he led them back into the land of Palestine,
and gave them the land that David came on the throne.
And finally because mankind turned against God,
there came Nebuchadnezzar in the year 586 before Christ
and destroyed the southern kingdom
and carried the Jews away into Babylonian captivity
for 70 years.
But there was the love of God
because a man by the name of Cyrus,
the Cyrus who was the Mede and the Persian,
arose, and by the providence of God
he enabled the Jews to go back to their own land.
And then there came 400 years of silence,
and then finally God broke the silence,
and God fulfilled his promise,
and the Savior that God promised in Eden
came into the world.
You talk about the love of God,
you and I can say,
you mean that God is love,
that his heart is love,
that God ever would plan and yearn
for our eternal welfare,
never our damnation,
in spite of the way we treat him.
Look in the history of the word of God,
and you find that love is there,
and it was demonstrated
beyond the shadow of a wish.
And today is Father's Day.
And as one father to another father,
this ought to be the day when we look at God
and we say that God is love.
That means that in spite of the attitude of man,
in spite of the reaction of man to God,
in spite of whether man is friendly or hostile,
that God ever yearns and longs
for a man's eternal goodness and ever his evil,
then we ought to say to ourselves today,
God, I want to be loved even as you are loved.
We as Christian fathers ought to say to ourselves,
God, I want to be like you in this.
I want to love even as you love me.
And if you and I as fathers would love that way,
then and only then would we know
how to treat our wives
who are the mothers of our children.
How do you treat a wife?
How does a Christian husband and father
treat a wife?
What's the criterion?
What's the principle on which this thing is worth?
It's rather strange.
Some of you young girls contemplating marriage come.
Some of you who are already married
have come to me and have said,
How do you know that you really love somebody?
How can you be sure
that even though you have married somebody
that you love him?
Now there ought to be affection
in a home to be sure.
I gave you a test once
and I don't know of a better one
to know whether you really have affection
and real love
and if there's an appeal to your mate.
Can you use his toothbrush?
I don't know of anything any better.
If you can use his toothbrush
or he can use yours.
There's affection.
There's real love.
But there's got to be a higher love
than that of affection
because again,
there are stresses and strains in marriage
where there's got to be something even higher.
There's got to be this love
that God has for us.
There's got to be in the home
on the part of a Christian father
this kind of love
that his aim and his longing at all times
is for the eternal welfare of his wife
and the mother of his children
and never to treat her in any way
whereby he might jeopardize
and endanger her eternal welfare.
I ask you this morning,
can you imagine a home
where father and mother
are motivated with this love that God has
where both of them have this criterion
and this principle
in treating one another
that this is the basis
that it's love
that there is every yearning
for the eternal salvation of the other one.
Never to say or do anything
that might endanger
or that might thwart
the eternal welfare of the other person.
Can you imagine how
under the most grave circumstances
any home could ever be broken in divorce?
I can't.
And yet what sometimes you wives come and you say
but there are problems in marriage.
You say we've been brought up
to know a certain thing is wrong.
We've been brought up to say again
this thing of sex is wrong
and suddenly you're married
and then suddenly everything becomes right
can you say we have a guilty feeling
in the marital act
which is ours again
as husband and wife.
What is the answer to that?
Again, bear this in mind.
When the commandment says
thou shalt not commit adultery,
the word adultery,
we get the word adulterate from that
and that word means
again to spoil something that is good.
God doesn't tell us
that there's anything wrong in sex.
There is nothing wrong
with marital cohabitation
but God has set that aside for marriage
and it was wrong
not that it is wrong in itself
but it was wrong before marriage
that in marriage it might be used
and it might be used
in the love that God has for us.
When husband and wife
can again,
can engage in the marital relationships,
the intimate relationship
with a love toward one another
that God has to them
with again this kind of love
that there is a yearning
for the eternal salvation of one another
and never for that person's loss
regardless of the relationship
then that feeling of guilt goes away.
Then there is a love of concern
for the eternal welfare
and then and only then
can you and I have the joy
that homes are not going to be broken up.
Oh, it does make a difference
when we marry him.
There was Mark Twain, Samuel Clemens,
you and I remember him as a humorist
and we think about his huckleberry fin
but after his death, you know,
there was probably some of his writings
which certainly do him no credit.
We know him as a humorist
but how many of us know Mark Twain
as a man that was an infidel,
a man that hated the very ground
God walked on,
a man that spewed at God,
a man that had no use for him,
that treated God as the scum under his feet.
You know, he married a Christian girl
and when he proposed to her,
she said that I'm a Christian
and I want grace at the table
and of course, like all young men,
he told her that was fine,
he would be happy to have it
and so there was grace
at the Samuel Clemens table for a while
and one day when she bowed her head
and she prayed,
he looked at her
and with all the vehemence
and the bitterness that he could muster,
he looked at her and he said,
shut up!
I never want to hear it again!
From that day on
in Mark Twain's home,
there was no prayer at the table.
Why?
Because Mark Twain hated God.
It would have been better
they had buried his ridiculous writings
against God with him.
He was a humorist,
but he was a hater of God.
He never knew the love of God.
It was not a happy home.
There was no love.
Christian fathers,
when we look at God
and if the heart of God is love
and that means that God yearns
for the salvation of you and me
regardless of our reaction to him,
it's going to have to be in the home.
And because God has made you and me
as fathers the head of the home,
whether we want to be or not,
God expects you and me to be like him,
that we shall be godly in love,
that we shall know how to treat our wives
who are the mothers of our children
if the home is going to stand.
Today is Father's Day
and John the beloved disciple says,
God is love.
Look at God
and he says,
the very heart of God is love.
The very soul of his being is love.
And that means simply again
that God yearns
and he longs for our eternal welfare,
never for our eternal loss.
The one thing that God hopes
will never happen to any man
is that a man be lost
regardless of how a man treats him,
regardless of whether a man
tramples him underfoot.
And God has demonstrated
that kind of love.
He is that kind of a God
because in the second place,
know this,
that God sent his son
to atone for the sins of the world.
And the world includes
not only those who would be friendly to God,
but it includes also his enemies.
You've got to stand at the cross of Calvary
once in a while,
look and say,
for whom did Christ die?
For whom did Jesus,
the son of God on the cross,
bear the guilt
and the punishment
of the world's sin?
Was it just for those
who were going to be friendly to God?
Or did he die for his enemies?
Didn't Jesus say,
one day that scarcely
will a man die for his friends?
But again,
Jesus died for his enemies
while we were yet enemies.
God loved us.
And God sent his only son
into the world.
Jesus Christ died for the guilt
and the punishment
of the world's sins.
And that includes everybody's.
And you and I may say,
oh, it seems too good to be true
that God could love
and always yearn for our salvation
and never want our eternal loss.
Listen, at Calvary,
he demonstrated it
because Christ, again,
that sacrifice of his
was an eternal sacrifice.
He was the lamb slain
from the foundation of the world
that in Jesus Christ
and in his shed blood
there might be provided
for the world
forgiveness, life, and salvation.
Did Christ, by his atonement,
provide the forgiveness of sins
only for a few,
for the friendly,
and not for those
who again trample God underfoot?
That whosoever,
that includes everybody,
doesn't it?
And there is the forgiveness
of sins.
God said,
I am willing to wipe out
of my mind forever
the guilt of all men's sins,
that I will remember them
no more,
that God says,
I'll never even think about them.
I will deliver any man
from death.
I will save any man
for heaven
because my son
on the cross
made those blessings available.
That's the love of God.
And then when you come
to Father's Day
and we say to ourselves
as Christian fathers,
what does God ask of us?
What God asks of us
is this,
if God is love,
that you and I be love.
That means that you and I
be little gods,
that we be like God
in this.
that there will be
a yearning,
a longing,
a real concern
for the eternal good
of all men,
never for the eternal evil
of a man,
regardless of how
he treats us.
And if that would be
in your life and mine,
then and only then
do we learn
how to treat our children.
How does a father
treat his children?
Some of us don't know,
do we?
When I was a young lad
in school,
I had some asthma problems
and I went to a doctor
and took a very great
liking to me
and I used to go out
to his home.
He didn't have any children
and I said to him,
a brilliant man,
you've been with
Mayo Brothers for years.
Finally,
in my own boyish way,
I said to him,
well, Dr. Miller,
how does it come
that you don't have
any children?
He looked at me
quite seriously
and he said,
because it's too grave
a responsibility
to be the father
of children,
a brilliant man
who didn't feel
equal to the task
and I'm sure
that all of us
as parents
have said to ourselves
at times,
who is equal
to the task
of being a parent
for children?
And yet we say,
how do you treat
your children?
If God treats us
in love,
that God ever aims
for our eternal welfare,
then the way
to treat our children
is this,
that at all times,
this is the criterion
and the principle,
that we will treat them
so that we will,
in every way possible,
we will help them
in their way
to heaven
and never hinder them.
And oh,
that means discipline
to be sure.
Children do not
object to discipline
when it is done
in love
for their eternal welfare.
I can think back
today on Father's Day,
can't you think back
of some of the disciplines
you had?
I think back
of this for instance,
in my home,
I could have
a piece of bread
and butter
anytime I wanted it,
and I could have
a piece of bread
with jelly on
anytime I wanted it,
but in my home,
I could never have
a piece of bread
with butter
and jelly.
Never.
Why,
my mother thought
that was extravagance
and so did my father.
I could have
two pieces of bread,
the one with butter
and the other with jelly,
but you never
combined them
in my home.
That's the way I was.
Did I resent it?
No.
That was extravagance
in my parents' language
and we just
didn't do it.
You talk about
discipline,
I can remember
with my father
was sick in bed
only once
that I can remember
before his death
and it happened
to be a heart attack
and in those days
when a man
had heart trouble,
the first thing
that he was relieved of
was the eating of meat.
And I can think back
as a child in my home
the day the doctor said
you can no longer
eat meat
and I remember
the reaction
of my mother,
if father can't eat meat
there will be no meat
on our table
and I grew up
through my formative years
in a real vegetarian home.
I didn't know
what meat looked like.
There wasn't any.
My mother said
I will not put meat
on the table
if your father
can't eat it.
We're not going
to eat it either.
We didn't.
I can think back
I suppose
that's why I love meat today.
We didn't resent it
and even bologna
which I kid about
even tastes good.
I don't suppose
I'll ever get enough meat.
I couldn't have a dog
when I was a child
but I got one now
but it was a home
of Christian love.
I didn't resent it
because there's got
to be discipline
even as God
disciplines you
and me
and in that love
where there are
Christian fathers
and mothers
where again
there is the aim
to enhance
a child's eternal welfare
and never to jeopardize it
or to endanger it
there's got to be
the discipline
also of Christian training.
If you and I
have come out
of a home
where our parents
brought us to church
we ought to be able
to thank God.
I see no trouble
in homes
when father is along
and I like to look out
in the kind of game
I like to see you men.
People say church
is for old ladies
and children.
It isn't.
It's for men
and I want to see you men.
It's for you fathers
and you fathers
that are here this morning
that have your kids
alongside of you.
Listen.
They're as proud
as peacocks
of you
and you know it.
You are the hero
of their life.
As far as I'm concerned
with my children
I want them to love me
not just because
I'm their father
I want them to love me
because I am what I am.
And that's what you want too
isn't that so?
Is there any greater assurance
that your kids
will love you
for what you are?
Accept this
that you have learned
to love them
with the love
that God has
for you and me.
The kind of a love
that you aim
for their eternal welfare
regardless of how
they may treat you
and you never desire
their eternal loss.
I want men in church
and I want a man
in the pulpit
a man's man
and I don't want anybody
a feminine
a sissy
in the pulpit
because we want men.
When men are here
women will be here too.
You talk about
kids loving you
what greater joy
can you have?
Your kids and mine
will love us
if we just treat them
with just a little
half of love
that God has for us.
I think back
with my one child
she was just
four years old
I was studying
one morning
she ran up the stairs
and came in
bright eyed
and said
here daddy
I picked you
a bouquet of flowers
she handed to me
and they were dandelions
but I never got
a grander bouquet
in all my life.
What more
could you ask for
in life
than a bouquet
of flowers
from a child
given in love
because they loved
you as father
they loved you
as daddy
that's living
isn't it?
Today is Father's Day
and John the beloved
disciple
looked at Jesus
and he looked at God
through the eyes
of Jesus
and he was able
to write
God is love
and God is love
and that means
in your life
that God ever yearns
and longs for our
eternal wealth
or never for our loss.
God is on the side
of saving us
and there is one thing
that God never wants
to have happen
in your life
and mine
that is that we be lost
regardless of how
we treat him.
Why?
Why God demonstrated
that love
because God's love
decreed that any man
that believes in Christ
shall be saved.
Any man
do you understand that?
Whosoever believeth
in him
that when a man
trusts Jesus Christ
God says
that man
who stands
in sorrow
of his sin
who knows
that he stands
condemned
but who puts
his trust
and his confidence
in the righteousness
of Jesus Christ
God says
that's the man
that I will save
and that's the man
that I will love
to save
and he didn't
distinguish
separate mankind
and it made no difference
regarding man's color
the color of his skin
or his previous condition
of servitude
God has decreed
in love
that any man
that trusts Jesus
and any man
can do that
shall be saved
and that the joy
of heaven
is this joy
the joy
of a sinner
repenting
Jesus put it this way
there shall be more
joy in heaven
over one sinner
that repenteth
more than over
ninety and nine
just persons
that need
no repentance
christian fathers
god is love
god says
as I live
saith the lord
I have no pleasure
in the death
of the wicked
but that the wicked
man turn from
his way
and live
if god ever
loves you and me
to the point
that he yearns
for our salvation
would a million times
rather save us
than to see us lost
then god says
you be loved
when you and I
have learned
to love
as christian fathers
then we're also
going to know
how to treat
those who come
in contact
with us
and with our homes
the united states
is on fire
today
isn't it
oh you can
laugh it off
and you can
chide it off
but listen
this thing
of segregation
isn't going
to stop
you know
that's facing
whenever a man
wants liberty
and whenever
a man
regardless of
the color
of his skin
is ready
to die
that he can
have liberty
he is going
to die
or else
don't you ever
kid yourself
this land
of ours
is on fire
it's about
time
we as
christians
begin to show
our colors
god hath
made
all of us
of one blood
it's about
time that you
and i are
saying that
all men
are created
in the image
of god
that a man
doesn't have
to die
to have
freedom
in this
country
this country
guarantees
it to him
whether you
and i are
white or
whether you
and i are
black
if god
loved you
and god
loved me
that god
would a million
times rather
save you
and me
even to
see his
loss
we're
going to
have to
love our
brother
we are
going to
have to
love him
because if
we say we
love god
and we
hate our
brother
john says
we're a
liar
then and
only then
when we
love our
brother
because god
loved us
in spite of
the way
we've
treated him
then and
only then
is this
going to
be a
land
where all
men can
say
with liberty
and justice
for all
that's
what this
land was
founded on
and that's
the greatness
and the
genius of
this land
that in
the love
of god
we can
have the
assurance
that god
dwells in
us
and that
we need
not be
afraid of
the judgment
because that
kind of love
will cast out
any fear
any trepidation
about death
because if
we can just
love our
fellow man
in christ
even as
god loves
us
and hope
and treat
a man
that we
might enhance
his heavenward
potentialities
rather than
to thwart
them
well then we
can have the
assurance that
god dwells in
us by faith
john was the
beloved disciple
he had to
learn oh he
was just a
young man in
his early
twenties when
he met
jesus down
at the
jordan came
down from
galilee you
know
remember one
time when
they were up
in samaria
and john
was there with
his brother
and the
samaritan
people wouldn't
let jesus stay
overnight
remember he
had a hot
temper and
he said lord
let me call
down fire from
heaven let's
burn up this
village and
jesus rather
smilingly looked
at him and
said now son
of thunder
bone air
jesus you
better hold
your temper
he had a
temper but he
had to learn
what it meant
to be loved
like god is
love but in
the upper room
he had his
head on jesus
buzzing remember
at the cross
he was the
only one he
stood there with
mary and
again they
boiled him in
oil trying to
kill him he
was the only
disciple that
died a natural
death but in
his old age he
was the one that
had penetrated
closest to the
heart of christ
that that's why
jesus loved him
the beloved
disciple he knew
what it meant
to love
fathers listen
the world's on
fire the world
needs to see
demonstrated in
your life and
mine the kind
of love that
god has
demonstrated for
you and me
we have fathers
and some of you
have your fathers
with your minds
the father of
memory and
today when i when
i think of my
father i think of
the day of my
ordination when i
was a child i
moved from chicago
to east st louis
when i graduated
from the seminary
my father wanted
me ordained back
in the home church
in chicago where
he grew up as a
boy and where his
father and my
mother's father were
charter members of
zion lutheran church
so up to chicago we
went my father was
not a very
demonstrative type
of person i
wondered what he
would do on the
day of my
ordination because
it had been seven
years planning to
go to college and
seminary and i
recall when i
started he said
well if there's a
will there's a way
we'll manage some
way and i realized
what it meant as
all of you do to
put someone through
school but on the
day of ordination i
wondered what he
would do when at
the end of the
service i stood
there and i knew
people would come
around and i about
had it figured out
what he would do
he didn't want to
show emotion my
dad walked up to
me and he shook
hands with me and
he just looked at
me and he wouldn't
trust to say a
word because he
knew that he
couldn't talk and
he just looked and
shook hands and
bowed his head and
walked away in a
hurry but today i
think of that
handshake there was
everything in it
that a christian
father could wish
for his son there
was pride and there
was joy and there
was a prayer but he
couldn't show emotion
and he walked away
hurriedly that was
my father for whom i
have great respect
and great admiration
oh when we walk the
glory road and i like
to think that when we
go out of god's house
on sunday that oh
if we could just sort
of walk on there and
feel we've been with
god and walk the
glory road with a
little joy you know
christian fathers
knowing the love of
god and having
experience we could
just walk the glory
road and and sing
with the joy in our
hearts knowing the
love of god but we
could go ahead and
sing today someday the
silver cord will break
and i as now no more
shall sing but oh the
joy when i shall wake
within the palace of my
king and i shall see
him face to face and
tell the story saved by
grace and i shall see
him face to face and
tell the story saved by
grace christian fathers
god is love let's go out
on the glory road and
let's love amen
the peace of god which
passeth all human
understanding keep and
unite your hearts and
minds in christ jesus unto
life everlasting
kingdom
king