Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God, our regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday,
as we find it written in Peter's first letter, the fifth chapter, especially the sixth verse.
Humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, the Lord of the nations, dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio,
today is the third Sunday after Trinity.
Today is also the Sunday before July the 4th, which is the birthday of our beloved nation.
Next Thursday, our land and nation will celebrate its 187th birthday.
And as we gather here in God's house this morning, we may say to ourselves,
does the word of God have a message for America in such a time as this,
living in this hour in which you and I are living?
When you and I look out at our nation this morning, and we see its needs, and we see its dangers,
and we realize that we are living in the atomic, the nuclear age, and we are living in the age of outer space,
and we say to ourselves, does God have something to say to our nation as we observe its 187th birthday?
And as we turn to the word of God, we find the apostle Peter, the great fisherman from up Galilee way,
wrote to the Christians of his day, living under the Roman eagle, living under the Caesars,
and he had a message for them, and that message is very appropriate and very vital for you and me as Americans
on this day when we celebrate the birthday of our great nation.
And this is what the apostle Peter told the Christians who were living under the Roman eagle.
He said, humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God.
We know that our God is a spirit, therefore God doesn't have a hand,
and therefore the hand is the symbol of power.
The mighty hand, therefore, the symbol of almighty, unlimited, omnipotent power.
And so Peter wrote to the Christians of his day, living under the Roman Empire,
humble yourselves under the mighty, the unlimited power of God.
To humble ourselves means to get on our knees.
To humble ourselves means to bow.
It means to stoop.
And when they say to ourselves, bow in humility, in what way?
And the apostle Peter tells us, for he says, cast all your care upon him.
In other words, this is the call to America today from the word of God as the apostle Peter speaks,
and that is, humble yourselves in a true confidence, in a true spirit of reliance on the mighty hand of God,
and trust him all the way through thick and thin.
That's what it means to humble ourselves under the mighty hand of God.
And we sophisticated Americans may say to ourselves this morning,
we are to get on our knees, America, and we are to trust in our God,
and to trust him all the way with an implicit faith, a faith that knows no ends,
and to trust that mighty, omnipotent, all-powerful hand of his.
Isn't there a danger if you and I put our trust in the mighty hand of God,
that we may find ourselves as the bottom man on the totem pole,
or that we may find ourselves out on a limb and somebody may saw the limb off in front of us,
or that you and I may say, we'll have everything to lose and we'll have nothing to gain?
It is well, Americans, as we speak from the word of God this morning
and celebrate the 187th birthday of our nation,
it is well to turn to the word of God and to see,
is God's hand mighty enough to meet our needs?
Is it mighty enough to meet our dangers?
Is it mighty enough to supply the things that we in America need today?
Let's look for a moment at the mighty hand of God.
Christian friends, it is just that.
It is that hand that is so mighty, that is so omnipotent,
and that is so all-powerful, that there isn't any need in America today,
but what the mighty hand of God can meet it,
and therefore, Peter says, on your knees, America,
trust to the very limit of your confidence,
the mighty hand of God, because in the first place, look at this mighty hand.
The mighty hand of God is still the hand that determines the destiny of nations.
What is it that makes a nation survive, we may say today,
because we have the need of survival in the world, isn't that right?
We may say to ourselves, why, it's the balance of power.
It is having an army, it is having a navy, it is having nuclear weapons, is it?
Is that the answer that caused the survival of nations,
or does God Almighty have something to do
with the survival land, the keeping of nations intact,
lest they go down and defeat?
It wasn't long ago that I was over in the land of Palestine,
and I came to the place where they said,
here is where ancient Jericho stood.
And Christian friends, when you stand in ancient Jericho,
there's nothing to see on the surface of the land.
They say, this is where we believe the city was.
And do you recall the story when Moses came to Mount Nebo,
and God allowed him to overlook the land of Canaan
that flowed with milk and honey.
And then Moses died, and God buried him,
and Joshua came into command.
And when Joshua, with the children of Israel,
crossed the river Jordan and came into the land of Canaan,
the first city that they were to take was the city of Jericho.
And you remember how they took it?
God said that there shall be the priests who shall take the trumpets,
and they shall march around the city of Jericho
once each day for six days.
And then God said, on the seventh day,
they shall march around the city seven times.
And when they have done that on the seventh time,
they shall blow their trumpets.
And when the people hear the blow of the trumpet,
they shall shout at the top of their voices.
And God says, the walls of Jericho will come down.
Did they come down?
I stood at the place where they said Jericho was,
and archaeologists have begun to dig there.
And they have dug down 70 feet in the earth's surface.
And down 70 feet they have uncovered a city
that they say, these are the ruins of ancient Jericho.
Does a nation survive by its own power,
or does a nation survive because it puts its trust
in the mighty hand of God?
Then you remember there was King Hezekiah,
who was king of the southern kingdom.
And when again Sennacherib had come,
the man that surrounded the city was going to take it.
That night Hezekiah, knowing that he was
woefully outdistanced in power,
he prayed to God and asked God for help.
And there came a plague in the night,
if you recall that incident.
And the next morning there were 185,000 dead Assyrians
lying around the city of Jerusalem.
The mighty hand of God determines the destinies of nations.
Oh, not that we are not to use our judgment,
and not that we are not to be armed to defend ourselves.
But again, America, humble yourselves under the mighty hand of God.
Nations stand by the power of God,
not because of the balance of power of men.
And when again the northern kingdom had sinned against God
in the year 722,
and Shalmaneser came,
he carried ten tribes of Israel off into captivity,
and they had been wiped off the face of the earth,
the famous lost ten tribes.
Why? Because they forgot God.
And then came the year 586 before Christ,
when Nebuchadnezzar the Chaldean came and sacked the city of Jerusalem
and carried the Jews away into captivity down in Babylon.
But you recall there was a prophet Isaiah
that lived 700 years before Jesus,
who had prophesied over 100 years before the man came into existence,
that there would be a man by the name of Cyrus,
and that that man would release the Jews,
and they would be allowed to come back from their home in Babylon
and to go back and rebuild the walls of Jerusalem
and come back into Palestine.
And that night at Belshazzar's feast down in Babylon,
oh, the Babylonian army was intense and it was terrific,
but because there was drunkenness and debauchery,
that night the Medes and the Persians broke in,
and they overcame the Chaldeans,
and Cyrus came on the throne,
and the Jews came back.
Why the almighty power of God
and come up to this last war, World War II.
Why was it that Hitler and his Nazi power,
why was it that they stopped
when they had England on its knees?
Even Winston Churchill couldn't understand.
What was it that made him stop
when there was no resistance?
But he stopped.
And the very fate of World War II was changed.
Why?
Because God Almighty,
the mighty hand of God,
still determines the destinies of nations.
And therefore, when the call to you and me
as we celebrate the 187th birthday of our glorious land,
it ought to be America on its knees
that we trust in God
and we go all the way into our trust,
because having God
and trusting the mighty hand of God,
nothing will ever happen to this nation.
Except the Lord God allows it to come.
That's the assurance that we can have as Christians
when we humble ourselves under the mighty hand of God.
And as we observe the birthday, therefore,
of our glorious nation today,
we ought to look inside and probe within ourselves
to see whether we really trust God.
Does this nation really trust God?
Are we a trusting people in Almighty God
and in His mighty hand?
You know, some of us may look with the stance
of that question this morning.
We may say we are disappointed
because of the recent decisions
of the United States Supreme Court
with regard to the schools
legislating the reading of the Bible
or the praying of the Lord's Prayer in school.
You know, I am proud of my nation
that the Supreme Court gave that ruling.
We must understand that the Supreme Court
did not say that we were not a believing,
a religious people,
but because this is a nation
where you and I have the freedom of conscience
to worship our God,
and that means that you can worship
the way he would worship.
That means that the atheist who refuses
to believe that there is a God
can worship as he would want to.
That means that the Roman Catholic,
the Lutheran, the Protestant,
can worship his way,
and all in our government,
all that the Supreme Court said.
That schools shall not legislate a religion.
That shall be left to the individual.
That shall be left to the church.
I was in Israel, in Haifa,
and in the Zion Hotel,
in a Jewish hotel.
And again, it was the first meal
that we had had that was a good one
for many a week.
And yet we sat there,
and it was a lovely meal.
It was beef, to be sure.
And I had coffee,
and I asked for cream,
and I knew when I asked for it
that I probably would not get it
because I was with an Orthodox group.
And again, the waiter said to me,
I am sorry,
but you will have cream
tomorrow morning for breakfast.
I knew the ancient ceremony
of Jewish law
that forbade a Jew to eat meat
and to drink cream
within an eight-hour period.
Yet I was a Gentile.
Yet again, even though I was a Gentile,
there was no cream on the table,
and no Gentile would have it
because no Jew would mix meat and milk
within an eight-hour period.
In our great land
where we have religious freedom,
again, if the Roman Catholic
would come into ascendancy
and would legislate religion,
it could well be that on Friday
no meat would be sold
in any grocery store.
We would have to eat fish.
And again, with regard to the Jew,
that cream and milk and meat
would not go together,
or even as regards
the Lutheran Church,
if we were in the ascendancy,
there would be a danger
that we might want
the very taxable money
of the nation
to go for the furtherance
of the Lutheran Church,
and we would not want that.
There is corruption
wherever there is power.
I thank God for a nation
that still stands
for freedom of religion
and says,
you are the ones to decide
what your religion shall be,
your church shall decide,
the government shall not interfere,
as you carry out your prerogative
to worship God
as your conscience would dictate.
It's a great nation
and I love it.
And therefore, again,
as Peter would speak
to the people of his day,
and you and I,
as we celebrate the birthday
of our great land,
we say,
does God have a message?
Yes.
Humble yourselves
under the mighty hand of God.
Humble yourselves,
America, on your knees.
bow the knee
with a real confident faith
and trust and reliance
and go all the way
in your trust
in the mighty,
omnipotent hand of God.
And we can say,
but is God's hand powerful enough
that God's hand can do something
as regards this nation?
Well, look in the second place.
Not only does God's hand
guide and determine
the destinies of nations,
but God's mighty hand
also determines
and holds in check Satan,
who is again
the roaring lion.
You recall when
Dick read the epistle lesson,
he said,
Peter had these words,
be sober, be vigilant,
because your adversary,
the devil,
as a roaring lion,
walketh about,
seeking whom he may devour.
This individual Satan,
this fallen angel of God,
he is depicted in two lights
in the word of God.
One is this,
his stealth,
that he comes in temptation
to you and me,
and by enticing us
to do that which is wrong,
to get us to fall away
from a living faith
in Jesus Christ
as our Lord and Savior.
But he's got another side,
and the other side
is the side of the roaring lion,
the ravenously hungry lion
that we are told
raves and roars
when it's hungry,
about to devour its prey.
Satan has that side of him,
and that's the side
of persecution.
When Satan cannot win
you and me
by enticement,
the next best bet he has
is to win you and me
by bringing persecution.
And when Peter was writing here,
he wasn't writing something
that was a theory.
Something had already
taken place.
Nero was emperor in Rome,
and you recall that he had
set fire to the city of Rome,
and when this thing boomeranged,
he was blamed for it.
And in order to take
and shift the blame
to someone else,
why here was again
the dupe,
those Christians,
those new people,
who were worshipping
a Jesus who was crucified,
a Jesus that they said
arose again from the dead,
and he blamed it on them.
And then the Neronian persecutions
broke out,
and Christians were devoured
by lions in the Colosseum
in which I stood
and thought back
of the time
when those things took place.
The roaring lion began.
And we say to ourselves,
well, does God control
the roaring lion?
After all,
it's true that in the last
30 years,
think of it,
in the last 30 years
there have been more Christians
put to death
because of their faith
than there have been
from the day of Jesus
until 30 years ago.
There are millions
behind the Iron Curtain
who are still in salt mines
and who are in subjection
and in subjugation
because of this crime
that they dare to confess
that Jesus Christ
is their Lord
and their Savior from sin.
And what may a person say?
Well, if God Almighty
has a mighty hand,
what is his power?
We must go back
to Calvary.
Jesus Christ conquered
Satan on the cross,
and when he arose again
from the dead,
Jesus said,
I saw que Satan
topple from his throne.
God Almighty
in this day of choice
still controls Satan
even though
he is still
the roaring lion.
God still controls him.
The church of Jesus Christ
is here,
and we say,
why does God
allow persecution?
Well, you see,
it accomplishes some good.
If persecution
would come to your land
and mine today,
how many of us
would stand up
for a true loyalty
in Jesus Christ
and face death?
You see,
there's one thing
that persecution does.
It cleanses the church.
You know,
the church gets
so top-heavy at times.
We join it
like we would
a lodge
or an organization
and we pay dues
and we expect
to be waited on.
We forget
the balm of Gilead,
Jesus Christ,
in the church.
We forget
that when we come in,
this is a hospital
for sin-sick souls.
We forget
that we come in
with the guilt
of damnation
on ourselves,
and we forget
that we come
to hear the glorious
good news
that the blood
of Jesus Christ
can cleanse a man
whiter than snow,
that he can stand
before the bar
of divine justice
and be a forgiven sinner.
We forget it.
And again,
the church becomes
a social status.
We belong to the church
where the best people go.
And when persecution comes,
we run,
unless there is
a living confrontation
of Jesus Christ.
It cleanses the church.
And another thing it does,
it increases the faith
of those who believe,
that we finally learn
to realize
that there's only one thing
important in this world,
and it isn't money,
it isn't stature,
it isn't status,
it is Jesus Christ.
And the other thing
is this,
you know it,
and so do I,
there are some people
in this world
who will never be one
for Christ,
except they see
somebody die for him.
There's one thing
that is unanswerable.
When a man says
somebody else was willing
to die and to be killed
for his faith,
then a living faith
in Jesus Christ
must be a vital necessity,
and it must be
an essential land,
the blood of martyrs.
It becomes the seed
of the church,
because through that seed
the church grows.
And so God Almighty
still controls it,
and we know this,
that when we,
in America,
we're on our knees,
and we come into
a real reliance,
and go all the way
in the mighty hand of God,
that if it would come,
God Almighty promises
you and me strength
to sustain us,
that we can stand
and quit ourselves
as Christians ought to be.
Today,
as we realize
that we're celebrating
the 187th birthday
of our glorious nation,
if persecution should come,
let us accept it gladly,
and know that it was
not something
that was inevitable,
it was something
that God allowed
to come,
relying upon God's strength.
Yesterday,
June the 29th,
and the ancient church
was always celebrated
as St. Peter
and St. Paul's Day,
commemorating their martyrdom.
Peter knew
what he was writing about
in the Neronian persecution.
He was brought to Rome,
and he was crucified
upside down.
He was crucified
because he was a Jew,
and he lost his life
because he dared
to be a soldier
of Jesus Christ.
And there was Paul,
the little Jew
from up Tarsus Way
in Cilicia,
when he was brought to Rome
because he was
a Roman citizen.
He was given the choice
and therefore
they beheaded him.
That's the way Romans died.
His head fell
from his shoulders.
But Paul was a man
that could say,
I have fought a good fight,
I have finished the course,
I have kept the faith.
Henceforth,
there is laid up for me
a crown of righteousness,
which the Lord,
the righteous judge,
who give me at that day,
and not to me only,
but to all them also
that love is appearing.
Those men died
because they humbled themselves
under the mighty hand of God,
and they knew
that God's hand
was mighty enough
to protect them,
except when God used them
to the glory of his name.
Today,
as we celebrate again
the birthday
of our great nation,
humble yourselves,
says Peter,
down on your knees,
America,
trust God,
trust him all the way.
You and I say,
will we be disappointed?
Bear in mind,
the mighty hand of God
is also this mighty hand
that will exalt
and that will abase
in due time.
Will there be a judgment?
Peter said,
humble yourselves,
therefore,
under the mighty hand of God
that he may exalt you
in due time.
Will there be a judgment day
when God's Christ will come?
You know,
sometimes men laugh at it.
Will there be a day
of exaltation
for God's own?
Have you ever noticed
as you read the Old Testament
the number of times
it is mentioned
about the children of Israel
being delivered
from the land of Egypt?
How again,
when Moses led them
an army of between
one and three million Jews
and they crossed the Red Sea
and they came into
the wilderness
and God kept them alive
by manna that fell
from heaven for 40 years
and we are told
that their feet
didn't swell
and their clothing
didn't wear out
in that 40-year period.
And they came
into the land of Canaan
and that great deliverance
again stands
as a monumental deliverance
that is going to take place
at the last day.
Will there be a debasement
of those
that have rejected Jesus Christ?
There was the flood
that inundated the world.
It stands
as a testimony of judgment.
There was the destruction
of Sodom and Gomorrah.
It stands
as a testimony of judgment.
There was again
the destruction
of Jerusalem
in the year 70
when Titus and Vespasian
sacked the city.
It stands
as destruction.
God will exalt
and God will abase.
Even Christ said
this generation
of this race
shall not pass away
till all be fulfilled.
The fact that the Jew
will live
to the end of time
is an absolute
ocular demonstration
of this promise
of God
that God
will come again
in exaltation
and God
will come
to dethrone
those who have
rejected Him.
And therefore
we face a problem
today
and in our nation
it's the problem
of the colored people
isn't it?
And we say to ourselves
what is the will
of God?
Some men
are not interested
in what the will
of God is
because they
do not believe
in the mighty
hand of God
to destroy.
But God's arm
will exalt
and it will abase.
What is the will
of God?
God has made
all men
in His image
hasn't He?
Adam and Eve
were our first parents
and all human beings
therefore
are made
in the image
of God
regardless
as to the fact
as to whether
a man's color
is white
or whether
his color
is colored.
There is only
one kind
of human blood
and it flows
through the veins
of all men
doesn't it?
What is the will
of God
as we stand
in our nation
that is on fire?
Let's realize this
that we ought
to say
if God Almighty
will come
to exalt
and condemn
we ought to pray
on our knees
today
God give us
the courage
to do what is right
regardless
of what the consequences
will be.
There was Abraham Lincoln
who stood
on the battlefield
of Gettysburg
and he spoke
these monumental
words one day
fourscore
and seven years ago
our fathers
brought forth
on this continent
a new nation
conceived in liberty
and dedicated
to the proposition
that all men
are created equal.
A score
you know
is twenty years
fourscore
would be eighty
wouldn't it?
Eighty plus seven
means 87 years.
So when
Abraham Lincoln
stood at
Gettysburg, Pennsylvania
where fifty one
thousand Americans
either died
or were wounded
in battle
it was at the time
when our nation
was just
eighty seven
years old.
This coming
Thursday
our nation
under God
will be
one hundred
and eighty
seven
years old.
One hundred
years.
the colored
people have
waited
for their
rights
which are
theirs
by constitution
and by law
in this
great land
of ours.
How much
more patience
do you
and I
want
from them?
We teach
our children
do we not
that they are
to stand
in the classroom
and to place
their hand
on their
heart
and to face
O glory
and to pledge
allegiance
and we thrill
when we hear
them stand
and say
I pledge
allegiance
to the flag
of the United
States of
America
and to the
republic
for which
it stands
one nation
under God
indivisible
with liberty
and justice
for all.
But listen
Americans
how many
children
stand in
the classroom
and under
their breath
have got
to say
with liberty
and justice
for all
but me.
we teach
our children
to stand
in church
and there's
the church
flag over
there
and to put
their hands
over their
hearts
and to say
I pledge
allegiance
to the
Christian
flag
and to
the church
for which
it stands
one
savior
universal
with life
and salvation
for all.
Do you
believe
life
and salvation
in Jesus
Christ
have been
prepared
for all?
Does that
mean the
colored man
as well
as the
white man
or are we
living a lie?
Do you
and I
believe it?
If we
believe it
when will
be as
Americans
and as
Christians
say
this thing
has gone
on long
enough?
The ground
before the
cross of
Calvary
is level
and it's
equal.
God
hath made
us all
of one
blood.
that men
may have
the liberty
that this
great nation
intends for
all.
Francis Scott
Key, you
know, asked
the question,
oh say can
you see by
the dawn's
early light
what so proudly
we hailed at
the twilight's
last gleaming?
He asked the
question, can
you still see
in the dawn
something that
we saw in
the twilight
last night?
And you
and I
may say
what did
Francis Scott
Key see?
And then he
goes on
whose broad
stripes and
bright stars
through the
perilous night
or the
ramparts we
watched
were so
gallantly
streaming?
He was
looking at
Fort McHenry
he calls it
the stripes
and the stars.
It was
gallantly
waving
and they
could see
it through
the night
and we
wonder how
could he
see it
through the
night?
But he
goes on
and says
in the
rocket's
red glare
the bombs
bursting
into air
gave proof
through the
night
that our
flag
was still
there.
That's what
it was.
Oh glory.
When the
bombs burst
into air
Francis Scott
Key
could still
see
Oh glory
waving in
the breeze.
Then he
asks America
this question
today as we
commemorate the
birthday of our
nation.
Oh say
does that
star-spangled
banner yet
wave
for the land
of the free
and the home
of the brave?
Does it
still wave?
Is it
going to
continue to
wave?
Oh only if
America gets
on its knees
only if
America
humbles
itself
before the
mighty
end of
God
and dares
to do
what God
wants it
to do
only then
can the
words that
Abraham Lincoln
spoke come
true
as he prayed
that all
this nation
of the
people
and by
the people
and for
should not
perish
from the
earth.
I love
this nation
and I
know you
love it
too.
We love
it that
we would
die for
it.
Today as
we commemorate
its glorious
187th
birthday
I call
on you
quit
yourselves
as men.
Quit
yourselves
as
Christians.
Quit
yourselves
as loyal
Americans.
Amen.
the peace
of God
which passeth
all human
understanding
keep and
unite your
hearts and
minds in
Christ Jesus
unto life
everlasting.
Amen.