Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God, our regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday,
as we find it written in Paul's letter to the Romans, beginning there in the sixth chapter,
especially the third verse.
Know ye not that so many of us as were baptized into Jesus Christ
were baptized into his death.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, the Lord of our Christian life,
dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Today, as you know, is the sixth Sunday after the Festival of Trinity.
It is our custom on these After Trinity Sundays
to deal with some of the common and practical problems of our Christian life and conduct.
You recall that last Sunday we talked about getting along with one another,
how to live in peace and harmony with one another.
And today we have a very practical thing that we want to talk about,
and that is the matter of carelessness in our Christian life.
I like to call it sloppy Christian living.
Sloppy Christian living.
This kind of living where we're off the beam.
We're either always to the left or we're always to the right,
but in our Christian life, it is a sloppy thing.
It's a careless thing.
It is an inferior thing.
It is a Christian life that is not becoming us as Christians.
And you know, friends, it's a very easy thing
to slip into a sloppy Christian life, isn't it?
It's very easy to look at our life
and to not care whether we are doing the will of God
or whether we are not doing it.
Not to care whether as we look at our life
that it's a soggy thing
and that it's something that we are rather ashamed of.
And it may all come very easily from this thing
that we say something like this to ourselves.
Now we are saved by the forgiving grace of God, are we not?
And that's true, isn't it?
We are saved by the grace of God
and that means that you and I are not saved by our life.
Isn't that right?
And because we are saved by the forgiving grace of God
and that our lives do not save us,
it's the easiest thing in the world,
especially for us Lutherans,
to get the idea that life, therefore, is not very important.
Because if life doesn't save,
what's the difference how I live?
What's the difference, therefore,
whether my Christian life is sloppy,
whether it doesn't measure up,
whether it's absolutely inferior,
whether it's the kind of a life
that is not becoming me as a Christian,
what's the difference?
After all, isn't it foolishness
to live on the beam
when we are not saved by our life?
Some of us may even draw this conclusion.
We may say,
why, the thing that we ought to do
is to go out and to sing to our heart's content
because the more we sin,
the more we show the world
how great is the forgiving grace of God.
If we go out and kill
and live in adultery and murder,
why, the world would say,
my, how tremendously best
is the grace of God that forgives
and actually we would be glorifying grace.
That's the way some Christians sometimes feel
about their Christian life.
And that's why today
we want to talk about this thing
of carelessness,
of indifference,
of sloppy Christian living.
Doesn't it make any difference
even though we are saved
by the saving grace of God
and our lives do not save us?
The speaker this morning
from the Word of God
is the Apostle Paul,
the little Jew
from up in Tarsus in Cilicia,
the great war horse
of the Christian church.
And we find him writing
to his Christian congregation at Rome.
And yet then,
when he had spoken to them
about the very fact
that we are saved
by the forgiving grace of God,
and there was a danger
that because they would know
that they were saved
by the mercy of God
in Christ Jesus
and not by their lives,
that somehow or other
they would get the idea
that the Christian life
is not important
and that they would go out
and say,
now I can sin to my heart's content.
It doesn't make any difference.
And therefore,
I do not have to avoid
being off of the beam.
And so he wrote to them
as he speaks to you
and me this morning,
assuring us
that we are saved
by the forgiving grace of God
to be sure.
Assuring us
that you and I
are not saved by our lives
and but therefore
telling and calling
to us as Christians
to avoid being off of the beam,
to avoid carelessness
in a sloppy Christian life,
to avoid anything
that doesn't measure up
because this is what
he told the Christians at Rome,
he says,
do you not know
that as many of us
as were baptized
into Jesus Christ
were baptized
into his death?
Do you not realize
that because you were baptized
into Christ's death
that therefore
you must avoid
being off of the beam
in your Christian life?
You've got to get rid
of a sloppy Christian living.
of that which is inferior.
You dare not be off of the beam.
You've got to be on the beam
even though you are not
saved by your life
because when you were baptized,
do you not know
that you were baptized
into his death?
It's well this morning
as we are here in God's house
to take a look at our baptism
and to realize
just what it has meant to us
and what it means
to be baptized
into Christ's death.
If there is anything
in the world
that ought to cause you
and me to avoid
being off of the beam,
to avoid sloppy Christian living,
the kind of living
that just doesn't measure up,
it is not becoming
you and me,
it ought to be this.
We were baptized
into Jesus Christ
and thus into his death
and that in the first place
means this,
that when you and I
were baptized
and baptized into his death,
that means that we were
joined to Christ's death,
that death
which made it possible
for the forgiving
grace of God
to operate.
How many of us
realize this,
that if Christ
had not died,
the grace of God
could never
have forgiven sin?
Some people say,
well God is a forgiving God,
he's gracious
and he's merciful,
therefore God
can forgive sins easily,
but listen,
God himself
could not forgive sins
had it not been
for the death
of his son Jesus Christ.
The second person
of the Trinity,
God the Son,
had to come out
of the ivory palaces
into this world of sin,
become a human being
without sin
and he had to go
to Calvary's cross
and there he had to die.
Why?
Because God
is a God of grace
but he's also
a God of justice
and being a God
of justice
when the soul sins
and it's punishable
by death,
God must carry out
that verdict of justice
and therefore
for God
to be merciful,
to forgive
on the basis of grace,
Christ had to die
and he had to meet
the justice of God
and you and I
don't understand Calvary
until we stand there
and say there was
God's Son
who willingly
met the justice
of God.
He on the cross
he bore the guilt
and the punishment
of the world.
He endured the equal
of an eternity
in hell
for the human race
and he met
the justice of God
so that by meeting
God's justice
therefore it was possible
for God
who is merciful
and gracious
to have a forgiving grace
and to forgive sins
and therefore
when you and I
were baptized
we received
we were given
this forgiving grace
of God.
How many of us
realize that the greatest
thing that has ever
happened to you and me
has been our baptism?
When in infancy
you and I
were brought
by means of water
and the word of God
in baptism
something tremendous
happened
and what happened
in baptism
we were united
and joined
to the death of Christ
and the merciful
forgiveness of God
became ours
and we were forgiven
our sins
delivered from hell
and damnation
and given eternal life
and bear in mind
when on the day
of your baptism
in mind
that tremendous miracle
of God's grace
happened
that grace
was given
you and me
to save us
never to be exploited
what happens
when a Christian
who has been baptized
into Christ's death
doesn't care
how he lives
what happens
when he's off
of the beam
what happens
when his Christian
life is sloppy
it's everything
but what it ought
to be
when your life
and mine
is sloppy
even though we are
not saved by our life
that means that
we are looking
at God's grace
and we are making
it mean
that God
is stupid
listen
can you think
of a greater crime
than to look
at God's merciful grace
and to try
to interpret it
in such a way
that God
ends up being stupid
that's what we do
you may say
what do you mean
God's grace
was given
for one reason
to save
yet it's possible
for many a Christian
look at God's grace
and to say
God I've got an angle
God you're rather stupid
I know how to get
around you
your grace
is so great
to forgive me
therefore
since it's so vast
and I'm not saved
by my life
I can go out
and live
just as I please
and I'll go out
and sin
to the very
limits of my ability
and your grace
is always bigger
in other words
we say to God
God you're not so smart
as you think you are
I'm a little more clever
than you are
I've got a way
around this thing
that I can live
as I please
I can be off
of the beam
and still be saved
because your grace
is big enough
to allow me
to do as I please
and listen
whenever you and I
accuse God
of being stupid
whenever you and I
say God
I can take advantage
of you
and I can exploit you
whenever you and I
play God
for a fool
watch out
listen friends
the forgiving grace
of God
was given
for one reason
that was to save
never that you and I
could say
God I'm clever
I can get around it
and I'll live
as I please
off of the beam
and your grace
is so big
that it will forgive me
you know it's like this
supposing a man
were dying
of a horrible
venereal disease
and realizing
that he was dying
of it because
of a profligate life
he found that
there was a medication
that would arrest it
and then he would
take that cure
that would arrest
this venereal disease
only to say
the reason for
the medical cure
is that I can go back
and live as I did
and when any Christian
accepts the grace
of God
only to interpret it
as God
you're a sap
and you're a fool
and you're stupid
that's my indication
that I can go back
and live again
that man's lost
the cure for
venereal disease
was never given
to allow man
to wallow in sin
that's what the word
of God means
when like dogs
we go back
and eat our vomit
whenever you and I
know we're not
saved by our life
but whenever
on the day of baptism
we were given
the forgiven grace
of God
it's time
that we as Christians
will realize
that it was given
for one reason
to say
never to allow
you and me
to exploit God
and say
God you're stupid
I'm more clever
than you
I can go out
and live as I please
because your grace
is greater than my sin
God forbid
perish the thought
and that's why today
when again
we realize
that we're saved
by the forgiving grace
of God
and we're not saved
by our life
but when St. Paul
calls upon you
and me
to say
avoid sloppy
Christian living
when you and I
live and our life
doesn't measure up
to what it ought to be
and we know it
and we don't care
when we're off
of the beam
and we say
what's the difference
I can live
as I please
I can sin
to my heart's content
today ought to be
the day
when we say
to ourselves
I was baptized
and when I was baptized
and I became
sharers of Christ's death
and I received
the grace of God
and therefore
we ought to say
to ourselves
I am going
to be on the beam
I shall avoid
anything in my
Christian life
that puts me
to the right
or to the left
of center
God wants
no sloppy
Christian living
when we can say that
and mean it
then and only then
will we begin
to appreciate
what it means
that we have been baptized
you know Paul
appreciated his baptism
immensely
did he not
he was on the way
to Damascus
you know up in Syria
when he met his Lord
and he was stricken
with blindness
and he went into
Damascus
and he stayed there
for three days
and he was blinded
at that time
and he was either
able to eat or to drink
and then the Lord God
went to a man
and said to him
his name was Ananias
he is not the other Ananias
you know it's too bad
they both have the same names
he's not the Ananias
and Sapphira
who were liars
but there was another Ananias
a Christian living up there
in Damascus
and God told Ananias
to go to a street
called Straight
to a home of a man
in the name of Judas
and there again
it was not Judas Iscariot
Judas Iscariot was dead
and he went to the home
of a man in the name of Judas
and he went there
and he said
you shall find this man
Saul of Tarsus
and Ananias went
you know
and again when he put
his hands on him
and prayed
Paul was able
to see again
and then we are told
that Paul was baptized
the grace of God
was granted
and sealed to him
the very death
of Jesus Christ
and because he was baptized
it meant a tremendous thing
how thankful
we ought to be
that in baptism
again
we became
children of God
and the mercy
and the grace of God
became ours
how thankful
that we have had parents
who in infancy
again
have brought us
as infants
to the kingdom of God
because even children
are born in sin
and they need
to be regenerated
the mercy of God
the very fact
that we have been baptized
it ought to be
the greatest occasion
of your life and mine
that is when God
did something
we were baptized
in connection
with Christ's death
the death
that brought life
and salvation
and enabled
even our God
to be a God
of mercy
oh we are saved
by grace
and you know
especially we Lutherans
we say if I'm saved
by grace
therefore it doesn't
make any difference
how I live
life isn't very important
it's foolish
to watch your life
and yet again
we're talking about
this thing of
careless Christian living
sloppiness
yes just being
run over at the heels
type of
who cares how we live
the idea that we can
go out and do
just about as we please
God forbid
says Paul
don't you realize
that when you were
baptized into Christ Jesus
you were baptized
into his death
and we say
well what does that mean
well it not only means
that we were baptized
into his death
that made it possible
for God to be gracious
but we were baptized
we were joined
to Christ's death
which occurred
once and for all
thank God
Christ died
once and for all
he didn't have to die
a number of times
when he who was the
God man went to Calvary
his great sacrifice
was sufficient
for all of our sins
and also for the sins
of the world
the word of God
assures us that
it was a timeless
sacrifice
it was a sacrifice
as the lamb
slain from the
foundations of the world
when he died
to sin
that was it
he paid the price
and he was done
and finished with sin
now Paul makes
a comparison
Paul said
now you are baptized
when you were baptized
in connection
with his death
you are sharers
of that death
that like as Christ
was finished with sin
so are you
finished with sin
you also have
died unto sin
when we have
we have died
in baptism
because Christ
came to live
in our hearts
and when he came
to live in our hearts
the day that you
and I were baptized
he came to give us
power
in order to resist
the temptations
and the enticements
of life
how can you
and I
who have Christ
living within us
who have died
therefore to sin
how in the world
can we as a Christian
never say
that sloppy Christian
living is alright
we can live a life
that leaves a lot
to be desired
it doesn't make
any difference
whether we measure up
it doesn't make
any difference
whether we're on
the beam
or whether we're
off of the beam
how in the world
can a child of God
that is baptized
ever say that
when in baptism
he has been connected
with the death
of Jesus
Paul says
we are dead to sin
like a dead man
take a dead man
who has died
from acute alcoholism
alright he's here
in the casket
he's died
because he is
drunk to excess
you can line
that man's casket
with all the
alcoholic beverages
you want
you can surround
that casket
with all of the
alcohol you want
that man's dead
and there is
no enticement
anymore
he's dead
to that temptation
or you can take
a man that has died
because of
profligate living
and you can surround
that casket
when he's dead
with all of the
Christine Keelers
and all of the
called girls
in the world
and they can stand
there and entice
and induce
but he's dead
therefore he is
immune
to temptation
and in the same way
when you and I
were baptized
and Christ moved
into your heart
and mind
by faith
he gave us power
so that as he died
once and for all
for sin
by turning to him
for power
you and I
have died
once and for all
to temptation
and to enticement
and therefore
when it's shoddy
Christian living
when it's sloppy
living
when you and I
are not on the beam
when your life
and mine
needs so much
to be desired
and we know it
and we don't care
what are we doing
we are saying
to Jesus Christ
who came to live
with us
when we were baptized
I don't want you
as savior
we are saying
to him
get out of my life
we are saying
to him
as far as
Calvary is concerned
he didn't have to die
for me
and may I say
with all the strength
of my own soul
that any man
that defies
Jesus Christ
and drives him
out of his life
is lost
he is lost
because of his life
not because
the forgiving
grace of God
failed
but because
by sloppy
Christian living
he drove
Jesus Christ
from his life
and that's why
you and I
today
when again
we talk about
salvation by grace
and that's true
and we say
we're not saved
by our life
and that's true
but nevertheless
it does not
follow from
those two truths
that it makes
no difference
how you and I
live
we dare not
say that we
can be off
of the beam
Paul
called with the
intensity of his
being to the
Roman Christians
you have got
to see to it
that you're not
off of the beam
away with
careless
Christian living
and if we
would determine
today as
baptized Christians
that we are
going to see
to it that
we are never
off of the
beam
that to the
strength that
we have in
Jesus Christ
we are going
to therefore
avoid careless
Christian living
then there would
be some
discipline in
our life
how many of
us when we
became a
Christian or
when we were
baptized or
embraced Christ
ever said to
ourselves
now it's
something where
I've got to
discipline my
life
you know we
sing the old
song
take my
life and
let it be
and that's
just about the
way some
Christians feel
about it
they stop
to take my
life Lord
and let it
be just as
it is
I want it
warm and I
want to live
just as I
please and I'm
going to fulfill
the lusts of my
heart and don't
you get in my
way take my
life Lord and
save me but
let me be
but the hymn
says take my
life and let
it be consecrated
Lord to the
tremendous
difference when
the athlete gets
ready he
disciplines himself
and he trains
himself how
many of us
train ourselves
to be on the
being how
many of us
say it's of
utmost importance
that our lives
shall not be
sloppy Christian
lives but will
be on the
being to have
lives that are
commensurate with
our Christian
faith to have
lives that measure
up to a certain
degree with what
that life ought to
be that it
because we are
baptized when
God says I
shall have no
other gods before
me how many of
us discipline
ourselves and
say God's got
to come first
when God says
not to take his
name in vain how
many of us have
controlled ourselves
that blasphemy and
cursing do not
come from our
hearts because it's
wrong we're off
the beam when
God says remember
the Sabbath day to
keep it holy how
many of us discipline
ourselves to say
that we're going to
worship God and
be in his house
unless God makes
it absolutely
impossible how
many of us have
ever disciplined or
is our prayer be
take my life and
let it be don't you
bother me Lord don't
get in my way I'm
going to send to my
heart's content
honor thy father and
thy mother how many
of us are disciplined
in life beyond the
beam with honoring our
parents and God
says thou shalt not
kill how many of us
say hatred is wrong
whether it's in your
heart or mine and
therefore hatred is
something that dare
not be found in the
Christian life because
you're off the beam
that's sloppy Christian
living that is
dethroning Christ
thou shalt not
commit adultery how
many of us looking
into our own hearts
have got to say away
with sinful thoughts
and desires I've in
baptism died to sin
thou shalt not steal
honesty in business
honesty with one
another bearing false
witness watching the
tongue that we speak
in love not coveting
how many of us have
disciplined ourselves
or is it only this
take my life and let
it be that it's a
great party and we
say boy this is
heaven too what a
chump is God and oh
how stupid God can
you be to save us by
grace that leaves us
and not we can go out
and live just as we
please no you can't
live just as you
please you and I
were baptized into his
death and that also
means this that when
we were baptized into
the death of Jesus
Christ we were put
into a relationship
we were joined to his
death which occurred
once and that was
followed by his
resurrection Paul says
Christ died once and
then he rose again and
we know that he did he
rose from the dead
showing that he had
gained the salvation
that he had again
atoned for on Calvary
and now Paul makes an
analogy he says Christ
died to sin then he
arose to a new life
then again that human
nature of his shared
in all the glory of
the divine nature
true God and true man
and he appeared and
he disappeared to the
disciples and to his
followers there was the
glory that was his
and newness of life
Paul says in the same
way when you were
baptized into his
death you died to sin
and then he says you
arose to a new life
why because the Holy
Spirit came to dwell
into our hearts
baptism means that
something happened to
you and me something
miraculous what
happened why we were
born of water and the
spirit we were born
again the Holy Ghost
on the day of your
baptism and mine he
came into our hearts
for the first time or
sealed himself when we
were baptized and when
the Holy Spirit came
into your hearts and
life and mine we were
born a second time
there was a living faith
in Jesus Christ and
when the Holy Spirit
came to dwell in us he
came so that our lives
when we would strive
would be pleasing to
God isn't it a
marvelous thing to know
that the Spirit of God
dwells in you and me
since the day of our
baptism when we were
baptized as infants
that it's sealed to us
as we were baptized as
adults and that Holy
Spirit takes the efforts
of your life and mine
and he adds the
righteousness of Jesus
Christ that our life
becomes pleasing to God
and listen in the moment
when we say to ourselves
it doesn't make any
difference how I live
I can live a sloppy
Christian life I don't
have to measure up I
can just be a lazy
fair individual and let
it go and come and let
my life be just as it is
but in the moment when
that becomes our
attitude what are we
doing we're grieving
the Holy Spirit the
Holy Spirit crying and
striving with you and
me struggling to get
us again to live as
God would have us live
and we say no the
tremendous danger is
this that we hardened
our hearts we hardened
our consciences to the
point where we can
harden our hearts that
the Holy Spirit will
leave your life and
mine and never come
back and we'll never
want him back and we
committed the sin
against the Holy Ghost
the unpardonable sin
which is nothing but
rebellion and you
and I can lose life
and salvation in the
name of Jesus by
living lives that are
careless and sloppy
and off the beam and
sinning against the
Holy Ghost oh we are
saved by grace yes we
Lutherans we shout it to
the heavens and that's
the very joy of our
church but let me tell
you Lutheran Christians
it's also a danger don't
you ever draw the
conclusion that God is
stupid because he saved
us by grace and that
therefore it doesn't make
any difference how we
live and we can be off
of the beam and live a
sloppy life and grace is
sufficient whenever there
is sloppiness in your life
and mine and we know it
we're grieving the Holy
Spirit and that's a
dangerous dangerous thing
today we ought to say to
us thank God we are saved
by his forgiving grace
it's the only way he could
save us but all if we
just live as baptized
Christians ought to live
who have been baptized into
Christ's death who are new
people in him who are born
again of the Holy Spirit
what it would mean if we
would just live as baptized
Christians saying I'm going
to get on the beam I've got
to be right there right in
center who knows what's going
to happen oh it's wonderful
to be on the beam and again
no sloppy living you know
Paul finally was brought back
to Rome after he had been
imprisoned for two years and
he stood before his
executioner and it was a
matter of life and death
and the big thing was Paul
if you confess Jesus Christ
as Lord your head's going
to be cut off he didn't have
to have his head cut off
somebody said what would
Paul what would he have had
to have done to in order to
have saved himself from
execution why it was a
simple thing if Paul when he
stood in Rome and I stood at
the place where tradition says
he was beheaded if when Paul
stood there and they asked
him do you embrace Jesus
Christ if he had been
willing to take a little
salt throw it over his
shoulder pronounce the name
of the emperor if he'd have
said oh Nero and would have
called upon one of the
Roman gods said oh Jupiter
that man could have walked
out of there scot-free with
his life we might say to
ourselves well now wait a
minute it wouldn't have made
much difference would why
didn't he take a little salt
and throw it over his
shoulder why didn't he say oh
Nero why didn't he say oh
Jupiter and he could have
walked out oh he could have
been a great help to the
church why because Paul had
been baptized into the death
of Jesus and he knew that the
saving grace of God was meant
to save him never to use it and
to look at God to use it as a
way of escape and to interpret
it as being something from a
stupid God and because Paul's
life as he lived it it wasn't a
soggy looking thing it was
something again it was not
sloppy and because he lived in
Christ he stood there and he
said no there'll be no salt
thrown over my shoulder I'll not
call on Nero I'll not call on
Jupiter I put my faith and my
trust in Jesus Christ and again
the sword cut that head from that
body and he gave his life because
he knew the joy of living a life
and being on the beam and when we
have lived our lives on the beam with
the power of Jesus Christ because we
have been baptized into his death
think of the joy that awaits us
yesterday we talked about the eclipse
of the Sun didn't we were told not to
look at it for a length of time lest
indeed the brightness of the light of the
rays would burn the eyes imagine what it
will be when we have been on the ball
showing that our faith in Jesus
Christ and in his grace is a living
thing when we shall see the great
beam Jesus Christ and our eyes shall
behold him and we shall not be blinded
but we shall see him who is the
brightest beam because he is God
himself oh to do away with sloppiness
in Christian living to do away with the
idea that it doesn't make any
difference to do away with the idea
that it doesn't matter whether we're on
the beam or off the beam oh to God that
we could walk the glory road and we
could have the assurance that comes when
we can say to ourselves I know that
when I was baptized thank God I was
baptized into Christ's death and then a
life well that gives evidence that we
are still in grace and we can sing on the
glory road blessed assurance Jesus is
mine oh what a foretaste of glory divine
heir of salvation purchased by God born of
his spirit washed in his blood this is my
story this is my song praising my Savior
all the day long this is my story this is
my song praising my Savior all the day long
God grant that you and I can be on the
beam amen
the peace of God which passeth all human
understanding keeping unite your hearts
minds and minds in Christ Jesus unto life
everlasting
everything
onun
osterior
fale
o
Camp
hay
rol