It be unto you and peace from God our Father and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written in the letter of Paul to the Romans,
our regular epistolary lesson for this Sunday, reading there in the 8th chapter, especially the 14th verse.
For as many as are led by the Spirit of God, they are the sons of God.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, the Lord of our life, dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Today, as we know, is the 8th Sunday after Trinity.
That is the 8th Sunday since we have celebrated the festival of the Holy Trinity.
And it is our custom on the Sundays after Trinity to deal with some of the practical matters of the Christian life.
And today we have this question to be asked, and it's this.
Who are the sons of God?
Who are really God's children?
Who are really God's sons or God's daughters?
And I am sure that if without thinking you and I would answer, we would probably say hastily,
why, all of us are God's children.
All of us are sons of God.
All of us are daughters of God, whatever the case may be.
And we would say, why, we are children of God because we are human beings.
All human beings are children of God.
You know, it's rather strange when we turn to the word of God, however, with that question,
and we ask on the basis of the scriptures,
just who are the sons and the daughters and the children of God?
We do not get that answer, that everyone, because he is a human being, is a son of God.
We find the apostle Paul writing by authority of God in the scriptures
as he writes to the Christian congregation at Rome, talking about this very matter.
And this is what the word of God says,
For as many as are led by the Spirit of God, they are the sons of God.
God's word says, therefore, that not all men, because they are human beings, are children of God,
but only such as are led by the Holy Spirit, only those who have the Holy Spirit,
are really God's sons or God's children.
That's a bitter pill to swallow, isn't it?
Some of us may resent that strenuously.
To say, do you mean to say that only the person who is guided by the Holy Spirit,
that only a person that has the Holy Spirit is a child of God?
We may say to ourselves, that can't be right.
There's no connection between the Holy Spirit and between a person being a son of God.
We may say, regardless of what anybody says,
I still believe that if I'm a human being, I'm a child of God.
And it doesn't make any difference whether I am led by the Holy Spirit,
whether I have him or whether I do not have him.
Quite a dispute, and it's quite bitter, isn't it?
But the fact still remains that when we turn to the authority of the Scriptures,
that the word of God tells us,
when we ask who are really God's sons and God's children,
the word of God says,
It is well this morning that we look at that statement from the word of God
to see whether it has any element of truth.
We may say there's no connection between the Holy Spirit and a man being a child of God,
but there is.
The Holy Spirit has a definite connection
because the Holy Spirit is the must in your life and mine
if we are children of God.
He is the essential one
if you and I are sons and daughters of God.
Without the Holy Spirit, we are not sons of God.
With him we are.
No human being, merely because he is a human being, is a child of God.
You've got to have the Holy Spirit and you've got to be led by him.
Why?
Why is he the absolute must?
Why is he the absolute essential?
Why is he the absolute necessity
in order that we can call ourselves children of God?
Because in the first place, let's know this,
the Holy Spirit is the one who makes us sons of God.
We are not sons of God or children of God until the Holy Spirit makes us such.
We are not children of God because we are merely human beings.
You may say to me,
Well, preacher, what are we then if we aren't children of God?
We are creatures of God, but we are not sons and daughters, children of God.
But you may say to me this morning,
Well, that's just a matter of semantics.
You're just arguing words.
What's the difference whether I'm a creature of God or whether I'm a child of God?
It doesn't make any difference, doesn't it?
When you turn to the Word of God again,
if you and I are mere creatures of God,
because we have been created and given life,
we are most miserable of all men
because the Word of God says we were born in trespasses and sin.
And the Word of God says we are all children of wrath.
We are therefore, if we are mere creations of God, merely creatures,
then look at our natural status.
We come into this world without any knowledge of God,
and that's why a man who is worldly,
who doesn't know anything about God,
doesn't even know whom I'm talking about when I talk about the Holy Spirit.
You and I come into this world not knowing that there is one God
and yet three persons,
God the Father, God the Son, and God the Holy Spirit.
But we come into this world not knowing that the Holy Spirit is the one
who makes us children of God.
We come into this world being dead in sin,
under the contamination and the taint of guilt and the taint of punishment.
The very fact that you and I can die is an evidence
that we come into this world as sinners.
And therefore, if we are only creatures of God,
there is a tremendous difference
because as creatures of God we are lost.
We stand condemned in the sight of a just God.
And therefore, in order to be children of God,
we must have the Holy Spirit who is the one who comes to us
and who makes us sons of God.
And we may say, how does he do it?
In infancy he does it in baptism.
By means of baptism, being born of water in the Holy Spirit,
he makes us children of God.
He implants a living faith in Jesus Christ into our hearts.
And he comes to us as an adult when we can hear the Word of God.
And first of all, the Holy Spirit through the Word of God
brings us to a conviction of sin.
When you and I stand before God and admit that we are a sinner,
admit that we have broken God's law
and we deserve eternal death and damnation,
we are under conviction.
And the Holy Spirit is the one who has brought us to that sorrow for sin.
And then the Holy Spirit through the Word of God
brings us to a living trust in Jesus Christ.
He causes you and me to stand in front of Calvary
and shows us the Christ who died for our sins,
the Christ that bore hell and damnation for you and me.
And when we are brought to put our trust in him and his righteousness,
then you and I and only then do we become children of God.
Paul uses a beautiful word.
He says we become in the spirit of adoption.
God adopts us as his children.
You see, God has only one son,
the only begotten son, Jesus Christ.
And therefore, when we become children of God,
we become his children only in the one way
in which it's possible, by adoption.
And that's a beautiful word
because that word has the connotation of love,
that God desires to make you and me his children.
And therefore, the universal marks of a child of God
is this, first of all, a conviction of sin
and a real trust in Jesus Christ as personal Lord and Savior.
Well, that means we have been born again.
That means we have been converted,
whatever word you like.
But it is the Holy Spirit who brings you and me
into sonship with God.
Just being a human being means we are only God's creatures.
And when the Holy Spirit makes us children of God,
then we are granted from him the forgiveness of our sins
and we are delivered from the eternal punishment of sin.
What must it mean to be a son of God,
to be born again by means of the Holy Spirit,
to come to a living faith in Christ
and to know that sin is forgiven,
to be able to look at your life
and I to look at mine
and see everything that has been done
contrary to the divine will,
and then to know that by the blood of Jesus Christ,
which is the greatest solvent in all the world,
that the Holy Spirit by means of his blood
washes out of the book of life
everything that you and I have done
contrary to the will of God,
that your life and mine looks at God again
into all of its holiness and righteousness
because the blood of Jesus Christ,
God's Son, cleanseth us from all sin.
Well, that's what it means to be a son of God,
to be born again by the Holy Spirit,
to be delivered from eternal death
and eternal damnation.
That's the status of sonship.
Who are children of God,
not you and not I merely because we're human beings,
know only those who are led by the Spirit,
who have the Holy Spirit,
none others, only God's children
by means of the Holy Spirit who is a necessity.
And when we begin to realize
that there is a tremendous difference
between children of God and those who are not,
well, then common honesty would lead you and me to say
that I want to be led by the Spirit,
that I might be a child of God.
And if that is your desire and mine,
then we ought to look within ourselves
and to ask ourselves,
do we have the Holy Spirit?
Are we being led by him?
How do you know whether you are led by the Spirit?
Have we come to repentance in Jesus Christ?
Have we come to faith in him?
Jesus says,
By their fruits ye shall know them.
The only way to test the genuineness of your faith and mine
is by our life.
Jesus says,
Look at the tree.
What kind of fruit are on the tree?
If there are nothing but corrupt fruits on your tree and mine,
then we are not children of God
because a good tree brings forth good fruit.
Not that you and I don't sin.
Every day we sin and do things that are wrong,
that we are not conscious of.
Every day we do things that we do not want to do,
but in your life and mine there ought not to be this,
that we deliberately do that which we know is wrong.
Are we of debtors to the flesh,
Paul says,
to live after the flesh
when we have become God's children?
We ought to look at the fruit of our life
and to see,
Does our life add up?
Is it the kind of life that ought to be a life
of one who is a child of God,
who is led by God's Spirit?
And when there is that evidence in your life and mine
that we are led by the Spirit
and that we are children of God,
that we have been made such by the Spirit,
then there is gone the fear of death
and the fear of an eternal punishment.
Man spoils himself in life, doesn't he,
by saying to himself,
Oh, I am a creature of God.
I am a human being.
Therefore, I am a child of God.
And yet, why the fear of death?
You know, we talk about funerals today
and we say they're getting smaller and smaller.
We always give us the only reason
because everybody works,
but that isn't the whole story, is it?
One reason why funerals are small is why?
Because we don't like to go to funerals.
Because when we go to funerals,
we are reminded of death.
And we do not like to be reminded of death
because some of us are afraid to die.
And we do not like to think of death
and to think of the judgment.
There might be a judgment.
And that's why some people are very prone
to want their bodies cremated,
hoping that if they should have their bodies
burned and ground into dust,
that even God Almighty will find the resurrection
of that body an impossibility.
But let us not deceive ourselves.
The mills of God grind slowly,
but they grind exceedingly fine,
and there will be a resurrection unto judgment.
And therefore, again,
we may look at our lives knowing this,
that not all of us are children of God,
only those of us who are led by the Spirit,
who have the Holy Spirit.
And oh, again, that burns us up, doesn't it?
And we resent that very thing.
But the Word of God says we are not God's children
simply because we're human beings.
The Word of God says,
for as many of us as are led by the Spirit of God
are the sons of God.
Having the Spirit makes the difference.
Why?
He is the absolute must in your life and mine
if we are children of God,
because the Holy Spirit also in the second place
is not only the one that makes us sons of God,
but He is the one who enables us to claim God as our Father.
Isn't it funny?
In terminology there, everybody calls God His Father.
We talk about the fatherhood of God,
and that's the lie of the age.
There isn't such a thing as the fatherhood of God.
God is no more the Father of all men
than you as the Father,
the Father of all children.
You are the Father only of your children,
even as I.
We are only Father to our own.
And then again, you may say,
well, what are you then if God isn't your Father?
God is the God of everybody,
but He is not the Father of everybody.
You say, that's semantics again.
You're arguing words.
What's the difference if God is my God
or whether God is my Father?
You may say,
doesn't a rose smell just as sweet,
even if you call it by another name?
Does it?
Is there any difference between God being your Father and mine
and God simply being our God?
There's a tremendous difference.
Because if I am not God's child
and He is not my Father,
then when I turn and pray to Him,
my prayers are totally unacceptable to Him.
How many men pray to some supreme being,
call God Father when Jesus Christ
doesn't live within their hearts?
I even had a minister tell me one day,
he says, when I'm in a group
where Christ isn't accepted
and I pray, I leave His name out.
Can you imagine anything any more blasphemous
than to leave out the name of Jesus Christ
in a prayer and deliberately do so
in order to deceive men
that God could possibly be a man's Father
except through Christ?
Jesus put it this way,
He says,
no man cometh unto the Father but by me.
When we pray in the name of Jesus,
it isn't just a form.
When we say we ask it because of Jesus
or through His name or in His name,
listen, it isn't necessary that we say it,
but it's always implied
for the simple reason that
no prayer has the right to be prayed
except it's prayed in the Spirit of Jesus Christ
because God is the Father only
of those who by means of the Holy Spirit
have been brought to faith in Jesus Christ.
How many prayers do you pray in groups
where Christ isn't mentioned and met?
A prayer without Jesus Christ
where He is deliberately left out,
don't forget, is blasphemy.
The prayer is not heard,
it is not acceptable,
it isn't answered.
That is strong language, I know.
But that's the Word of God.
But oh, when the Holy Spirit
has brought you and me
into sonship with Christ,
then, Paul says,
we receive the spirit of adoption
whereby we can cry,
Abba, Father.
Do we realize what it means
to be able to call God
who has created us our Father?
I think of the time in the Civil War.
You recall the soldier
that was caught to sleep
on sentry duty
and was sentenced to be shot?
His father, when he heard about it,
came to Washington
to see Abraham Lincoln, the President.
Naturally having no credentials,
he couldn't get in the White House.
There he was seated on the curb
outside of the White House
crying because the life of his boy
was at stake.
There was a little boy that morning
playing on the sidewalk
outside of the White House
who walked up to the gentleman
and saw him crying and said,
what are you crying about?
The man told him,
I want to see the president,
but they won't let me in.
The little boy offered his hand
to the man and said,
come, we'll go see the president.
The man looked at the boy,
but he took his hand
and the guards left them
go down the sidewalk
and they opened the door
to the White House
and Abraham Lincoln,
the President of the United States,
was in session with his cabinet.
But the door opened
and the little boy walked up
to Abraham Lincoln
with the man
and he says,
Father,
this man wants to talk to you.
It happened to be Todd Lincoln.
Abraham Lincoln was President
of the United States,
but he was Todd Lincoln's father.
And Todd Lincoln,
with all boldness and confidence,
knew that his father
was never too busy to hear him.
And the man pled
for his boy's life
and his boy was saved.
That's the prerogative
and the honor
that comes to us
when by means
of the Holy Spirit,
God becomes our father.
And that means
that you and I
have a glorious privilege
of going to him
with a childlike confidence
any time.
God is never too busy
and God promises
to hear us
and to answer
and always in the best
possible way.
You may say to me,
what do you mean by best?
Why by best
from the standpoint
of the eternal destiny
of your soul and mine,
God answers the prayers
of his children
only in one way
and it's always the best way.
Sometimes he says no.
Sometimes God says yes,
but always there is strength
to bear the things
and always from the point
of view of eternity
that God says,
this thing that I give you,
my child,
is best.
There is a tremendous difference
and we ask,
who are children of God?
Oh, we can argue
all we want to
that everybody,
because he's a human being,
is a child of God.
He isn't.
You are not a child of God.
Neither am I
because I'm a human being.
I'm anything
but a child of God.
For as many years
are led by the Spirit of God,
they are the sons of God.
And therefore,
when we see the status
of sonship,
that God becomes our Father,
well then it ought to be
the very essential
in your life and mind
that we ask ourselves,
am I a child of God?
Or am I just one
of his creatures?
Is God my Father?
Is he merely my creator?
We only need to look
at ourselves
and to ask ourselves,
how about prayer?
How about prayer in your life?
When did we pray last?
When did we turn to God
as our Father
with the confidence
that because he's our Father,
he is willing to listen?
How many of us
are going through life
worried stiff about tomorrow,
afraid to move
in the future?
And we look out
and we can say
as Burns said,
O ye banks
and braes of bonny dune,
how can ye bloom so fair?
How can ye chant,
ye little birds
and eyes so full of care?
How many of us
are so full of care
that life is almost meaningless
and we wonder
whether it's worthwhile
simply because
we've got a Father in Heaven
who promises
to hear and to answer
and we don't even pray.
If you and I
are guided
by the Spirit of God,
if we are sons of God,
we talk to our Father
because our Father
loves us
and our Father
promises courage
for the day.
Jesus prayed,
oh, when he was in Gethsemane,
look what a man of prayer
he was,
as a human being,
let alone God.
And I stood in Gethsemane
again thinking of
how he prayed
so fervently,
free to,
oh, my Father,
calling upon God
as Father.
Oh, my Father,
if it be possible,
let this cup pass through.
Remember,
he spent all night
in prayer
before he chose
the twelve,
communing with God
as his Father
before he picked
the twelve
when he named
James the Greater
and James the Less
and John and Jude
and Judas
and Peter and Philip
and Matthew
and Andrew
and Bartholomew
and Simon
and Thomas.
He did it
after an all-night
in prayer.
One of the earliest prayers
that I learned
in childhood,
this thing Abba,
it's the Hebrew word
which means Father.
It's never been
translated into English.
It's like the word
Amen is Hebrew,
the word Alleluia
is Hebrew.
Hosanna Hebrew
stays in the Hebrew language.
Did you learn
that prayer
Abba,
Lieber,
Fater,
Father,
dear Father,
oh,
and we can cry
again by means
of the Holy Spirit
to God as our Father.
We can face life erect
because God says
that I'll work
everything for your good.
Who are the sons of God
and the children of God?
Oh, again,
those are fighting words
to some individuals.
Some say,
I don't care what you say.
If I'm a human being,
I'm a son of God.
But God doesn't say so.
You and I are not
children of God
simply because
we are human beings.
We are children of God
only when we are led
by the Holy Spirit
because He is the must.
In a man's life,
if a man is a son of God,
it's the Holy Spirit
who must be there.
He is the essential.
Why?
He's not only the one
that makes us sons of God
who enables us
to claim God as Father,
but He's the one also
that bears witness
with our spirit
that we are children of God.
What witness does a man have
that he is a son of God
if he's basing it
merely on the fact
that he's a human being?
Oh, I know that a lot of us
have it.
How many of us have said this?
I'm just as good
as anybody else
who goes to church.
You see,
we try to justify
the fact that I'm a human being.
There are,
I'm a child of God
just as much
as anybody is
that goes to church.
You ever have your neighbor say,
I'm just as good
as anybody who goes to church.
I don't care if you're
a big bunch of hypocrites,
that's why you go.
We ought to remind them,
come on in,
there's room for one more.
But again,
this thing of what you do
and I'm better than you are,
isn't it strange?
We try to justify ourselves
that we are sons of God
because we are human beings
and then, of course,
we're always better
than a lot of people.
Supposing we are.
Strange, though, isn't it,
that we always compare ourselves
with somebody
that we know is worse.
We never compare ourselves
with somebody
that is superior, do we?
But as you come out
on the short end on that,
and that's no fun,
isn't it?
That's no fun.
How many of us
justify ourselves
and try to verify
something within us
that we are sons of God
because we're human beings?
We don't get very far,
do we,
especially when we face death
or especially
if we're honest enough
to face our sins.
When we begin
to face our sins,
then something happens.
But when, again,
the Holy Spirit
causes you and me
to have to our souls
the testimony
that we are children of God,
what does he do?
Through the Word of God,
he testifies to us
because we have repented
of our sins,
because we have put
our trust in Christ
that we are saved.
And in thousands
of scripture passages,
he comes to us
in the Word,
assuring us
that because Christ
died for everyone,
therefore he died
for you and for me,
because his was
an eternal sacrifice,
because it was
for all men,
therefore you and I
are included,
though whosoever
the Word of God
is so broad
and that it includes
every man
and there are
thousands of testimonies
that the Holy Spirit
brings to you and me
through the Word
that we are children of God
and that because
we are children of God,
then the glorious status
that we are heirs of God
and joint heirs
with Christ
of eternal life.
Think of the status
of sons yet.
The man without
Jesus Christ,
the man without
the Holy Spirit
may argue all
he wants
and can say,
I'm a human being,
therefore I'm a child
of God
and that only
the man that has
the must in his life,
the Holy Spirit,
can say that
because the Holy Spirit
has caused him
to be born again
to come to a living
trust in Christ,
that he is an heir
of God
and a joint heir
with Christ.
Think of what it must mean
to be an heir of God,
to be a joint heir
with Christ,
God's only begotten Son,
an heir of eternal life.
Oh, how we hold on
tenaciously to life,
don't we,
and we want it
and when death
comes to a loved one again,
the sorrows that come
because life is sweet
then being an heir
of God
means life forevermore.
What must it mean?
Is it any wonder
that Scripture says,
I have not seen
nor ear heard
neither have entered
into the heart of man
the things which God
has prepared for them
that love him
to have life,
abundant life,
life forevermore.
Now that's what we
inherit in Jesus Christ,
sons of God,
not mere again
creatures of God
because those are
words that burn.
we ought to say
to ourselves,
we are not
sons of God
because we are
human beings.
We are sons of God
only as we are led
by the Holy Spirit
that God's Spirit
dwells in our hearts
by faith.
And in order to know
whether he is there,
we ought to ask him,
what's our attitude
towards the word of God?
How did we feel
in coming to church
this morning?
I wonder if we get up
on Sunday
and ever say to ourselves,
this is the day
which the Lord
is made,
we will rejoice
and be glad in it.
Or is going to church
a humdrum thing
that it's a matter
of duty
we can't reel
it over with
to get out?
Or do we come to church
and say,
thank God the Holy Spirit
through the word of God
that will be preached
will bear witness
with my spirit
that I am a child of God
and when I am a child
of God,
nothing else matters
and can we go out
of church feeling
that we have confronted
God,
that we have seen
him in his word.
That we go out
as sons of God
holding our heads
high in him
because he is our father
and he understands.
Paul said again
that when the spirit
bears witness
with our spirit
we are the sons of God
and then there is
joy in suffering.
But what's happened?
What's happened?
Why is it that the world
doesn't hate the church
as the world
ought to hate the church?
Maybe some of you
this morning say,
I don't believe
what you're saying.
Maybe some of you
are saying,
if what you are saying
is true
that only they
are children of God
who have the Holy Spirit
and I don't have
the Holy Spirit
to see what that does
to you,
it makes you lost,
doesn't it?
No man likes that.
There is a stigma
that is attached
to being a Christian,
a child of God
and belonging
to the church.
What's happening
in America
that the world
loves the church
like it loves it?
Why is it that
belonging to the church
today is a status symbol?
Everybody belongs
to the church.
It's grand.
The big thing is
find out the one
where your social standing
will be a little larger.
That's the big thing today.
It's the thing to do
to go to church.
The world
ought to hate the church
because the church
says to the world,
you may be a human being
but unless you are led
by the Spirit of God,
you are not God's son,
you are damned.
Those ought to be
fighting words.
What's happened
to the church?
Oh, in this great
ecumenical movement
that is going on,
certainly it'd be wonderful
if the church were one.
But I'm wondering
if the church
in its desire
to be one
is forgetting
the message
that it has
and that's a two-edged sword.
The message
that cuts to the quick
that tells the man
of the world
without the Holy Spirit
you're not a child
of God
regardless of what you say,
you're lost,
you're damned.
That should make
a man hate the church.
Look at Paul.
On his first missionary
journey with Barnabas
when they come over
again to the island of Cyprus,
came up into Asia Minor,
remember when they came
to a place called Derbe
and when Paul was there
here were people
worshiping idols
and he healed a man
that had been crippled
from his mother's womb
and they began
to worship Paul
and Barnabas
as though they were
gods in human flesh
and they called Barnabas
Jupiter
and they called
Paul Mercury
because he was the spokesman
and they began
to offer sacrifices
and Paul stopped them
and he said
we're only human beings
and then Paul preached
the gospel
but what did he tell them
at this time?
He told them
that only in Jesus Christ
does a man
become a child of God
and then because
he had said
the same message
over in Iconium
they came from Iconium
they got a hold of Paul
and they took him out
and they stoned him
as far as they were concerned
they killed him
because of the stigma
of being a Christian
they thought he was dead
after being stoned
but he got up
there must have been
a young man
who was watching
because when Paul
came back to Derbe
he picked up the young man
you know
became a great war horse
in the church too
Timothy
Timothy must have seen
all that
and again
he went on
carrying the torch
but when Paul
preached the essence
of the gospel
and let it be seen
that only the man
that has Christ
is a child of God
they tried to kill him
it's the stigma
of the cross
nobody's killing
anybody else
in America today
are we
because somehow
or other
the church
has gotten so soft
and so supine
and so self-sufficient
that the world
says that'll never
harm us
we're just alright
too
whether you're in
or whether you're out
have you ever been
in a place
where it was a stigma
to be a Christian
last summer
I was in a nation
where to be a Christian
was a stigma
we were in a restaurant
in a certain city
a very nice restaurant
we had had our meal
and right up a few stairs
from the main part
of the restaurant
there was a grand piano
standing there
and one of our party
of 25
a school teacher
walked over
and sat down
at the piano
and began to play
very fine pianist
also by the way
she began to play
a popular number
of we sing here
in the United States
it had an electrifying
effect in that restaurant
I was amazed
that they know
our popular music
and they began to sing
and the waiters
stood there
and they watched
and there was approval
and there was applause
as she played
from one number
to the other
then as she modulated
from one song
to the other
she started to play
a Christian hymn
and when she started
to play the Christian hymn
and some of us
sang rather softly
the silence
in that restaurant
was deaf
everybody stood there
there was a glare
because they hated
Jesus Christ
I know
what the stigma
of the cross is
I felt it
key
just get
some place
where Christ
is he
where other religions
have taken the place
and you begin
to realize
the world
ought to eat
the church
because the church
and I can't speak
in any plain
or says to a man
just because
you're a human being
you may be
a fine human being
that doesn't make
you a child
of God
you're lost
you've got
to have
the Holy Spirit
you've got
to come
to a conviction
of sin
and you've got
to come
to a living
trust in Jesus
Christ
or you're lost
those are
fighting words
that's the stigma
of the cross
but when God
is our father
we ought to
walk the glory
road
and we ought
to say to ourselves
am I a soldier
of the cross
a follower
of the lamb
shall I blush
to own his cause
or even to speak
his name
must I be carried
to the skies
on flowery beds
of ease
while others
fought to win
the prize
and sailed
through blood
he sees
am I a soldier
of the cross
we ought to realize
that to be a son
of God
means to be a soldier
of the cross
but to walk
the glory road
in this conviction
this is still
our father's
world
isn't it
this is my
father's world
why should my
heart be sad
isn't it time
that the message
of Jesus Christ
becomes so
pertinent
and sharp
that at least
the man of the world
knows that we're
talking about it
if some of you
hate me this morning
because I have
told you that
just because
you're a human
being
you are not
the son of God
that's the
stigma of the cross
but my prayer
is
that you'll not
go out of this
church this morning
but what you
will ask the
Holy Spirit
to bring you
to a conviction
of sin
and to a living
trust in Jesus
Christ
that you can
go out of church
and know the joy
of what it means
to be a son of God
Amen
The peace of God
which passeth
all human understanding
keep and unite
your hearts and minds
in Christ Jesus
unto life everlasting