Let us be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God taken from our epistolary lesson for this Sunday,
written in Paul's letter to the Ephesians, reading there in the fifth chapter, the seventeenth verse.
Wherefore be ye not unwise, but understanding what the will of the Lord is.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
Sons and daughters of the Protestant Reformation, in Christ Jesus, dear friends,
you who are here in God's house this morning, and you also, Christian friends,
who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
This coming Thursday marks the 446th anniversary of the great Protestant Reformation.
It was on October the 31st, 1517, that a young Augustinian monk by the name of Martin Luther
nailed on to the castle door of the church in Wittenberg in Germany 95 theses or propositions.
And those hammer blows, believe me, Christian friends, rocked the earth to its very foundations.
Those hammer blows that day changed the entire course of human events in this world.
And all because those 95 theses or propositions had at their heart and center this question,
what is the way to heaven?
What is the way of salvation?
What is the way to eternal life?
And Martin Luther, in those propositions, proclaimed a way of salvation that was new.
It was different than the accepted way of his day.
That's why those hammer blows rocked the very earth on which you and I walk.
And today, as we stand, 446 years later, and we say to ourselves, what does that mean to me?
And above all, we look at it and we say, is it possible, therefore,
since Martin Luther announced a new way of salvation,
one that was different from the accepted way of his day,
is it possible today to come to the unvarnished truth with regard to the way to heaven?
Is it possible to really know the truth?
Is it possible to have the unadulterated truth?
This is the way to heaven.
I read as my text the word of God from the apostle Paul to the congregation at Ephesus.
And there in writing to them he says these words,
Wherefore, he says, be ye not unwise.
Wherefore, don't be fools, he tells the Ephesian Christians,
but understand what the will of the Lord is.
Understand and know the will of the Lord.
In other words, what is the will of the Lord?
What is the way of salvation?
What is his will with regard to the way of eternal life?
And when Paul calls upon you and me through the word of God that we are not to be fools,
that you and I are to be wise and therefore we are to understand the will of God with regard to the way of salvation,
let's realize this, that it is possible, it is not beyond our grasp,
it is not beyond our reach,
that today, 446 years later,
we can ask ourselves,
What is the truth in this matter?
What is the way to heaven and to eternal life?
It is within our grasp because in the first place,
God has given us his scriptures wherein is made known the way to heaven.
Martin Luther wondered what is the way of salvation.
He wondered,
Is it the way I have been taught?
Is it the way I have been told?
Is it what others have told me?
Is it what the church says?
Is it what the church has decreed in its counsels and in its decisions?
Martin Luther said,
I am going to turn to the Bible.
Why?
Because he found in the Bible that the apostle Paul,
writing to the young Timothy,
had said these words in his second letter.
He said,
But continue thou in the things which thou hast learned and been approved of,
that not from a child thou hast known the holy scriptures,
which are able to make thee wise unto salvation.
Martin Luther knows that in the scriptures a man becomes wise to salvation.
A man in the scriptures no longer is a fool,
that he turns to the scriptures and he finds the way of salvation.
Because Paul had said to Timothy,
Again,
Thou hast known the holy scriptures from a child,
which are able to make thee wise unto salvation.
Because he says all scripture is given by inspiration of God.
All scripture is given by the authority of God,
that God's spirit has moved men to write,
that they have written what God wants them to write without error.
This is the inspired, the infallible word.
And therefore Paul told Timothy,
And it is profitable for doctrine to find out the truth,
for an instruction, again,
that the man of God may be perfect,
thoroughly furnished unto all good works.
And so Luther turned to the word of God,
to the inspired writings.
What do the scriptures say?
This is the only authority.
This is the only inspired and infallible authority we have.
Again, he knew that Christ had preached on earth.
There was no New Testament when Jesus was preaching.
Again, Christ preached and then came the apostles.
They had the Old Testament.
But when again they had preached,
we say to ourselves,
What did they preach?
Do you realize Jesus never wrote a word,
as far as we know?
We have no record of any writing of Jesus.
It was written for him.
The Holy Spirit therefore wrote down what Jesus had taught
and what the disciples had preached,
that you and I might know the truth.
Jesus said,
If you continue in my word,
you shall know the truth,
and the truth shall make you free.
And therefore God's Holy Spirit wrote down for us
that we have the New Testament.
There was Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John
who gave us written records of the life of Jesus.
There was the book of Acts,
the history of the Christian church of the first century,
written by Luke,
the only Gentile writer of the New Testament.
And then came the letters that Paul wrote
by inspiration of God
as he went on his three missionary journeys
in established Christian congregations.
The letter to the Romans that we have.
First and second Corinthians
is letter to the congregation at Corinth in Greece.
Galatians,
the letter to the Galatian Christians
up in the province of Asia Minor.
And then Philippians up in Macedonia
where Lydia, the seller of purple, lived,
you recall.
And in Thessalonica in Greece.
And again,
then the letters to Timothy
and to Titus
and to Philemon
and the book of Hebrews.
Whether Paul wrote it,
we do not know.
But again,
this is the letter to the Jewish Christians.
And then we have the letter
again of James,
the brother of the Lord,
and of Jude,
the brother of the Lord.
The two letters
that the Apostle Peter has left us.
The three letters of John
besides the Gospel.
And then finally,
the revelation,
the Apocalypse.
God has given us this record
by inspiration.
And it was Martin Luther
that went to the Word of God
and said,
what does the Word of God say?
This is the one
and this is the only authority.
And you and I have it.
And therefore,
we can say today,
446 years later,
this Bible is open to you
and to me
and to all men
to go and find out
for ourselves
what does the Word of God say
as regards the way to heaven
and the way to eternal life.
At the time of the Reformation
under Martin Luther,
movable type
had been invented
by Gutenberg.
And therefore,
when there came
movable type,
here was an opportunity
to print the Bible.
Luther went to the Wartburg
and there he spent time
translating the entire Bible
into the language
of the German people.
Think of it.
What a colossal,
gigantic task.
The Old Testament,
39 books written in Hebrew,
translating them into German.
The 27 books of the New Testament
written originally in Greek,
translating them into German.
When the German language
didn't have the word,
he invented the word.
A friend and colleague of mine
just coming back
from Helsinki
where the Lutheran World
Federation was held,
came with a party
into East Germany
and he went to Isleben
where Luther was born
and went over to Wittenberg
and they went to
the Wartburg Castle
where Luther translated
the Bible
into the language
of the common people.
And a communist guide said,
here is where a man
by the name of Martin Luther
invented the German language.
That is all communism
will say about him.
But Martin Luther did more
than invent the German language.
He translated the Bible
into the language
of the people
that the people
might have the opportunity
to go to the word of God
and find out
what is this way
of salvation.
True,
446 years ago
Martin Luther
did announce
and promulgate
a new way of salvation.
It was new in this
that it was different
than the accepted way
but it really wasn't new.
It was the way
of scriptures.
And that's why today
as we stand
446 years later
we ought to say
to ourselves
since Paul calls upon us
not to be fools
but understand
what the will of God is
know it
know the unvarnished truth
we ought to determine
that that's what we want
and if we want it
badly enough
then we would familiarize
ourselves
with the word of God.
How many of us
are content
to take the minister's word
for it?
Content to take
what the church says?
what other individuals say
as regards
the way to heaven?
The greatest question
the most important question
in your life and mine.
I was interested
in reading
that Cardinal Joseph
Sittler
from the Archdiocese
of St. Louis
when Cardinal Ritter
is his name
was over at the
second assembly
of the ecumenical conference
in Rome
Cardinal Ritter
who is the Archbishop
of St. Louis
in that cathedral
where I have been
many a time
he made this speech
in Rome
and he called
upon his church
he said this
when he was asked
what does the church need?
he said
my church
must go back
to more preaching
it must have
the preaching
of the word of God
there is too much
liturgy in the church
there isn't enough
preaching of the word of God
and to that I say
yea and amen
because that's
what every church needs
is preaching
of the word of God
I was in
St. Peter's Cathedral
on a Sunday morning
in Rome
and again
they were building
the bleachers
for the ecumenical meeting
they were sawing wood
and hammering
you couldn't hear yourself
think
when you're in the cathedrals
you say
how could anybody be heard?
well they were not built
to be preached in
they were not built
to be heard in
because in the rendition
of a liturgy
you don't have to hear much
there is no preaching
and therefore again
they are built
to preach in
that's what God wants
and when the church
of Jesus Christ
whether it's Roman Catholic
or whether it's Lutheran
or what have you
goes back to a preaching
of the word of God
then and only then
shall we come
to that untarnished truth
and that certainty
as regards
the way of salvation
that's what we need
I know Lutheran ministers
who have said to me
give me the liturgy
and you can omit the sermon
listen liturgy
is all right
but sometimes
I change it
and put it into
20th century vernacular
and then you sit up
and you act like
you're awake
and you take part
and the organist wonders
will I get my cue?
but again
it can get humdrum
yes liturgy
is all right
but it can never
take the place
of the preaching
of the word of God
that's exactly
what we need
and again
thank God
for anybody
who wants to put it
back in the church
because if there's
going to be unity
it's going to have
to be unity
on the basis
of the word of God
and the biggest question
that faces you and me
is simply this one
what is the way to heaven?
446 years ago
Martin Luther
in his theses
announced a new
way of salvation
it was new
in that it was
different from
the accepted way
and as you and I
stand here
over four centuries
later and say
to ourselves
can we come
to certainty
and know the
unbiredest truth
we can
why?
not only because
again God
has given us
the scriptures
when it's revealed
the way
but in the second place
these scriptures
that God has given us
they testify
that we are saved
by grace
alone
that salvation
is by grace
alone
you may say
preacher
what do you mean
grace alone
you may say
you men
preach in language
that we can't
understand
and it goes
overhead
well what good
is preaching
if it's over
what do you mean
by grace alone
Paul says
when he wrote
to the Ephesians
we are saved
by grace
what do you mean
grace
think of
grace is
the undeserved
love of God
it's the mercy
of God
let's get at it
this way
did you ever buy
a package of
food of some kind
either in a can
or in a package
and it's set on the label
untouched by human hand
I'm sure you have
where it again
would have you know
that no human hand
touched this
this was prepared
exclusively
without a human hand
having touched it
use that for a moment
I think it will become
clear what we mean
by salvation
by grace alone
salvation by grace alone
means this
it is untouched
by human hand
let me put it this way
salvation by grace
by the mercy of God
means this
that salvation
was bought
and paid for
packaged
and ready
for you and me
before you or I
were ever born
does that help
you and I
never touched it
salvation
eternal life
deliverance
from hell
and damnation
has all been bought
and paid
and packaged
without you and I
ever having
touched it
no human being
it is ready
and has been
before we were
ever born
we had
nothing to do
with it
whatever
that's what
grace means
why
because the love
of God
this mercy of his
when God saw
that we could not
have anything to do
with it
that you and I
could not save
ourselves
God sent his son
Jesus Christ
into the world
and he went
to Calvary's cross
and there is
the God
man
true God
and true man
he bore the guilt
and the punishment
of your sins
and mine
all of the guilt
and all of the
punishment
he bore the guilt
of your coming
into this world
in sin
and I coming
into this world
in sin
he bore the guilt
of our mortal
and again
of our venial
sins
he bore the guilt
of every thought
word and deed
of you and me
before we were
ever born
it was all
bought and paid
for in the
sufferings and
death of Jesus
Christ
he bore the
equal of an
eternity in hell
untouched by
human hands
that is before
you and I
were ever born
that's what it
means
we are saved
by grace
does that help
and that means
this then
that this salvation
that this word
of God proclaims
that is by grace
alone
has been bought
and paid for
and packaged
and made ready
for the entire
human race
from the time
of Adam
to the last
child
that will ever
be born
of woman
that's what
grace means
but you and I
may have a little
problem
we may say
well I can see
where it's bought
and paid for
for me
because I live
after Calvary
how about those
who lived before
Calvary
well the Bible
answers that one too
because it tells us
that Jesus Christ
Calvary
he was the lamb
slain
before the foundation
of the world
in the eyes of God
it was a timeless
sacrifice
and Christ
in the eyes
of his heavenly father
was slain
even before Adam
was created
therefore
salvation
eternal life
for Adam
and Eve
were bought
and paid for
and absolutely
boxed and packaged
for Adam
and Eve
before they were
ever created
does that help
that's what it
means
that salvation
is by grace
alone
and you and I
can say
is it possible
that we may come
to certainty
this Bible
says that we
are saved
by grace
alone
Paul again
writing to the
feet
says by grace
are ye saved
and it's been
prepared
bought
and paid
for
untouched
by you
and me
already
waiting
in the blood
of Jesus
Christ
and that's
why today
446 years
later
we ought to
say to ourselves
if I can come
to certainty
if Paul says
be not unwise
don't be fools
and he says
understand what
the will of God
is that I can
come to certainty
that I can
know this
truth
as regards
the way
of salvation
then I ought
to thank
God
that God
has restored
that truth
true it was
new
and some say
because it was
new and different
when Martin Luther
announced it
because it was
different from
the accepted way
therefore it was
wrong
listen
it was new
only in the sense
that it was
different
it wasn't
new
it was as old
as the Christian
church
take the book
of Acts
and go back
to an account
there
of the council
of Jerusalem
that met in
about the year
this was the
problem that
came up in
the early
Christian church
is salvation
by grace
alone
is it prepared
by God
alone
through Christ
untouched
by human hands
and there was
a meeting
in Jerusalem
because the
problem was
vexing the
church
is that it
well what
happened
Peter was there
and Peter
told of his
experience
that he went
to Caesarea
remember when he
was called
to Caesarea
I stood in
that old
sea coast
town
and there
lived Cornelius
who was
again a
Gentile
a non-Jew
Cornelius
wanted to be
a Christian
and therefore
how does a
non-Jew
a Gentile
become a
Christian
well Jewish
Christians
thought
that they
had to be
circumcised
first
and become
a Jew
you've got
to circumcise
a Gentile
then you can
become a
Christian
but you see
what that
meant
that meant
that salvation
was not
by grace
alone
that it
had to be
touched
by human
hand
that man
was going
to add
something
well Peter
said when I
went to
Caesarea
and I
went into
Cornelius'
home
and he
wanted to
be a
Christian
and I
baptized him
he said the
Holy Spirit
manifested himself
and we talked
in languages
that we had
never learned
before
just as we
did on the
day of
Pentecost
Peter said
surely the
Holy Spirit
was telling
us this is
the way it
is
and then Paul
got up
and Paul
testified at
that council
meeting
and he said
on my
missionary journeys
when I preached
to Gentiles
he said
there was
the manifestation
of the Spirit
we never had
to circumcise
Gentiles
there was
nothing they
had to add
it was by
grace
and then James
the brother of the Lord
he got up
and testified
on the basis
of the word of God
the Old Testament
this is what the Bible
says
in the year 50
therefore this thing
was settled
when we talk about
Luther announcing
something new
sure it was new
in the sense
that it was different
but it was the same
old way
that goes right
back to Jesus Christ
that was settled
in the council
of Jerusalem
when again
the Holy Spirit
brought the church
to a unity
this is it
and we ought to
thank God
for it
and we ought to
thank God
that we have it
because again
there is that
certainty
that we can have
we stand here
446 years later
and we say to ourselves
if Luther announced
a new way
after all
if it was different
can we know
can anybody know
why it's within grasp
because again
we've got the scriptures
it's the only authority
that's what he used
the scriptures testify
that salvation
is by grace alone
in the third place
they testify this
God's scriptures
testify
that salvation
or the way to heaven
is by grace alone
through faith
you may say
now bring that down
so I can understand
what are you talking about
faith
well if grace means
this it's untouched
by human hand
if you've got that
it was bought
and paid for
before we were born
let's look at faith
what do you mean by that
by faith we simply mean this
that this tag
it's how do I get it
in other words
if grace
the mercy of God
has made it possible
and it's been ready
for me even before
I was born
how do I get it
well what does
the word of God say
Luther was told
that you get it
again
you get it by
earning it
by your life
and so if ever
a man ever tried
to earn
this gift of grace
that was prepared
before he was born
if ever a man
tried to earn it
by his life
he did
first of all
he became a monk
and that meant
that he took
the vow of poverty
renounced everything
that he ever had
he took the vow of chastity
to live a clean life
he took the vow of celibacy
that he wouldn't marry
he went into the monastery
again
he beat himself
he mortified the flesh
he did everything
that he could
he starved himself
he beat his back
that the blood would run
and all cried out
but it never satisfied
oh Lord
when have I done enough
you see
he was trying
because he had been told
that you get this gift
by again earning it
you get it by your life
but isn't it marvelous
that when he turned
to the word of God
and he saw Paul
writing to the Ephesians
and all said
by grace are ye saved
through faith
that means
not by your life
isn't it marvelous
that it isn't by life
Luther was trying
by his life
but he was haunted
by this
that he knew
that he thought evil thoughts
he spoke things
that he shouldn't say
he had done things
that he shouldn't have done
he had left undone
many a thing
that he should have done
and he cried out
and he said
how can I by my life
ever buy
this gift
of eternal life
and everlasting salvation
and then he read
in the word of God
that the just lives
by faith
or justification
that justified man
is a forgiven man
to be justified
means again
to be saved
it means to have God
declare you without sin
by faith
faith therefore
means it's not
on the basis of life
it means that this gift
becomes yours and mine
on the base of faith
which means to trust
it means to just
humbly trust
Jesus
as your personal
Lord and Savior
and that's what
Martin Luther found
and oh what a joy
that he a sinner
could have this salvation
that was bought
and paid for
in the blood of Christ
before he was ever born
that it was given
to any man
who would just trust Jesus
that would mean
for a man to stand
and to say
I'm a lost sinner
but I put my faith
and my trust
and my hope
of salvation
in you Lord Jesus
that in your righteousness
that you merited
on the cross
that you will give me
that in exchange
for believing
and therefore I am saved
and that's what he found
and again
when a man through faith
puts his trust in Christ
he always commits his life
he gives his life
not that his life saves him
but he gives it
in honor of Jesus
and he gives it
as a sense of gratitude
because he has been saved
certainly the life
goes along
but again
salvation is
by believing
what does that mean
today in your life
and mine
today 446 years later
doesn't it mean this
that when we say
I want to know
the unvarnished truth
what is the way to heaven
and the word of God
is here
and it's by grace
through faith
by trusting
doesn't it mean
that we've got the answer
to hopelessness
is there any reason
for any man ever
to be hopeless
although hopeless
is the world
here's Winston Churchill's
daughter
commits suicide
you wonder
what's so hopeless
in life
we think of Judas
taking his own life
what's so hopeless
what is this thing
but again
when we understand
that the way
is not by our life
but it is
by trusting in Jesus
think what that means
that means
there is no hopelessness
you and I
can't sin
so greatly
but what again
if we trust Jesus
there is eternal life
I don't care
what we have done
it matters not
what sins
have been charged
against us
it matters not
how far
we have gone away
there is only
one sin
that can condemn us
and that sin
is refusing
to trust Jesus
that's all
the unpardonable sin
is nothing
but the sin
that says
I don't want
to be saved
to trust you Jesus
I don't care
what you have done
or what I have done
it's never hopeless
the only thing
that can prevent
your salvation
and mine
is by refusing
to put our trust
in Christ
as our personal Lord
that's what
Luther announced
it wasn't new
God knows
it was the gospel
it was the good news
it was hope
for the world
no wonder
it shook the world
to its very foundations
oh I stood
in Worms Germany
we were there
one warm day
in July
we were the only
two my wife and I
and we had a guide
with us all day
a young lady
a Lutheran
who knew the history
and I stood
in Worms
at the place
where Luther had stood
when he gave a defense
of that new way
of salvation
which wasn't new
at all
and then again
into the Lutheran church
the Luther Kirche
there in Germany
and Worms
and went in
and emblazoned
on the walls
are the three articles
of the Apostles' Creed
and the matchless explanations
that Luther has written
remember you memorized them
remember especially
the explanation
of the second article
and it's written there
in the church in German
I believe that Jesus Christ
true God
begotten of the Father
from eternity
and also true man
born of the Virgin Mary
is my Lord
who has redeemed me
a lost and condemned creature
purchased and won me
from all sin
from death
and from the power
of the devil
not with gold or silver
but with his holy precious blood
and with his innocence
suffering and death
that I may be his own
and live under him
in his kingdom
and serve him
in everlasting righteousness
innocence and blessedness
even as he is risen
from the dead
lives and reigns
to all eternity
this is most certainly true
do you remember it
written emblazoned
on the walls of the church
and then there was
the Luther Platz
again the Luther Park
where Luther stands
a large monument
with the reformers
with a bible in his hand
with the words inscribed
here
stay
I stand
I cannot do otherwise
God
help me
what does it mean
to you and me
listen
it means this
it means that
salvation
is open
bought
and paid for
and ready
for you
and me
right now
not five minutes
from now
right now
this is the moment
in your life
and mine
I don't care who you are
I don't care if you've been
guilty of murder
I don't care if you've murdered
ten unborn children
I don't care what adultery
has beset you
I don't care how many things
you've done
that you can't undo
I don't care how many things
stand
and they stand
just history
and they haunt you
but I know this
just as certainly
there's a God in heaven
in this moment
right now
there is life
and salvation
for you
because it's by grace
it's been bought
and paid for
Jesus bore hell
for all of those things
before you were born
and he says
if you trust me
right now
if you can turn
and say to him
I'm a sinner
but I trust you
right now
oh you don't have
to make up anything
tomorrow
and you can do that later
but right now
this is the moment
in your life
pass me not
oh gentle Savior
hear my humble cry
while on others
thou art calling
do not pass me by
Savior
hear my humble cry
while on others
thou art calling
do not pass me by
can you say that
you can say it
in your pew
or where I'm standing here
wherever you are
on the radio
you can say
don't pass me by
I trust you
as my Lord
you can stand
right now
saved
forgiven
one of God's children
that's what the
reformation meant
and when Martin Luther
was ready to die
that's what his
faith and his
trust were
it was peace
because he had
announced a new
way
but it wasn't
new at all
it was the
same old way
that God
had revealed
in the scriptures
may God grant
you and me
in this moment
peace in Jesus Christ
amen
the peace of God
which passeth all
human understanding
keep and unites
your hearts and minds
in Christ Jesus
unto life everlasting
him
you
For God so loved the world
that he gave his only begotten Son
that whosoever believeth in him
should not perish
but have everlasting life.