grace be unto you and peace from god our father ran from the lord jesus christ amen let us hear
the word of god our regular epistolary lesson for this sunday as we find a written in paul's
letter to the philippians in the third chapter especially the 20th verse for our citizenship
is in heaven and now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts
be acceptable in thy sight oh lord our strength and our redeemer amen
in christ jesus our lord and savior dear friends you who are here in god's house this morning
and you also christian fans who are worshiping with us by means of the radio last sunday you
recall our text was taken from paul's letter to the philippians and today it is also taken from that
same letter it was while paul was on his second missionary journey you remember that he went over
into macedonia up into the city of philippi and there to establish the first christian congregation
on the continent of europe paul always loved that congregation dearly so that years later when he
was a prisoner in rome he wrote a letter to that congregation and we know it as the letter to the
philippian congregation and in our text this morning paul is telling the philippian christians
what their high position is as christians he is telling them what an exalted position is theirs
because they are children of god what a high enviable position it is and then he tells them just what
that position that status is since they are christians he said our citizenship is in heaven
in other words he says philippian christians because you are christians this is your high position you are
no less than citizens of heaven you are not citizens of earth you are not citizens of this world you are
no less than citizens of the heavenly country and the saint paul speaks to you and me this morning through
the word of god reminding us that as christians this is our high status it is our incomparable position
that we are no less than citizens of heaven citizens of the heavenly kingdom not citizens of the earth
and sometimes i suppose in your life and mine it's true a statements like that leave us cold do they not
we say to ourselves all right so i am a citizen of heaven i am not a citizen of earth what about it
is that such an exalted position after all and in your life and mine there are times are there not when
we say to ourselves well i don't know whether that is such an exalted enviable incomparable position
that i am a citizen of heaven we may say sometimes it seems like citizens of the earth citizens of this
world have the odds in their favor they have the advantages they seem to have the blessings
we do not seem to have the blessings and the advantages that citizens of this earth have
and then we begin to wonder do we not you know today is the second last sunday of the present church
year next sunday brings this church year to an end for we remember that the calendar year of course
begins on january the first but the church year does not begin at that time it begins the first sunday
in advent which happens to be the first sunday in december this year the church year ends next sunday
and as we think about the lengthening of days and as we think about our departure from this world
it is well that this morning we take a look at our position at our status and if this is such a mighty
position such a high calling that we are no less than citizens of heaven and not citizens of earth we
ought to look at it to see whether the odds the blessings the advantages are not on our side not
on the side of citizens of this world or of this earth on the basis of the word of god paul when he
wrote to the philippians he was filled with this joy we are no less he says but then citizens of heaven
we are not citizens of the earth and the advantages are ours if we just stop the thing for a moment
because in the first place let's know this being citizens of heaven because we are christians
that means this it means that we are friends of the cross of christ we are on the contrary not
enemies of the cross of christ as our citizens of this earth paul aptly describes what he means by
citizens of the earth or of this world he says there are many that walk and he told the philippians and
i've mentioned this to you before and he says now i mention it to you again with tears that he says
they are the enemies of the cross of christ who is a citizen of this world not a citizen of heaven
any man who is an enemy of the cross of christ you know those are words that you've got to look at
twice you notice paul does not say by inspiration they are enemies of christ he says they are enemies of
the cross of christ there's a tremendous difference many a citizen of this earth of this world who is
not a citizen of heaven is not an enemy of christ oh many a citizen of this earth loves him he will
tell you that christ is the greatest teacher that ever lived he will point you to the sermon on the
mountain say isn't it wonderful look what he taught and then many a citizen of this earth will point to
christ and say what a marvelous example there is no greater example in all the world than christ and
they will thrill to him and say if you walk in the way which he gave as a pattern then that's all you
need they love him as a teacher and they love him as an example but they are enemies of the cross of
christ there is something about the cross that the citizen of this earth doesn't like he has no room
in his life for the cross why you say the cross of jesus means his death and therefore the man of the
world says as far as i'm concerned he didn't have to die on the cross all that you need is to have him
as a teacher and all that you need is to have him as an example and then follow him live like he lived
be good to your neighbor live a clean decent life a good moral life be honest be above reproach and
that's all you need for salvation you see he looks at the cross and he says that's slaughterhouse religion
that's the blood i do not want the blood but you see paul says he is an enemy of the cross of christ
why because look at jesus he did not come into this world to be primarily a teacher jesus christ didn't
come into this world to be primarily an example in which you and i are to follow him and walk he came
primarily and foremost to die and when a man looks at jesus and he denies the very reason why he came
he takes unto himself something that is secondary jesus christ came for the cross why because he knew
that who can bring a clean thing out of an unclean not one he knew that you and i if we follow him by
an example cannot save ourselves he knew that you and i could never be perfect that he is a perfect
example we can never attain to perfection and so that's why he god's son came out of the ivory palaces
and went to the cross to die because in that death he knew that he would have to atone for our guilt and
for our punishment that in his death and in his death alone salvation might be possible for the human race
a man who is a citizen of this earth is a man that may love christ but he's an enemy of the cross and
therefore we say where is there any advantage a child of god who is a citizen of heaven he is a friend of
the cross of christ because that's the center of what he believes it is the cross because he stands at
the foot of calvary and he confesses his sins and he knows that within himself there dwelleth no good
thing and he knows that only by the shed blood of jesus christ is there forgiveness life and salvation
and therefore when we are citizens of heaven listen the advantage is on our side the blessing is on our
side because ours is the advantage at the end of life of heaven and the man who is a citizen of this earth
his is hell there is a tremendous difference is there not without the cross
without jesus christ that died friend if all you can see in him that he was only a teacher
and that he was only example you are an enemy of the cross of christ and you are denying that which
is vital and that which is necessary and no man shall see heaven on the basis of following jesus as an
example it's the cross that stands paramount and that stands center in christian theology and that
must stand as a friend in your life and mine is there any difference between heaven and hell when jesus
talked about judas who lost his salvation he said it were better for that man that he had never been
born then he said one day for what shall it profit a man if he should gain the whole world and lose his own soul
if you had the whole world and you lost your soul and you lost the citizenship of heaven
jesus says you're the loser because there are no compensations
that's the loss for which nothing can make up for it it were better that you and i had never been born
it's strange isn't it in our lives when we are reminded we are citizens of heaven not this earth but
sometimes we still feel that the advantages the blessings again the real privileges the odds are all
on the side of the other person but there is a difference the difference is heaven with god eternally
or hell paul says again their end is destruction their end is perdition perdition again satan is the son
of perdition and eternity separated from the very presence of god's grace and god's mercy the advantages
the blessings are on our side what a noble position what an enabling place what an enviable stand and
status is ours we are citizens of heaven not of this earth and if this morning on the second last
sunday of the year is the day's length and we think about the end of time if you and i could take that
truth and write it onto our hearts never to forget it that this that we are citizens of heaven not of
this earth then we would watch into our life that no man under any circumstances will ever take away
from you and me the christ of the cross oh and all of the ecumenical movements that are going on and
they're fine bear this in mind there is one central truth that we dare not lose and that is the christ
that died when you take calvary away from jesus you've got nothing left he is vital on my trip recently when i
was in europe i was in geneva switzerland and we passed the place of the united nations assembly which
was in session and then we rode along and we came to a place of a rock and there was a plaque on the rock
that said this place marks the workplace where woodrow wilson's league of nations had its beginning
and they were they held their meetings in geneva switzerland and when you think that in world war
one eight million five hundred thousand young men of the nations of the world lost their lives in
world war one and our great president woodrow wilson said this shall not happen again and there was the
league of nations with his famous 14 points but woodrow wilson found out to his sorrow that the 14
points of the league of nations that the 13 000 minute points of international law could not prevent
another war and he himself wrote that if civilization is to stand man must be redeemed spiritually that's it
and when man is redeemed spiritually don't forget he is redeemed by the precious blood of jesus christ
there is no other way don't let it slip through your fingers and mine we have an exalted position
we are citizens of no less than heaven of the heavenly country not of this earth well that means that we
are friends of the cross of jesus christ if you can emblazon it on your soul and mind this morning that we'll
never forget that don't let anybody under any circumstances take from you and me the christ of
the cross paul put it this way i am not ashamed of the gospel of christ for it is the power of god and
to salvation to everyone that believes when he wrote to the philippians paul was reminding him look at our
exalted position he said philippians as christians this is your position this is your exalted place
this is your great status you are citizens of no less than heaven itself not citizens of earth
and therefore the advantages and the blessings and the odds are all on our side even though at times we
may wonder about them because in the second place let's know this that being citizens of heaven
means this that god is our god in contrast to those who are citizens of this earth whose god is their
belly paul says whose god is their belly who glory in their shame who mind earthly things what's he
talking about the man of the world the man who is not a citizen of heaven he has a god but it's not god
it is again his own belly or his own stomach or his own cravings within he has one aim in life and that
is to get all that he can of the material things of life because to him life consists only in the
abundance of the things which a man has and therefore you've got to get and you've got to have
if you are going to be happy he knows no god but his own cravings and he craves and he craves and he
goes on because he spends and absorbs all of his time in the things of this life because the man that is
a citizen of this earth is thoroughly convinced that the only joy and happiness that he shall find
will be in the material things of life how about citizens of heaven citizens of heaven have as their
god god himself and when you and i as christians have as our god god and not the cravings of our own
hearts for the material things of life then we allow god to remind us of the fact that we are not citizens of
this earth because we are transients we are pilgrims we're just passing through we're tourists we have
no abiding city here and god writes it on your soul and mine that we are just strangers and pilgrims and
therefore god warns you and me not to wrap ourselves too tightly around the things of this life because we
aren't going to be here very long we're just passing through we are only tourists we are not citizens
of the earth and when god almighty warns you and me that we are not to become so completely absorbed
into our life that these things shall overshadow him and that these things will dim god into our life and
blind us then we have this advantage the advantage of being citizens of heaven that we have peace with
god whether god blesses us with a lot of material things with very little and the man who is a citizen
of this life has no peace within even though he should own the world the man that lives as a citizen of
this life soon finds out that there is only a passing satisfaction in the material things of life
as soon as something is acquired the craving starts all over again with something more
and the man craves and he craves and then comes fear fear of losing what he's got and so he lives there
is no peace of mind because god made you and me that conscience that part within you and me that is the moral
stamina and the moral quality and that voice of god within us can never be satisfied by the material things
but when again our god is the true god and not our belly then we know this that god in pointing us to him
having him and jesus christ we have peace with god everything is all right we are saved it matters not
then whether god blesses us with abundance or not many a trial of god has been blessed with abundance
abraham was an extremely wealthy man isaac and jacob were extremely wealthy people david and solomon were
extremely wealthy joseph of arimathea was an extremely wealthy man nicodemus was a wealthy man
but again they knew that they were citizens of heaven and never were these things allowed to blot out god
the advantages are on our side because citizens of heaven have peace within and when there is
restlessness within which means that there is a soul without god in jesus christ
there is no peace there is no peace there is no happiness there is no contentment on this second last
sunday of the church year oh that god would write it on your soul and on mine that we are citizens of
heaven not citizens of this earth just pilgrims if we would write it there never to forget it then whenever
adversity comes in your life and mine we will gladly accept it and we will stop feeling sorry for ourselves
and becoming despondent why does god send adversity in your life and mine sparing none of us john milton put
it this way he said sweet are the uses of adversity which like a toad ugly and venomous hath yet a jewel beneath
her crown have you ever asked why does god send adversity in your life and mine we who are citizens of heaven
do you want to know one reason because god knows how weak you are and how weak i am and how easy it is
to become so absorbed in the things of this life i mean honestly i do not mean being crooked
i mean getting these things in an honest and an upright way but god knows that you and i can get so
absorbed in these things that somehow or other they choke out god and they blind god to us
then god because he loves you and me knows something's got to be done he isn't going to give
you and me up that easily and then he sends adversity why because god knows if there is anything
that will make you and me stop if we're getting too absorbed in these earthly things and say wait a
minute wait a minute i am so absorbed i am forgetting god but adversity will do it i talked to a man when he
was offered a job twenty five thousand dollars a year what a salary and what an increase for him and as we
spoke he said to me don't worry about that money he said you see god took my son when he took my son i
know i'm not going to wrap myself around the things of life why was it that one of you said when you had
your new home all built that you were afraid to move into it because you thought something might happen
isn't it strange if in your life and mine we are prone to be so absorbed in a good way with decent
material things that we might blind god out of our life that then adversity comes and we say wait a
minute god something's wrong that's when we ought to thank god and say thanks god that you've taught me
that i am a stranger and a pilgrim here and that i'm not a citizen of this earth but what do we do
sometimes we get the blues and we start feeling sorry for ourselves and we start down the road of
despondency what is despondency listen despondency means this that i'm a bit irked and put out at god
and i say god you oughtn't to treat me that way god that isn't right i'm hurt and therefore we get
the blues and we get depressed and we think god's got something against us when the very opposite is
true god's trying to get you and me to put him back where he belongs then we start down that horrible
tragic road of despondency i'm mentioning this because i've got it on my heart
not less than three people this last week have been to see me because they were despondent and
talking about taking their life and one of them said to me what's the difference
if i take my life i only hurt myself don't i what's the difference now we're talking about all of us
on this side of the jordan you who are alive and i'm alive what about this thing when i get depressed
and i get despondent because i'm a bit put out at god do i have the right to take my life because i
am going to hurt only myself do you know of any place in the word of god where because i'm feeling
sorry for myself that i've got a right to take my life you know of any place like that do you know
that any place where that would excuse it that doesn't excuse it does it the big thing is we may
say no man in his right mind would take his life god judges that not i and i would never step in where
god belongs but listen if you are deliberately planning right now is the time to do some thinking
over 200 000 in our country every year attempted over 30 000 completed may i ask you right now from
the bottom of my heart to yours do you know what you're doing right now are you accountable for your
life if you're on the road to despondency answer me do you know you're on the road
are you accountable do you know right from wrong right now oh not when the deed is done but where
are you now did you have sense enough to come to church or not to come to church are you have sense
enough now to listen or not listen do you know what you're doing do you have a knowledge of right
along listen to take one's life as a deliberate act and therefore it depends on this am i accountable
when i deliberately plan to take my life a man only hurts himself is that right why there's something
about taking my life that is different than if i take the life of somebody else if i took your life
there would still be time that i could repent that i could get right with god but you see when i take my
own life deliberately when i plan to do it just because i'm on the road that's despondency and i take
my own life don't you realize that then you and i stand before almighty god in death with our blood on
our own soul and there isn't any time for repentance when death takes place the word of god knows no place
after death for repentance you may say to me well can i repent ahead of time well listen the very
essence of repentance is this that if i'm sorry i won't do it you can't do it ahead of time that's
the tragedy i'm talking to you and to myself on this side of the jordan god's that judge when these
things take place not you and i doesn't a man hurt only himself but oh god what you and i can do to
ourselves write it on your soul this morning will you when you start walking down that damnable
horrible dark road of despondency for god's sake don't think that it's pleasing god say to yourself
god god i'm sorry that i'm irked at you and for god's sake turn around and come back and talk to yourself
could i say it any clearer i had to say it it's all in my heart there's too many of you
who are talking about this thing you don't want to live because you're feeling sorry for yourself
i'm at your service i'm at your service 24 hours out of the day you and i are citizens of heaven
don't walk that road don't go down that road and let somebody take the heavenly citizenship away
because we are despondent it's a bad road stay off don't ever get on it never
when paul wrote to the philippians he was writing with a thrill in his heart and he was reminding them
this is your high calling we are citizens of heaven think of it no less than citizens of heaven
not citizens of earth we're only pilgrims here and some of them wondered and began as you and i
wonder we said the obs the advances the blessings all seem on the other side but they aren't because
listen being citizens of heaven as christian means this that we are awaiting the return of jesus christ
paul put it this way he said our citizenship is in heaven from whence we look for the savior the
lord jesus christ who shall change our vile body that it may be fashioned like unto his glorious body
according to the working whereby he is able even should do all things unto himself
isn't that marvelous paul said listen we as christians we wait for his return the man of the world
the citizen of the earth isn't waiting for christ to come again he doesn't believe he's coming
but you and i know that before he died he said he died and he said after i die i will rise again he
arose and we know that he went up the slope of the mount of olives one day and i walked it and i was
there where again he blessed the eleven and he went to heaven the angel said he's coming back remember
that oh he's coming back he conquered the grave what's going to keep him from coming back he is coming
back and then when he comes back what is our advantage but when he comes he has told us this that our
bodies can go down in the graves and he will raise them up and we will put on a glorified body a body
like the son of god has no longer touched by sickness and disease and those who are only citizens of this
world will put on a corruptible body which will be a body for damnation there is a tremendous advantage
on our side when we stop to think and on this second last sunday of the church here when the
shadows begin to lengthen we begin to think about the end of time what we not then if we write it on
our souls god don't ever let me forget it i'm a citizen of heaven i'm only a stranger i'm only a
tourist i'm only a pilgrim i'm only passing through here i don't belong here and therefore don't let me
get so absorbed in the things of this life god that i block you out of my life oh then we ought
to be examples to one another and to encourage one another when sickness comes ought we not
what ought we to do as christians oh death's going to look for a cause isn't it you are going to die and
so am i and death's going to find some reason to choose me sickness and that sickness can take
multitudinous forms all the time may come in your body mind will start to slowly waste away and everybody can see it
but oh we can follow the example of paul can't we and we can go to one another and say all these
bodies of ours they can become so contaminated with sin and they can go down and oh they can be so
destroyed with all kinds of vermin and all kinds of diseases but oh when christ comes again we can say
but we're going to put on a new body it's going to be a changed body it's going to be a glorious glorified
body never again showing the signs of sickness and disease and then when we can encourage one
another doesn't it mean this that as the shadows lengthen if sickness has come to us especially
incurable illness we can thank god for it because you know god has a purpose in that that's the way
god makes us homesick doesn't he you know we can even be a tourist and we get so absorbed in the things
of life that we sometimes forget that we're citizens of heaven and we're going there and we
wonder well how will god get us to want to go and he sends sickness doesn't he then we get homesick
well there was abraham he left her of the chaldees remember and he came on over to the land of came
into a strange land and again through all the things of life and the trials that he had he became homesick
and we read about abraham and we are told that abraham he looked for a city which had foundations
the real eternal city whose builder and maker is god he got homesick he wanted to go home and when
sickness comes to your body and mine and we know that it's incurable something precious starts doesn't
we we get homesick we get along for the homeland we get along so the fulfillment of our citizenship
i had a birthday last week and of course i missed the card that i usually got from my sister and when
i thought of her again it always came a day late always late with a card or a birthday card but i saw her
body waste away just wasting away and draining away and i saw a heavenly homesickness there longing to go
home longing to be with her lord and you know this thing of sickness it's god's way of telling you and
me child i'm getting a bit homesick for you we waited in heaven a long time and now i've sent sickness
and soon i'll be calling for you we're anxiously awaiting your coming we're a bit homesick for you
the mansions are ready it's about time to come home well that's the advantage of being a citizen of
heaven isn't it well we can walk the glory road and when the illness takes our bodies we can look up
and say that i'm the citizen of heaven the homeland oh the homeland the land of souls free born
no gloomy night is known there but a the paid this morn i'm sighing for that country my heart is aching
oh to be at home in the homeland to be there with our christ that's the fulfillment of a homesickness
god grant that this morning you will write on your soul and i will write it on mine
what a lofty position you and i are no less than citizens of heaven the advantage
is on our side amen
the peace of god which passeth all human understanding keep and unite your hearts and minds
in christ jesus until life everlasting