Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the Word of God as we find it written in the Gospel according to St. Luke,
reading there in the first chapter from the 67th to the 79th verse as follows.
And his father Zacharias was filled with the Holy Ghost and prophesied, saying,
Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for he hath visited and redeemed his people,
and hath raised up an horn of salvation for us in the house of his servant David,
as he spake by the mouth of his holy prophets, which have been since the world began,
that we should be saved from our enemies and from the hand of all that hate us,
to perform the mercy promised to our fathers, and to remember his holy covenant,
the oath which he swore to our father Abraham, that he would grant unto us,
that we being delivered out of the hand of our enemies might serve him without fear,
in holiness and righteousness before him all the days of our life.
And thou, child, shalt be called the prophet of the highest,
for thou shalt go before the face of the Lord to prepare his ways,
to give knowledge of salvation unto his people by the remission of their sins,
through the tender mercy of our God, whereby the dayspring from on high hath visited us,
to give light to them that sit in darkness and in the shadow of death,
to guide our feet into the way of peace.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, our great Advent King, dear friends,
you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us this day by means of the radio.
Today is the first Sunday in Advent.
It also is the day that ushers in a new church year.
Now the word Advent means the coming,
and it refers to Jesus as the coming one,
the one who is going to come again.
The Advent season includes the four Sundays before Christmas,
and it has as its purpose to get us ready for a proper celebration of the birthday of Jesus.
And this morning, on this first Sunday in Advent,
as we look forward to the birth of Jesus Christ,
we would get ourselves ready by asking Zacharias,
a priest of God, the father of John the Baptist,
just who this Jesus, who was born in Bethlehem, really was.
The occasion for the expression from Zacharias
was the time when John was just eight days old.
It was the time when the family and friends gathered together
to circumcise the child, giving him the sign of the covenant,
and to give him a name.
Now all the relatives and friends thought surely that this child was going to be called Zacharias.
Zacharias after its father.
And they turned to Elizabeth, the mother, and they asked her,
and she said,
No, we are not going to call him Zacharias.
We are going to call him John.
And they said,
But nobody else in the family has the name John.
Why do you want to call him John?
And then they turned to Zacharias.
Now Zacharias had not spoken a word for nine months,
not since the time that the angel had come,
and had said that his wife Elizabeth and he would become parents of a child.
And they motioned to him,
What shall we call this child?
And he motioned then for a tablet,
and he wrote on a tablet,
His name shall be called John.
And then it was that his speech was regained,
and he was able to talk,
and we are told that he, being filled with the Holy Ghost,
began to prophesy.
And he began to talk about his son,
and also about the birth of Jesus,
even though Jesus was not as yet born in Bethlehem.
It was still six months before the birth of Jesus.
But in prophecy,
Zacharias sees it as something already having happened,
and this is what he said.
Oh, there were a number of times
when Zacharias, early in the morning from the temple,
would look out,
and he would see the dawn of a new day,
see the beginning of a new day.
And so when he thought of this Jesus that was going to come,
he said this about him,
He is the day spring from on high.
The day spring from on high hath visited us.
He is the spring of day.
He is the beginning of a new day.
He is the dawn of a new day.
That's who this infant Jesus is.
And today, as Zacharias speaks to you and me
from the word of God,
and we ask him,
Zacharias, who is this Jesus,
the manger child of Bethlehem?
Zacharias says,
Do you not know who he is?
He is the day spring from heaven.
He is the dawn of a new day.
He is the new day of hope
and comfort and joy for the world.
He is the one whose coming
has meant a new day of hope in this world.
That's who he is.
And you and I on this first Sunday in Advent
getting ready for Christmas,
we may say,
Isn't that a bit of an exaggeration?
That Jesus is the new day from heaven?
That his coming has brought a new day into this world
that would never have happened had he not come?
Isn't that stretching it just a little bit too far?
Isn't that an overstatement?
And yet on the basis of the word of God today
as we get ready for Christmas,
is let's know this,
that when Zacharias likened Jesus
to the dawn of a new day,
he is the new day that has come from heaven,
that is no exaggeration,
that is no stretching of truth,
because just as surely as God lives,
let's know this,
that Jesus,
by his coming from heaven,
he brought a new day of hope to this world
that this world would never have had
had Jesus not come.
There is no exaggeration,
there is no stretching here whatsoever.
Let's look on this first Sunday then
at what Zacharias tells us about
this manger child of Bethlehem.
He is the day spring from heaven.
He's the dawn of a new day.
He is a new day of hope for this world.
And he is because had he not come,
there would never have been
a new day of hope for this world.
Because in the first place,
let's know this on the basis of the word of God,
that Jesus,
the day spring from heaven,
the new day from heaven,
he came to bring light to them
that sit in darkness
and in the shadow of death.
Do you realize that if Christ
had not come into this world,
there would be no light
to men in darkness,
to men who are sitting
in the shadow of death?
What do you mean by light in darkness?
What do you mean by death?
Had Christ not come,
no man would know
his true spiritual condition.
But you may say,
but we still had the Old Testament,
did we not?
And do we not have the New Testament?
So would it have made much difference
if Christ did not come?
But the thing that you and I
must bear in mind this morning is this.
Had Jesus Christ not come,
there would not have been an Old Testament.
There would never have been a New Testament.
The Old Testament testifies of Christ.
And therefore,
had Jesus not planned on coming,
God would never have given us
the Old Testament covenant.
You and I wouldn't have it.
And because Christ came,
and that means because we have
the Word of God
which testifies about him,
therefore you and I know this,
that we would never know otherwise
if he had not come.
We know that we are sinners
in the sight of God.
We know that we are lost sinners
We know that we are condemned sinners
in the sight of God.
We know that we are lost in sin.
We know therefore that a just God
looks at you and me
and condemns us because of his justice.
That we would never know
had Christ not come into the world
to give us light
because you and I sit in darkness
and we sit in the very shadow of death,
yes, eternal death,
and eternal hell.
And thus because he is the new day,
he is the day spring from on high,
he is the one who has brought
deliverance from hell
for this world.
You can't exaggerate
what the coming of Jesus Christ
has meant into this world.
No Christ,
there would be no deliverance
from eternal death and hell
for any man
because no man can be his own savior
who can bring a clean thing
out of an unclean,
not one.
And so there was no exaggeration
when Zacharias, the priest of God,
in prophecy,
looking at this child
who was yet unborn,
said of him,
why he's the dawn of a new day.
He is the day spring from heaven.
He is the beginning of something new.
He is the one who has brought
a new day of hope to the world.
Without Jesus Christ,
no man would know the way of salvation.
no man would be delivered
from eternal death
in hell,
both body and soul.
And that's why on this first Sunday
in Advent,
when we're getting ready for Christmas
and we're asking ourselves,
well, whose birthday
are we really celebrating?
Who is this, Jesus?
We ought to say to ourselves,
well,
Zacharias tells us
that he is the new day from heaven.
He is the dawn of a new day.
He is the one
that has brought a day of hope
to this world
that the world would never have
had he not come.
And we ought to write that
onto our hearts this morning.
And if you and I would do that
as we're getting ready for Christmas,
then we would begin
to give him credit also
because he has come
for the byproducts
that this world enjoys.
Because the coming of Jesus Christ.
How many of us stand
and give Christ credit
for the byproducts of his coming,
the new day in the world?
All that you have to do
is stand someday
in a nation
where the spirit
of Jesus Christ
doesn't rule.
And let me tell you
when you are in such a nation
that seemingly is untouched
by the spirit
of Christ's coming,
it will write
an indelible mark
on your soul
that you'll never forget.
And you'll say to yourself,
I never realize
what Christ's coming
has really meant
in this world.
You and I talk glibly
about a democracy.
Demos meaning people
and crosses power,
power in the hands
of the people.
Do you realize
that a democratic way
of life,
liberty of the individual
is a byproduct
of the coming
of Jesus Christ
into this world?
When Jesus came
and testified
that all men
stand equal
in the sight of God,
that all men
are precious,
if all men
are free
in the sight of God,
then all men
shall be free
among themselves.
it came
from Christ.
Stand in a nation
where man
doesn't have
his freedom.
And I'll show you
a nation
that has repudiated
Jesus Christ.
Another thing,
go into some
of these nations
where the spirit
of Christ
is not predominant
and see if you
find mercy.
I have seen
under Muslimism
widows who have
been disowned
by their husbands
standing with babes
and infants
in their hands,
crying and screaming
at the top
of their voice
for a piece
of bread.
I never saw
such poverty.
I have never
seen such a lack
of mercy.
It'll haunt me
for the rest
of my life.
Where did mercy
come from
in this world?
How does it come
we've got hospitals?
that we take care
of our children,
crippled children,
retired children?
Why?
Because Christ
as a byproduct
brought mercy
into this world.
Go into the nations
untouched by Christ
and go back
before his coming
and children
that were born
without perfect bodies
or minds
were given to the animals,
the wolves,
to eat up.
You women,
had Jesus Christ
not come into this world
in India
under Hinduism,
it would be better
that you had been born
a cow
rather than a female
because in Hinduism
cows are more sacred
than females.
You look in this world
and we say
the byproducts
of Christ's coming,
the very fact
that we can enjoy
again for our children
and education,
the very fact
that we have learned
mercy,
some of it,
those are the byproducts
of his coming.
Why don't we give him credit?
I wonder
how many within
the sound of my voice
may have this happen
to them.
Oh, you may never
have embraced
Jesus Christ
as your Lord and Savior,
but I wonder
if someday
when you stand
before him
that he will turn
to you and say
and you weren't
even a gentleman
enough
to even say
thanks for my
byproducts.
You accepted them
and you never
said a good word
for me
because you were
so selfish
and you took
them for granted.
Depart from me
I will spew thee
out of my mouth.
I don't care
who you are,
friend.
If you're going
to be honest
and decent,
at least tell him
thank you
for the byproducts
that you're enjoying
in this country
even if you repudiate
him as Lord
and Savior.
It's only the decent
gentlemanly thing
to do.
Getting ready
for Christmas
and we say
what did his coming do?
Was that coming
so pretentious
and so marvelous
that had he not
come this world
would be poorer?
Zacharias
when he in prophecy
began to speak
of that infant Jesus
he said
why he's the day
spring from on high.
He's the dawn
of a new day
in this world.
He is the spring
of a new day,
the beginning
of something new,
the dawn
of a new day
of hope.
That's what he is.
When you and I
look and that's
no exaggeration.
Listen,
if Jesus Christ
had not come
we would still
be in darkness
and in the shadow
of death
without hope
and we'd not
know the answer.
There would be
no deliverance
but in the second
place let's know
this,
that because Christ
who is the day
spring from heaven,
who is the new
day from heaven
because he came,
he came in order
to be Israel's
horn of salvation.
what did Zacharias
think about
this Jesus
of Nazareth?
Oh, he knew him.
Elizabeth had been
at their home.
She had, again,
and they had talked
these things over
and the angel
had also announced
these things to Mary
up in Nazareth
and Mary had come
down into this country
down in Judea
in the hill country,
probably Hebron
and she had been
visiting with her
cousin Elizabeth.
Zacharias knew
the story.
He knew that
Jesus was coming
from Mary
and he knew
who this Jesus
really was.
He calls him
what?
He says,
and God hath
raised up
an horn of salvation
in the house
of his servant
David.
Let's ask
Zacharias this morning,
was Jesus
who was born
in Bethlehem,
was he the
Jewish Messiah?
Was he the
Christ who was
to come?
and Zacharias
with every power
that was his
empowered by the
Holy Spirit
would say
that Jesus
was the Messiah
that was promised
in the Old Testament
that the prophets
of God
had talked of
since the beginning
of the world.
He was the horn
of salvation
that came from
the house of David.
He was the fulfillment
of the prophecy
that was given
to Abraham.
Oh, my Jewish friends,
listen.
Jesus
who was born
at Christmas
is your Messiah.
He is your Christ
beyond the shadow
of a doubt.
Had he not come,
there would never
have been
and there never
will be
another Messiah.
He is the
one
and only
genuine
Messiah
of all Israel.
Zacharias
said,
he's the horn
of salvation,
horn,
the symbol
of the horn
of the bull
which is the power
and therefore
a powerful one
this new day
from heaven
powerful enough
to be the Messiah
to bring salvation
to Israel.
Oh, his coming
has meant this,
that because
he is Israel's
horn of salvation,
therefore that
blessing of salvation
that he came
to bring
is retroactive
and it goes
back to the very
time when the
world began.
Zacharias
said the prophets
were telling
of him
this great
day spring
from heaven,
this great
new day,
this beginning
of a new day,
this new day
of hope
that is coming,
the prophets
told about him
which means
that it was
such a wonderful
salvation
that he brought
that even
from the time
of Adam and Eve
as they looked
forward to his
coming in faith
and every lamb
that was slaughtered
in the temple
at Jerusalem,
when men
slaughtered them,
they looked
forward in faith
to the coming
horn of salvation
which is Jesus
Christ,
the day spring
from on high.
Oh, he brought
salvation and it
was retroactive
in history to the
beginning of time
and it goes on
to the end of time.
We're getting ready
for Christmas,
aren't we?
When we say to
ourselves,
who is this Jesus,
this manger child
of Bethlehem?
Why, Zacharias,
again, who was
the father of John
says, don't you
know who he is?
Why, he's the dawn
of a new day.
He's the one that
has brought a new
day into this world
that had he not
come, there would
never have been a
day like he has
brought.
There would never
have been hope.
have been comfort.
There would never
have been consolation
and joy like he
has brought.
He's the day spring
from on high.
Getting ready for
Christmas over this
morning, we could
just, again,
write that on our
souls as we're
looking to Christmas.
Then again, we
would put into
God's hands the
thing that sometimes
vexes us and that
says, what about
those who have
lived and died
without ever
having heard about
Jesus Christ, the
horn of salvation?
What about those
in the Old Testament
who never heard
about Jesus?
What about those
in our time who
live and die and
never hear about
him?
What the answer
to that is?
What we put that
into the hands of
God, that's God's
business, but you
know, we like to
deal with that because
somehow or other we
like to get
comfort.
We like to say,
well, God surely
will never condemn
anybody who has
lived and died and
never heard about
Christ.
God will never
condemn him.
And then we get
behind it and then
we say, well, God
isn't going to
condemn me either
whether I accept
him or not.
If he's not going
to condemn them,
he isn't going
to condemn me.
You see, it's sort
of a shelter, it's
sort of a blanket
that we try to put
over ourselves to
keep us from
reckoning with
Jesus Christ.
What God will do
with those who
have lived and
died without ever
heard about Jesus,
that's God's
business.
But you and I,
as we know who
he is, that he is
the new day from
heaven, we ought to
spend this Advent
season in telling
others what Christmas
really means.
How many know
what it means?
How many understand
what Christmas
really means on
the basis of the
word of God, that
it's the birthday
of the great
day spring from
heaven, the
birthday of a
new day, of he
who came into
this world, who
brought a new
day of hope to
this world that
the world would
never have.
Why, when
Zacharias was
prophesying that
then he looked at
his son, eight
days old, and
he called him
John, and then
he said, and
thou, child, shall
be the prophet of
the highest, or
you're going to
be the prophet of
the highest, the
great one that is
going to come, and
you're going to
prepare the people
before his face,
before the face of
the Lord.
John the Baptist
went out and he
told others about
this Jesus, this
great day spring
from on high.
What greater
occasion do you
and I have than
to put that
Christ into
Christmas, to let
others know just
what is happening,
what we are going
to celebrate, the
birthday of the
great new day from
heaven, the one
that came as the
great horn of
salvation for
Israel.
We say to
ourselves, was
Zacharias saying
too much?
Was it exaggerated?
Was it stretched
just a little bit
too tight?
Was it an
overstatement?
And oh God, it
wasn't.
Zacharias in
prophecy and thinking
about that child
that was going to
be born?
Oh, he says,
because of the
mercy of God, the
day spring from on
high has come, the
new day, the
spring of a new
day, the dawn of
a new day, he
who's coming has
meant a new day of
hope for the
world.
That is no
exaggeration because
had Jesus not
come, there would
never have been a
day of hope for
this world because
in the third place
we know this, that
this Christ, who
is the day spring
from on high, he
came in order to
guide our feet into
the way of peace.
Had Jesus Christ
not come, there
would not be a
human being on
the face of the
earth right now
that would know
how to come to
peace with God.
We'd all be
guessing because
had Christ not
come, there would
be no scriptures.
They testify of
Jesus, no Christ,
no scriptures.
How does a man
come to peace
with God?
How many in
church this
morning who are
listening know
nothing about peace
within turmoil and
unrest?
You're wondering
whether life is
even worth living
because you don't
know how to
come to peace
with God, that
everything between
God and you is
just the way it
ought to be.
Jesus came to
guide our feet in
the way of peace.
He came to tell
us that you stand
before God and you
tell God you're a
sinner and you tell
God you're sorry.
That isn't hard,
is it?
God, I'm sorry
that I'm a sinner
and I deserve to be
banished from you
eternally.
And then Jesus
has taught us
that we turn and
we ask God for
forgiveness for
Jesus' sake.
We say, God,
forgive me the
guilt and the
punishment of my
sins, not on the
basis of anything
that I have done,
but for Jesus' sake
who died on the
cross for me.
That isn't hard,
is it?
And on the basis
of Jesus Christ,
God forgives you
your sins and me
mine.
And when sin is
forgiven and God
has canceled the
guilt and the
punishment of our
sins, then we
have God's peace.
Oh, we may not
feel it at all
times, but we
have it and then
we go out and
we live that
life in righteousness
that we are
capable of doing
to his honor and
glory because
everything is just
right between
God and us.
Does peace mean
anything?
Without peace,
nothing means
anything in this
world, does it?
In a world of
unrest, a world of
restlessness, Jesus,
he is the one who
brought a new day
in this world
because his coming
has meant this,
that he has brought
eternal rest for
all men.
And that eternal
rest is heaven,
that you and I,
body and soul,
may spend an
eternity with God
in his home.
Had Christ not
come, no man
born of woman
in this world
would ever have
the eternal peace
of God.
Yes, believe you
me, you can't
exaggerate his
coming.
And because we
can't and he's the
day spring from
heaven, he's the
new day, the dawn
of a new day, the
dawn of a day of
hope, the dawn of
a day of comfort
and consolation, as
we're getting ready
for Christmas and
this is the first
Sunday in Advent
and we look again
into the manger and
we say, who is this
Jesus?
Zachariah says, he's
the new day from
heaven.
Ought we not
therefore just take
time this morning
to look and to
probe into our own
hearts and homes,
is that Christ, is
that new day in
your home and in
my home?
You know, Zachariah
has had to learn a
lesson too.
For nine months he
was not able to
talk.
Why?
Because when
Gabriel, the angel
came to him and
told him that his
wife Elizabeth was
going to be the
mother of a child,
he wouldn't believe
Gabriel.
So he had nine
months to think it
over.
He rebelled and he
couldn't talk until
John was eight days
old and then his
speech came back.
Then he knew what it
meant to believe the
promises of God.
How about in your
house and mine today?
You know, coming into
my office so often,
husbands and wives,
fathers and mothers
coming with their
marital problems and
you get something like
this.
So often a wife says,
well, it's just like
this.
I no longer love my
husband.
Or the husband comes
in and says, I hate to
be brutally frank, but
I'm going to tell you, I
no longer love my
wife.
It's all gone.
And then you see the
ideas, well, when you
no longer love your
mate, why then you
got to do something
about it.
You have the right to
do what you want to do
about it.
You just break it up.
And of course you
don't care about the
kids there.
They don't count
anyhow, you see, the
big thing is the
great ego, the
great eye.
I don't know what
they mean by love.
Oh, I can get a good
idea that love is
gone.
They no longer
thrill when the
mate walks in.
Or sexual desire has
somehow or other
been abated.
And because that
doesn't seem to be so
paramount, love is
gone.
But I like to tell
them that if you'd
put into that home a
different love, if
you'd put into that
home the new day, the
day spring, there is
a love that comes
from obedience that
you can control.
And that love is to
love husband or wife
to the point that you
want them saved.
When husband and
wife love one
another, they say it
matters not this
earthly thing that we
may call love, but
we're going to treat
one another in such a
way that we're going
to make the heaven
journey a little
easier, then there's
a new day in that
home.
I know a little boy
about six or seven
years of age.
Mother was combing
his hair one morning
and he looked up at
her with the love
that a kid has for
his mother and he
said, Mother, when I
grow up, I'm going
to be a good boy.
I'm not going to be
like Daddy.
Am I, Mother?
Just like the
twinkling of an eye,
she reached up and
she cracked him
across the face
with her hands and
she said, Don't
talk about your
father like that.
He looked up at
her with tears in
his eyes, amazed and
wondered what had
happened.
He thought he had
said what she would
want him to say and
what would delight
her.
But there was a
mother that was
poisoning that little
boy every day about
his daddy, but when
the thing was
reversed and she
heard the little
boy repeating what
she had said, then
she saw how foul it
was and she cracked
him.
But she was the
mother that should
have stood and
cracked her own
face because she
was the poison.
How about your
home and
mom?
Is it nothing but
poison from one to
the other?
And you're
wondering why the
children repeat it
and it sounds so
terrible when they
tell you about it.
What kind of a
Christmas are you
going to have?
Zacharias early in
the morning would go
out and he'd watch
the dawn of a new
day.
When he saw it, he
likened Jesus to the
dawn of a new day.
You can put a new
day if you put
Christ into your
home.
Did you ever go out
into the garden early
in the morning by
yourself?
Did you ever watch
the dawn of a new
day?
Did you ever stand
there and when you
saw the dawn of a
day, did you ever
say there's the day
spring?
There's the dawn of a
new day.
There's the beginning
of another day and
Zacharias, he said
that's what Jesus
is.
And if you put that
new day into your
home, oh, what a
difference.
Can't you stand in
the garden some
morning and sing
from your very soul,
I come to the
garden alone while
the dew is still on
the roses and the
voice I hear falling
on my ear, the
Son of God
discloses, and he
walks with me and
he talks with me and
he tells me I am his
own, and the joy we
share as we tarry
there, none other
has ever known.
Oh, we're getting
ready for Christmas,
friends.
Look into the manger,
who is he?
He's the new day from
heaven, go out into
the garden and see
the dawn of a new
day, and put the
new day Jesus Christ
into your home, and
then I promise you,
it can't fail.
Yours is going to be a
very merry Christmas.
Amen.
The peace of God, which
passeth all human
understanding, keep and
unite your hearts and
minds in Christ Jesus
unto life everlasting.
Amen.