It be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written in the gospel according to St. John.
Reading there in the 21st chapter, from the 15th to the 19th verse as follows.
So when they had dined, Jesus saith to Simon Peter, Simon son of Jonas, lovest thou me more than these?
He saith unto him, Yea, Lord, thou knowest that I love thee.
He saith unto him, Feed my lambs.
He saith to him again the second time, Simon son of Jonas, lovest thou me?
He saith unto him, Yea, Lord, thou knowest that I love thee.
He saith unto him, Feed my sheep.
He saith unto him the third time, Simon son of Jonas, lovest thou me?
Peter was grieved because he saith unto him the third time, Lovest thou me?
And he saith unto him, Lord, thou knowest all things.
Thou knowest that I love thee.
Jesus saith unto him, Feed my sheep.
Verily, verily, I say unto thee, When thou wast young, thou girdest thyself, and walkest whither thou wouldst.
But when thou shalt be old, thou shalt stretch forth thy hands, and another shall gird thee, and carry thee whither thou wouldst not.
This spake he, signifying by what death he should glorify God.
And when he had spoken this, he saith unto him, Follow me.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer.
Amen.
In Christ Jesus, our risen Lord, dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also Christian fans who are worshipping with us by means of the radio.
Last Sunday, as all of us know, we celebrated Easter, did we not?
We celebrated that day that commemorated the anniversary of Christ rising again from the grave,
even as he said he would.
And you recall that last Sunday we looked at this risen Christ,
the one that came back from the grave as he had said that he would,
and we saw that he is really the indispensable Christ.
He is the Christ that you and I must have,
that having him we have everything,
and lacking him we lack everything.
Well, on Easter Sunday, Jesus made some appearances.
He appeared to Mary Magdalene, you remember.
He appeared to the women.
Then on Easter afternoon, he appeared to Peter in private.
Then came the appearances to the two men on the way to Emmaus.
And you recall, then on Easter Sunday night,
he appeared to the disciples behind locked doors,
and Thomas was not there.
On the following Sunday night, he again appeared to the disciples,
and Thomas was there.
Now, our text talks about the third appearance that Jesus made to the disciples.
The one was on Easter Sunday night.
The next was on the following Sunday night.
And this third appearance took place up on the shore of the Sea of Galilee.
It was not down in Jerusalem.
But in the meantime, the disciples had gone from Jerusalem.
They had traveled about a hundred miles,
and they were up at the Sea of Galilee.
If we were to guess, we would say it must have been about three weeks after Easter.
You recall that on the day of Christ's resurrection,
that the angel told the women to go and tell Peter and his disciples
that he will meet you in Galilee.
Evidently, Peter was anxious to get up into Galilee for this meeting with his Lord.
We are told that seven of the apostles were there.
Five of them are named.
We are told that Peter was there.
We are told that Thomas was there.
That Nathaniel, or Bartholomew, as we like to call him, was there.
James and John, and the other two are not named.
There were seven of them up in Galilee,
about a hundred miles away from Jerusalem,
about three weeks after the resurrection.
Then we are told that as they were there, it was evening,
and the apostle Peter said, I'm going fishing.
And the other men said, we're going along with you.
So they got into a boat.
They rode out into the Sea of Galilee, and they were fishing.
And they fished all night, and they didn't catch a thing.
And then as morning began to break,
these seven men in the boat noticed that there was a man standing on the shore,
but they could not see who it was.
But it was Jesus, the risen Lord, making an appearance to them,
but they didn't know it.
And as they looked, the man on the shore said,
men, have you caught any fish?
And they said, no.
And then the man said, throw your net on the right side of the boat.
Evidently, they had had the net on the left side,
and they took their net and put it on the right side.
And when they did, there was a miraculous draw to fishes.
They couldn't even draw the net up.
And then it was that John, the beloved disciple, said to Peter,
I know who that is on the shore.
That's the Lord.
And just as soon as he said it,
Peter put on the coat that he had taken off,
and he put the belt around his waist,
and he got into the water, and he started to go to the shore.
The rest followed.
They were not too far away.
We are told only about a thousand yards.
And as they walked up on the shore,
lo and behold, they saw some burning embers,
some burning coals,
and there was fish on the fire,
and there was bread.
And then as they brought again the fish to the shore,
Jesus says, bring me some of the fish that you have caught.
And that was put on the fire.
And we are told that not one of the seven would dare ask,
who is this speaking to us?
That they knew that it was the risen Christ.
And so on the shore of the Sea of Galilee,
early one morning,
about three weeks after Easter,
if we were to guess,
here there was breakfast with the risen Lord.
And then after they had eaten,
came the incident of our text.
Jesus turned to Simon Peter.
To understand this incident,
we must know this,
that when Jesus appeared to Simon Peter
on Easter Sunday afternoon,
while we are not told in the Word of God
what went on there,
you and I can very well assume what happened,
that it was then that Jesus forgave him
for his defection,
that he had denied him.
But there was still one thing that had to be settled.
Was Peter to be reinstated into the Apostolate?
Was he fit to continue to be a minister of Jesus Christ?
He was forgiven,
but would the other men accept him?
He who had so boldly denied his Lord
on the night of the betrayal.
That remained to be done.
And so you can well imagine
that Peter was very anxious
for this meeting in Galilee.
And there, besides the other six men,
Jesus turned to him and he said,
Simon, son of John,
lovest thou me more than these love me?
Oh, it brought back to Peter
what he had said in the upper room that night
when he had bragged about his love for Jesus
and he said the wall of them would forsake him.
He'd never forsake him.
And it was that night, remember,
that Jesus said,
you will deny me three times
before the rooster crows twice.
And Peter didn't believe it,
but he had gone out
and he had miserably denied
the ever known Jesus.
And so Jesus comes to him and said,
Simon, son of John,
do you love me more than these?
And he could only hold his head down
and look and he said,
yes, Lord, you know that I love you.
And then Jesus said to him,
Simon, feed my lambs.
Here came the word of reinstatement.
Here was the reinstatement of Peter.
Peter, I still want you
as one of my ministers.
I still want you
as one of my shepherds.
When he told him,
you go feed the lambs,
there was the signal
you are to continue
as one of the twelve,
that there would be no question.
And then he turned to him
the second time
and he said,
Simon, son of John,
do you love me?
Do you love me as your Lord?
Not more than these,
but do you love me?
And then again,
with his head down in humility,
Peter said,
yes, Lord,
you know that I love you.
And then Jesus said,
feed the sheep.
Feed my sheep.
And then the third time
Jesus turned to him
on the shore of Galilee that morning
and said,
Simon, son of John,
do you love me?
And it hurt him
and it grieved him so much
that Jesus would ask him
the same question three times.
And then he said,
Lord, you know all things,
you know that I love you.
And then Jesus came back
a third time,
feed my sheep.
The thing that we are interested in,
in those words of reinstatement
to Peter,
when Jesus assured him
that he was still one of the twelve
and that he wanted him
to be one of the twelve,
three times Jesus said to him,
feed, feed, feed.
In other words,
the word feed means to teach.
Teach the lambs,
teach the children,
the young people.
Feed the sheep,
feed the adults,
feed the sheep,
feed the flock.
That's the interest this morning.
Do you notice that
the risen Christ
had as his chief concern
when he reinstated Peter
that Peter should go out
and he should teach,
that he should instruct,
that he should nourish
in the word of God?
And as you and I
stand this morning
in spirit on the Sea of Galilee
and we hear those words
from the risen Jesus,
let us realize
that the chief
and the foremost
and the prime concern
in the living Christ
for ministers
is this,
for shepherds,
that they shall feed,
feed,
feed the flock,
that they shall teach
the flock.
You and I may say,
well,
this thing of teaching,
does it do any good?
You know,
sometimes we get
a miserable idea
about teaching
the word of God
because preaching
is just simply
teaching the word of God.
This thing of feeding
the flock,
feeding the lambs
and feeding the sheep,
we may say to ourselves,
what good does it do?
We may say,
oh,
it's nice to come
to church on Sunday
and to hear the minister
preaching the sheep,
but after all,
isn't it a frustrating thing?
Does it accomplish anything?
Are there any results
that come with teaching,
with feeding?
Evidently,
the risen Christ,
when he made it
the chief concern,
when he reinstated Peter,
evidently,
Jesus had the conviction
that it was
of prime importance
that the flock be fed,
that the flock be taught,
that young and old
be fed the word of God,
or he would not
have reinstated Peter
with those words.
We may put a low estimate
on teaching.
We may say
it doesn't do much good,
but today in God's house,
let's see,
if the risen Christ
made it of prime importance
that the flock be fed,
and that that be
the task of the shepherd
above all,
and the minister
and the ambassador
of Jesus Christ,
then we ought to say
to ourselves,
what good does it do
to teach the word of God?
Does it accomplish anything?
Oh, this low estimate,
is it love's labor's lost?
Does it mean that all shepherds
of Jesus Christ
are only frustrated individuals,
only there to entertain
and to amuse
and not to teach?
Does it do any good?
Well, in the first place,
let's realize this,
it must do a tremendous
amount of good,
because through the teaching
of the word of God,
the Holy Spirit brings us
to a conviction of sin.
Anybody within the sound
of my voice
have a conviction of sin?
Do you believe
that you are guilty
of having broken God's law?
Is there anyone
who stands in the conviction
that because he is guilty
of having broken God's law,
that he stands condemned
before the sight
of a just God?
Is there anyone
within the sound
of my voice
who says,
I deserve to be banished
from the presence
of a just God,
because I have deliberately
violated his law
and I have broken his word?
Would the God
that there are many of us
under a conviction of sin,
but where did it come from?
It came from being taught,
from being fed
the word of God.
Because there's something
about the word of God
that isn't true
about any other word,
Jesus one day
put it this way,
he said,
my word is spirit
and my word is life.
He meant by that,
my word is spirit,
the Holy Spirit works
through the word of God
and therefore even
those shepherds
who are sinners
shall bring it
and even though
the pastor shall
feed the flock,
nevertheless,
that word of God
has the Holy Spirit,
God himself,
the third person
of the Trinity,
who comes to man
through that word,
bringing man
to a conviction
of sin.
Were it not
for the teaching
of the word of God,
for it not
for the fact
that the very shepherd
shall feed the flock?
How many of us
would stand
with a conviction
of sin
and be filled
with sorrow
and thus,
how many of us
would also have
a crying need
within ourselves
to be delivered
from sin?
How many of us
this morning
can say with Paul,
oh wretched man
that I am
who shall deliver me
from the body
of this death
when we realize
how hopeless it is
to be our own savior
and that because
we are lost
and condemned
that we need help?
Where did that
craving come from?
Within you and me
that we shall
crave again
a way out
and have somebody
as a savior.
If you and I
can stand today
with a conviction
of sin
and we can stand
again realizing
what sin means
and that we are
hopeless and therefore
we must cry out
to be delivered,
bear in mind
it came from
teaching.
It came from
being instructed
in the word of God.
It came from
being fed
the word of God.
Without being
fed the word of God,
without the shepherd
feeding the flock
and feeding the lambs
and the sheep,
there would be
no one under conviction.
There would be
no one so crying out
to be delivered,
crying out for help
and for the savior.
And that's why today
as we stand again
on the shore
of the Sea of Galilee
and we hear the words
that Jesus the living
Christ spoke to Peter
in the presence
of the other disciples,
feed, feed, feed.
That was the chief
concern of the risen Christ.
Then ought it not
be the chief concern
of your life
and mine,
especially in our
homes?
Do you and I
love Jesus Christ
enough that we
say to ourselves
the prime purpose
in the home,
the real thing
that we must do,
we must feed
and above all
the lambs.
Do we love him?
Oh, it was a sad
experience for Peter
to be sure
when Jesus said
to him three times,
Simon, son of John,
do you love me
more than me?
Do you love me
as the Christ?
And when Peter answered,
he used another word
for love.
He said,
yes, Lord,
you know I like you.
He was even afraid
to say I love you.
And Jesus the second
time said,
do you love me
at all,
Simon Peter?
And Peter answered,
Lord, you know
that I like you.
And finally Jesus
said to him,
Simon Peter,
do you like me?
Do you just even
like me?
And that's when
he was grieved
and he said,
Lord, you know
all things.
You know I like you.
He never used
the Agapon word
for love once.
How many of us
love him enough
that we can say
to ourselves,
this is the
prime thing,
main thing
in our homes.
I was just reading
what J. Edgar
Hoover has to say
about 1964.
Oh, again,
not to excite us,
but he said
in 1964,
you can expect
this,
a 20% rise
this year
in forced
rapes
in our country.
Think of it,
20%.
He said,
you can expect
a great increase
in sexual crimes
in our country
this year.
And then he says,
you can also expect
a tremendous rise
in child molestations
by introverted
and sex-perverted
adults.
It isn't a very
nice picture,
is it?
But if the
risen Christ said,
this is the thing,
feed,
then you and I
love him enough
that we might
bring him into
our own homes
and stem the time
as regards
our children.
Oh, we put
such a low estimate,
do we not,
on this thing
of teaching.
And we say,
what good does it do?
oh, what are the results?
It doesn't do any good.
Oh, you may amuse
and it may entertain
and it may again edify,
but what good does it do?
But nevertheless,
when the risen Christ
reinstated Peter
into the apostolate,
he said,
feed,
feed the flock,
does it do any good?
It must,
because in the second place,
know this,
that through the teaching
of the word of God,
the Holy Spirit
brings us to a living faith
in Jesus Christ.
Anybody here in church
this morning
or on the radio
who has a living faith
in Jesus Christ,
anybody here who said,
he is my Lord
and my Savior,
that I put my trust
in him for the forgiveness
of sins,
that I know that in him
and his shed blood,
that I know that I am
a saved soul,
if so,
the word you get it.
Again,
you may say,
I got it when I was
baptized as a child,
but nevertheless,
you would have lost it
had you not been fed.
Somewhere along the line
you were fed,
somewhere along the line
you were taught,
you were instructed
the word of God.
And when ambassadors
and separate to Jesus Christ
are to rightly divide
the word of truth,
they not only preach the law
by which there is
the knowledge of sin,
but they preach
the glorious gospel,
the good news.
They tell the story
that again,
God's Son came out
of the ivory palaces
into this world of sin.
He was none other
than God the Son
from everlasting God himself
and born of the Virgin Mary
took unto himself
a human body
and a human soul
without sin.
And he as the God-man
went to Calvary's cross
and there on the cross
on Good Friday
he bore the guilt
and the punishment
of the world's sin
and on Easter
he raised himself
from the dead
assuring that God
had accepted his sacrifice
and that in him
and his shed blood
there is life
and salvation
for all men.
And when that word
is preached
even though by sinful shepherds
and the flock
is taught
the Holy Spirit
that works
through that word of God
brings men
to a living
trust in Jesus.
It is the gift
of the Holy Spirit
if you and I
have come to trust him
and therefore
it does do something
without the preaching
of the word of God
how shall they believe
in him
Paul says
of whom they haven't heard
and how shall they hear
without a preacher.
And that means
that when we have been
brought to a living faith
through the word of God
in Christ
as our Savior
that in him
we have the forgiveness
of sins
we are delivered
from hell
and eternal life
is ours.
We talk about
a saved soul
what do we mean?
A saved soul
is one that has
the peace of forgiveness.
He knows that in Christ
Jesus his sins
are forgiven
that God has blotted out
the memory of his sins
forever.
He knows that the peace
of God is his.
The terror of hell
is gone
because he knows
Christ bore the equal
of an eternity
in hell for him.
The joy of heaven
is his
because he knows
the righteousness
of Jesus Christ
that he earned
on the cross
is big enough
even to save him.
Yet isn't it strange
when we talk about
teaching
feeding
we say what good
does it do?
We put such a low
estimate on it
and yet
upon the very shore
of the sea of Galilee
when the risen Christ
reinstated Peter
the very prime
important thing
was this
Peter go out
and feed the flock
feed the lamb
feed the sheep.
And if that was
the great concern
of Jesus
ought it not be
your concern
and mine
in your home
while it is
still
possible.
how many
of us
cry out
today
and say
it seems
to be
too late?
How many
of us
say
what do you
do
when you've
got an
18 year old
daughter
that says
I won't
do what
you tell me
to do
I'm 18
and I'll
live my life
as I please
and I'll
do as I
please
and I will
act as I
please.
What do
you do?
you do
when you have
a son
that looks
at you
and says
I don't
care what
you say
I'm 18
I'm 21
I'll
live my
own life
I'll
do as I
please
and it's
none of
your business
what do
you do?
What do
Oh you
don't use
your fists
I would
warn you
and I
have
don't do
it
because
one father
thought that
was the
answer
and he
prided himself
in his
physical
ability
but when he
looked at
his son
he landed
under the
table
when he
woke
up
you better
watch out
bud
that son
may be a
lot stronger
than you
think
what do
you do?
Is it
beyond the
realm
that if
you and I
have failed
at home
and our
kids hate
us and we
hate them
is it
beyond the
realm of
Christian
possibility
to get
together
and to
apologize
ask for
forgiveness
think
think of
what
Peter
went
through
here
was
the
draught
of
fishes
that
morning
three years
ago
he was up
on the
same sea
and there
was a
miraculous
draught
of fishes
the net
break that
time and
Jesus said
I will make
you fishers
of men
that's when
he was
called to the
apostle
here again
another
miraculous
draught
and here
he was out
because he
had defected
the ranks
then he
walked up to
the shore
and here
again
were coals
burning
don't you
think
it reminded
him
that when
he was
in the
courtyard
of
Caiaphas
there were
coals
of fire
that he
had warmed
his hands
on the
night
when he
betrayed
was it
too late
and yet
Jesus
reinstated
him
I knew
a Columbus
policeman
very well
he was
as hard
as tax
he looked
like
Jack Dempsey
the
Manasseh
and he
was as
hard
as Jack
Dempsey
ever
thought
of him
he could
curse
like nobody
else
could curse
it was
again
to stand
it was
blasphemy
from one
end
to the
other
it was
a man
that never
got along
with his
son
the home
was a
hell
on earth
he had
the red
light
district
in Columbus
one of
them
and he
told me
as he
a story
that he
would walk
the beat
and at a
certain
time
during the
night
he met
the policeman
on the
adjoining
beat
and they
would talk
the other
policeman
happened
to be
a Christian
but the
policeman
that I'm
talking about
when the
other man
talked to him
about Christ
he laughed
and he
ridiculed
him
and he
thought
it was
the craziest
thing that
ever happened
followed it up
with cursings
and blasphemy
he was
hard
and then
there came
a scrape
one night
and his
buddy
policeman
was killed
then this
hard-hearted
policeman
began to
say to himself
who hasn't
I had been
killed
what about
me
what would
have
happened
then he
began to
think about
and he
went on
home
and he
had a
son
that hated
him
and the
wife
said what
kind of
a home
is this
but he
had the
courage
to sit
down
and to
say
I
failed
but we
can
start
and he
started to
go to
church
and he
came out
to the
seminary
and he
wanted to
take some
religious
courses
he used
to study
up in
my room
and one
day he
said to
me
Hansen
would you
come over
to my
house
Friday night
and have
supper
with us
and I
said I'd
be glad
to
and I'll
never forget
that meal
I sat
down
and looked
and he
said would
you ask
the blessing
and I
said yes
when I
was finished
he looked
at me
and he
says I
never
thought
the day
had ever
come
that anybody
would say
grace in
this house
and his
wife looked
at me
and the
boy
and they
said
you can't
imagine
what this
place was
like
this was
hell
now that
Christ has
come into
this home
when again
there were
three people
that had
learned to
love one
another
maybe it's
hell in
your house
sometimes we
wonder when
we come to
church we
wonder what's
wrong with
teaching
God forbid
that any
shepherd should
ever stand
in the pulpit
and not
teach and it's
a tremendous
job but let
me tell you
no shepherd
can do it
alone if
things aren't
right in your
house and
mine it
isn't going
to do much
good when
you come
here
teaching is
a tremendous
thing
it taxes
a man to
the nth
degree oh
if you've
never done
it you
don't know
this afternoon
if you want
to do
something take
fourteen sheets
of eight and a
half by eleven
paper and write
on the top
three words
feed feed
feed and
then sit
down and fill
fourteen pages
of what you
want to teach
on that and
don't repeat
the sermon let
it come from
you then when
you've got it
down be sure
it's up here
that you don't
have to read
it then you
may begin to
understand what
teaching means oh
it's more than
just edifying it's
more than making
people feel good it
is to tell them
something to
instruct them then
you begin to
understand what it
means sometime to
be up at two
thirty when you're
asleep or three
o'clock to write
down an idea before
it fails you then
you know what it
means to lose a
night's sleep to
teach it's
tremendous but no
teaching from any
shepherd is ever
going to do any
good unless things
are right in your
house and things
are right in mine
to depreciate and
to put a low
estimate on
preaching on
teaching let's
realize the
risen Christ when
he reinstated
Peter to the
apostle he said
feed feed feed
why because it
is of tremendous
importance does it
do any good oh
it's not only
because the holy
spirit works through
it brings men to
a conviction of
sin and to a need
of a savior it
not only brings us
to a living faith
in Christ and to
forgiveness life and
salvation but through
the word of God the
holy spirit causes you
and me to grow to
grow in our
Christian life today I
announce this quasi
modal genity Sunday
and you may say what
in the world does
quasi modal genity
mean well it's the
latin for something
that Peter had written
it means as newborn
babes this is the
apostle Peter Sunday
he wrote later think
of it the man that
was to go out and
feed who had been
reinstated he wrote
quasi modal genity
as newborn babes he
said to the
Christian desire long
for the milk of the
word be fed he said
that's why it's called
this Sunday because
we've got to grow
wouldn't it be
horrible if we didn't
grow physically yet
isn't it strange that
some of us think
nothing of it if we
do not grow spiritually
when the word of
God is taught and
when it is preached
and when it is
proclaimed and we
are fed the holy
spirit again causes
us to grow we grow
in the capacity of
understanding we grow
again in knowing what
is right and wrong
the conscience becomes
very very sharp that
we understand right
and wrong as we
never understood it
and it shows in your
life and mine because
we are walking with
him we have become more
christ-like and thus
again as we grow
through being fed the
word of God lambs and
sheep in the entire
flock we grow strong
against temptation so
that we can keep our
faith to the very day
of our death we've got
to have it on the day
of our death and the
temptations of life
come Jesus told Peter
Peter if you love me go
out and feed the lambs
feed the sheep feed the
flock get out and
teach does it do any
good it's the means
whereby the holy
spirit strengthens you
and me that we can be
faithful to the very
day when we shall stand
on the very day of our
death before our God
and if again the chief
concern of Jesus Christ
on that day up at the
sea of Galilee when he
reinstated Peter into the
apostolate if the chief
concern of that risen
Christ was this the
feed then again if that
is the chief concern of
our life and our home we
can look forward to
anything that may come
in life it was a rather
sad day up there as you
and I stand and listen
when Jesus had reinstated
him he looked at him and
he said Peter when you
were young he said you
girded yourself you
dressed yourself and you
went wherever you wanted
to go but he said Peter
when you become old Peter
was about 35 about that
time he said Peter when
you become old he said
you're going to reach out
your hands and another
is going to tie you and
another will take you
where you don't want to
go and John who was
writing these words he
wrote about the year
19 this had already
taken place John was
telling us Jesus said
this to indicate by what
way he should die and
glorify God you see Peter
died a martyr's death he
lived to see the day when
somebody did tie his
hands and they did lead
him where he didn't
want to go oh you
remember the story when
persecution had broken
out and tradition says
that Peter was fleeing
Rome going down the
Appian way friends had
told him to save his
life and as he was
fleeing the city of
Rome he saw somebody
coming again he didn't
quite recognize him
and as he came closer
he saw that it was the
Lord and he said to
him quo bodies
domine whither goest
thou Lord and Jesus
supposedly said to him
I'm going back to Rome
to be crucified again
and Peter this time he
didn't defect tradition
says he turned around
and walked back the
Appian way and came
into the city of Rome
and he was crucified
this time he said oh
don't crucify me like my
Lord with my head up
crucify me upside down
so they drove the nails
into his feet up and
his head down into his
arms and he was
crucified so tradition
says upside down for
his Lord the man that
was reinstated and the
man that went out and
he fed the flock and
he fed them and he
fed them when you and
I have been fed and
faith has grown it
matters not what shall
come we shall have
this joy that when
Christ shall return at
the end of time you
and I and our very
bodies will see him
face to face and he
will know us and we
shall know him I
think of old Job of
old when again Job
was able to say I
know that my Redeemer
liveth and that at
the latter day he
shall stand upon this
earth and though
after my skin worms
destroy this body yet
in my flesh shall I
see God and Job
said I know my
Redeemer lives and I
know my body when it
goes down to earth
will be eaten up by
worms but I know that
at the last day my
risen Lord's coming
again and he will
raise up my body from
the grave and I
know that in my body
I shall see him
when you and I
thank God have been
taught and we have
been trained and
instructed and
nourished then we can
look forward to the
worst that the world
can give but knowing
again that a faith is
grown and that the
Holy Spirit still
operates through the
word of God we can
stand and know that
when he comes again
what a joy will be
ours with our own
bodies raised from the
dead we shall see him
because we know that
our Redeemer lives
it's nice to stand
every once in a while
on the Sea of Galilee
and to see the risen
Christ as he reinstated
Peter who had
defected the ranks and
to know where he put
the emphasis he said
Peter go out and feed
feed feed feed the
lambs feed the
sheep feed the
flock God grant you
and me that we may
consider the prime
importance in our
home because it's
through being fed
that you and I know
him and that he
shall know us at the
latter day when we
shall stand before
him and oh God to
have him know us
amen
the peace of God
which passeth all
human understanding
keep and unites your
hearts and minds in
Christ Jesus unto
life everlasting