Peace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written in the Old Testament in the book of Esther,
the fourth chapter, the fourteenth verse.
And who knoweth whether thou art come to the kingdom for such a time as this?
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight,
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, our Lord and our Savior, dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
you who are the listeners of our radio audience,
and especially you, the forty-three young men and women,
the high school graduates of our church and of our Sunday school.
This is your baccalaureate service.
You have come, young friends, to God's house this morning
in order to hear a message from the word of God
as you say farewell to your high school days
and as you take a look at your future.
I wonder how many of you have spent long moments in the last several weeks
on this perplexing question.
Does God really guide my life?
Does God really lead me?
Does God really direct me?
Or is God the kind of a God who allows me to flounder as best I can,
to grope as a blind man and to feel my way along in life?
Does God really lead me?
Where is the guidance of God
that I can have some assurance that my life can be beautiful,
that it can be worthwhile,
and that it can be most satisfying?
How many of you have spent many an hour
on that question?
Does God guide you
as high school days are over
and you are now looking to the future?
I would like to, at this baccalaureate service,
assure you, young men and women,
that God does lead you,
that God is hopelessly and gloriously concerned in your life,
that he leads you every inch of the way
and that your life can be beautiful.
It can be most satisfying and most complete,
that God never for a moment allows you to flounder
and to grope in the darkness,
trying to feel your way,
wondering where to go.
And I would like to impress that truth on your minds
by calling to your attention an incident
that happened in the Old Testament
about 500 years before Jesus came into human history.
It was back at the time after the children of Israel,
the southern kingdom had been destroyed
and Nebuchadnezzar had taken them in the year 586 B.C.
into captivity down in Babylon.
Then, you know, the Babylonian Empire fell
and the Medes and the Persians came to power
and the man on the throne was the Persian king
called Ahasuerus or Xerxes.
One night, as he was giving a party there in Persia
and they were drunken with wine,
he ordered that his wife Vashti
should come and display herself
before a group of drunken men.
She refused to do so
and so he banished her as queen.
And so then his portuers went out
into the land of Persia
to find someone who would take the place of Vashti
who would be the queen of Persia.
And they found a very beautiful little girl.
She was a Jewess and her name was Esther,
which means star.
Her Hebrew name was Hadessa,
which means Stella.
This little star, little Estrelita,
because of her beauty,
she was brought to Susa
and the king picked her as his queen.
He did not know, however,
that she was a Jewess.
That information was kept from her.
The man who stood next to the king
was a man by the name of Haman.
We would call him the prime minister.
And because Esther had been an orphan child
and had been reared by an older cousin
who had adopted her
and he became her guardian,
this man Mordecai was his name.
He stayed near the palace
that he might communicate with Esther
who was now the queen of Persia.
And because this man Mordecai
again realized that being a Jew,
he would bow to no man,
Haman the prime minister hated him
because Haman thought that he was a god
and he wanted everybody to do obeisance to him.
But Mordecai refused.
And so Haman planned
that he was going to kill Mordecai
and more than that,
he was going to exterminate
the entire Jewish race.
There was going to be genocide.
And by duping the king,
he had the king sign an edict
that on a certain day in Persia,
the Persians would rise up
and they would kill these alien people.
That every Jew would be exterminated.
And of course,
that would mean also Queen Esther herself.
And then it was that Mordecai,
in communicating to Esther,
told her,
he said,
Esther, you must do something.
The fate of our people depends upon you.
And then he spoke the words of this text.
He says,
Who knows, Esther,
whether thou art come to the kingdom
for such a time as this.
How do you know
but what God has led you, Esther,
that he has guided you,
a little Jewish girl,
to become the queen of Persia
for such a crisis
when your entire race is at stake?
God guided Esther.
And may I assure you,
when you have asked yourself the question,
Does God lead me?
Does God guide me?
Does God have anything to do
with choices in my life?
I want to assure you that God has.
He is hopelessly involved in your life.
God leads and guides
who are not left to flounder alone.
And you may say,
But it's hard to see.
I see no evidence of God in my life.
You may look and you say,
The events of my life,
they're ordinary.
They're commonplace.
They're trite.
They're rather trivial.
I fail to see the hand of God.
I'd like for these moments this morning
as we are here in God's house,
I would like to show you
on the basis of Esther
that God does lead and direct your life.
And that if you will look
with the eye of faith
on those little inconsequential events
in your life,
you will see that God
is hopelessly and gloriously involved
in your life every inch of the way
and every day
that you aren't left to flounder alone.
In the first place,
I would remind you of this,
that perhaps again,
God is leading you
for such a day as this,
even as he led Esther,
that in the first place,
God has led you
to be born in this era,
and he has led you
to know Jesus Christ.
Don't you think Esther
thought many a time,
I wonder why I was born
an alien down in Persia
instead of over in Palestine
where my people had come from.
Don't you imagine
that Esther wondered at times,
why have my parents died?
Why am I an orphan?
Why was I born with the beauty
that I have been born with?
How does it come
that I was born in this age?
You know,
when I was in Egypt
down in, again,
Luxor,
450 miles south of Cairo,
and I saw the great temple
of Ramses II,
and I realized
the heathenism of Egypt
back 2,000 years before Christ,
you know,
the thought came to my mind,
I wonder how it was like
to have been born then,
and I said to myself,
I wonder why I wasn't born then,
when I saw again
the pyramids in Egypt,
again the pyramids of Sheops,
and I said again to myself,
I wonder why I was born
in the 20th century,
not back there
2,000 years before Christ,
when I stood in the cave
of the bulls,
when the Egyptians
worshipped the sacred bull,
and again,
steeped in heathenism,
I thought to myself,
I wonder why I was born now,
and not back there,
did you ever wonder
why you were born
in the 20th century?
God moves in a mysterious way,
we have just sung,
haven't we?
But again,
God must direct your life,
because you were born now,
not 2,000 years ago,
why were you born
into the home
that you were born in?
How does it come,
you have the father and mother
that you have,
not somebody else's father and mother?
Does God guide you
in this era?
Most assuredly,
he does,
even as he was guiding Esther,
and above all,
in this guidance,
God guided you
to know Jesus Christ.
Many of you were seated here
on Palm Sunday
four years ago,
weren't you?
After again,
your days of catechism,
when you were led
by your parents
to know Jesus Christ
as Lord and Savior,
you heard the story
of God's Son
who came into this world,
and became a human being,
and went to Calvary
and suffered and died
for the sins of the world,
when he gave a complete atonement
for sins,
and that in him,
through trust in him,
there is forgiveness,
life, and salvation.
You came to know him
as Lord,
and you may say,
what is the guidance of God?
Where is his leading?
Does God care about my life?
Is his hand
in the shaping
of my human days
from day to day?
And my answer is yes,
unequivocally.
God is hopelessly involved
in your life.
You again have been led
to Jesus Christ,
and therefore,
God still guides you
in the ways of right,
so that in the ways of right
in which you are to walk
in the future,
you may not lose
that life and salvation
which is yours in him.
Ours is an amazing God,
young friends.
The matter of right and wrong
is something that is absolute
in his sight.
Right is not something relative
that it changes today,
and that what is right today
is wrong tomorrow,
or that what is wrong now,
50 years,
may be right not at all.
The rightness of God,
because God is immutable
and he is changeless,
that rightness stands
throughout time
and it stands
throughout all eternity.
What is right
is always right
in the sight of God.
What is wrong
is always desperately wrong.
And as God guides you
from day to day
on the basis of the knowledge
that you have of him,
guiding you in the ways
of right,
God guides you
every inch of the way,
calling upon you
at all times,
do that which is right,
lest you lose
Jesus Christ.
God is hopelessly
and gloriously
involved in your life.
He does lead you,
he guides you,
even as he was guiding
Esther,
little Esther,
elite 500 years
before Jesus came
to the world.
And that's why today
I would say to you,
I hope that you go out
of church this morning
believing this,
that God has his finger
in your life.
I want you to go out
with this assurance,
regardless of anything,
that God leads
and God guides.
If you will go out
of church with that conviction
this morning,
then I know this,
you'll have daily contact
with him.
I want to be very honest
and frank with you,
you will never be seated
of course like this again
in this church,
will you?
This is it.
And another thing,
if there's ever a loss
in the church,
it's after this Sunday.
Rather strange,
isn't it?
But why is it that some say,
I've gone to church
all my life
and this is the end,
the apron strings are cut,
I'm going to live my own life.
I know my parents
have brought me to church,
but I'm going to find out
what it is not to go to church.
There isn't anybody
that can stop you,
isn't that right?
From now on,
you're on your own.
I know you're 18,
you're not 21,
but you're on your own.
The great drop
in the church comes now.
Be very honest with you
and reckoned with you,
that's when the dip comes.
If we're going to lose you,
we're going to lose you
after high school.
Because again,
you can say,
I can live my life
as I please,
I'll do as I please,
I don't have to obey my parents,
I don't have to do anything
but what I want to do.
But if you can go out
of church this morning
knowing this,
that God does lead your life
and he does direct that life
and God is hopelessly involved
and gloriously so,
you will have daily contact.
You'll keep it up
and you'll go to church
and you'll hear the word.
And again,
Jesus Christ will still live
in your hearts.
Here was again
a man by the name of Haman
who was threatening
the extinction
of an entire race
of people,
the Jew.
May I say,
that happened 500 years
before Christ,
but don't forget,
it also happened
in our day too.
Don't forget Adolf Hitler.
This thing of genocide
was tried in his day.
Yes,
when he wandered away
from God
and that which was right,
when a man does that,
a man is a dangerous man
and six million Jews,
don't forget,
went into the gas chambers
of Buchendalt and Dachau.
Human beings
created in the image
of God,
gassed
because a man
tried to exterminate
the Jewish race
just like Haman did of old.
You have no idea
what a potential
you have for wickedness
without Jesus Christ.
A painter tells the story
that he wanted to paint Jesus
and all the twelve disciples.
He started with Jesus.
It was a number of years later
that he wanted to get a man
to typify Judas.
And he went out again
to the lower sections
of the town,
to the underworld,
and he picked a man
that looked to him
just like Judas.
When he was painting him
one day,
the man that he was painting
as Judas looked at him
and he says,
I was the man
that you used years ago
to be the Christ.
It's not a very long way
from being a Christian
to being a Hitler
who would exterminate
an entire race of people.
You do not know
what you can do
when you forget
that God guides you.
And that's why
speaking to you
face to face
and heart to heart,
I hope that when you go
out of this church
this morning,
you have the assurance
that God does lead,
He does guide.
And God is hopelessly
concerned in your life
that you're going to say,
therefore I'm going to live close.
And I'm not going to forget Him
because who knows
the potential
of evil
that can come
in any man's life
without Jesus Christ.
You may say,
well,
my life is,
oh,
it's inconsequential.
The events of my life,
there's nothing extraordinary.
There's nothing great
or pretentious.
I fail to see
the evidence
that God has something
to do in the guidance
of my life.
And I want to assure you
that He does.
Just as again,
Mordecai said to Esther,
who knoweth
whether thou art not
come to the kingdom
for such a time as this?
God's leading you
for such a crisis.
God leads you.
Don't you ever forget it.
He guides you.
He is hopelessly
involved in your life.
Because in the second place,
I want to assure you this,
that God, again,
has led you to be endowed
in a most unique
and singular way.
Have you ever realized,
and I know you have,
just how different you are
from the man sitting
alongside you
with the girls?
You've seen it in school,
haven't you?
Why is it that you look
at some and you say,
oh, I wish I had
that guy's brain?
Maybe you've looked
at some of these girls
and said,
I wish that I had
her ability and talent.
Isn't it strange?
You've noticed
a difference,
haven't you?
Maybe you've gone
into an inferiority complex.
You know,
it's easy to do,
isn't it?
When I turn over
a radio set
or look at the back
of it and see
all those wires,
I get weak all over.
Because to me,
it's a maze
I don't understand it.
I'm doing good
with a television set
to get the picture
in focus.
I don't know
what it'd ever do
if something was wrong.
If an automobile
to run had to depend
upon my fiction
it,
it would never run.
Now,
shall you get
a very feeling
of inferiority?
No,
again,
there are some things
we can do
and there are some things
we can't do.
There was Esther.
Again,
uniquely situated
and endowed.
She was a beautiful girl.
But oh,
what quality
she must have had
when finally
Mordecai told her,
he says,
your race depends
upon you,
Esther.
You've got to go
into the king
and you've got
to tell him
that he's been duked,
that he signed
a death warrant
for our nation.
You've got to tell him
you're a Jewess
and you've got to tell him
that on a certain day
we're all going
to be killed.
Well,
again,
if you understand
the rule of the Persians,
no one dare walk
into the presence
of the king
without first
having been summoned
and it was punishable
by death.
But Esther was
a clever woman
to be sure.
She was a wise
and a person
as a serpent
and harmless
as a dove.
She used to actually
dressed up beautifully
that day
and again,
then she was going
to walk in
on her husband.
She hadn't seen him
for months.
Walked in on him
unannounced
and if he would hold up
the golden scepter,
that would mean
she could come in
and if he didn't
hold it up
it means she would
be taken out
and killed.
And she said
to Mordecai,
I go and if I perish,
I perish.
And again,
with a prayer
on her lips,
she walked
into the presence
of her husband,
the king of Persia.
She looked
and she wondered
what he was going
to do.
When he saw her,
he looked up
the golden scepter
and he held it
out to her
and she walked up
and she touched it
and she bowed
before him
and he said,
what do you want?
Then she told him,
she said,
I want to give
a banquet for you
and for him
and the prime minister
and the king said,
all right.
So they had a meal
that day.
Then the king said,
what is on your heart?
And she says,
I'll give another banquet
for you two tomorrow
and I'll tell you.
The next day,
the king and Haman
were together
and there was Esther
and finally she stood up.
Again,
little Esther Lita,
a little Jewish exile girl,
a little orphan.
And she stood up
before the king of Persia
and she said,
you have been duped,
oh king.
You have been duped
to sign the death warrant
for the nation of aliens
that live among you.
And she says,
I am a Jewess
and if this is carried out,
I shall be killed.
The king in rage
looked at her
and he said,
who caused me to do that?
And she says,
Haman,
you're high,
the gang,
you're prime minister.
And he had done it
and he had duped
and full enraged,
the king walked out
of the room
and Haman threw himself
on the couch
where Esther was lying.
When the king walked in,
he said,
would you even besmirch my wife?
And Haman had secretly
built a gallows
in his own yard
because he was going
to hang Mordecai
because Mordecai
wouldn't bow to him
and the king ordered Haman
to be hanged
on the gallows
that he prepared
for another.
And because in the laws
of the Persians,
no law could be rescinded,
the king issued
another redict
and he says,
you Jews may defend yourselves.
When the day came,
the Jews defended themselves
and 75,000 Persians
were killed.
But they were not exterminated
because of the heroism
of Esther.
Of Esther who again
had been endowed by God
and God led her
through again
the circumstances of life
to fulfill her mission.
I hope you go out
of church this morning
with this conviction,
young friends,
that God does lead you,
he guides you,
and he directs you
that your life
can be beautiful
and it can be worthwhile
and it can be satisfying.
And if you can go out
with that conviction again
as God through circumstances
will lead you
to find your niche
and your mission in life,
then you're going to submit to it
when God calls you
and leads you
to see your responsibilities.
Some of you may say,
well I don't know
what I'm going to do.
I'm worried.
I don't know what I want to do.
The answer doesn't come.
Does God guide me?
Will God guide me
and lead me
to my mission in life?
And my answer is yes.
If you will watch
the opportunities
and the circumstances of life.
If you'll pardon
my own illustration in life,
I'd like to tell you my story.
When I entered
Capitol University,
I wasn't certain
that I was going to be a minister.
I was hovering
between ministry of medicine,
one or the other.
I wasn't sure.
When I returned
to Capitol University
in my sophomore year in college,
it so happened
that I had discovered
that I had a large stone
in my kidney.
I was not in good shape.
I lasted out the year
and I remember
taking my final examination
just a young lad,
19 years old.
Took the final examination
and that stone
started to act up
and I was a pretty
miserable person.
I took the first train
to St. Louis
that I could get out.
I didn't want to be sick
in Columbus.
I called my urologist
and I told him
that something was wrong.
And the first time
I got to see him,
I'll never forget
when I was being examined
by him,
he looked at me
and he said,
how long has this been going on?
And I told him
and when he looked at me
and he said,
I hope you don't lose a kidney.
I know what it means
to lie on a hospital bed alone,
19-year-old boy,
a lot of ambition
and wanting to do something
in life,
then being told
you might lose a kidney.
Life almost folded that day.
I wondered,
oh, to be a minister
to go through life
with just one kidney.
God and I had quite
a conversation that day
and I asked God
that if it were his will
that he'd save that kidney for me
that I was willing
to give him my life
to surrender it
and to be a minister
that I had in mind,
it seemed that God
was calling in that circumstance
like he had never called before.
Well, the stone was removed,
the kidney was checked
and double-checked
as urologists do
and he came in
and he said to me,
your kidney isn't damaged at all.
You can be a healthy minister
and I say this
in the deepest sense
of humility
and appreciation.
This coming week,
it'll be 33 years
since I graduated
from the Capitol University Center.
I've been in the ministry
for 33 years
and I've never missed
one Sunday for illness
in 33 years.
I want you to know
that as far as I'm concerned
from the depth of my soul,
God does lead
and God does guide.
And as this church
has grown
to the largest
Lutheran church
in the Ohio district
of the American Lutheran Church,
believe you me,
the responsibilities
are tremendous.
But the health
that God has given
amazes me.
Don't you ever forget
God does lead
and guide
and direct you
and I ask you
when you see
his hand
accepted
and surrendered.
Yours will be
the joy
of fulfilling
your mission
and your mission
in life
and that's
the greatest joy.
Life can be beautiful,
it can be worth living.
There was Queen Esther
and you may say,
what am I going to do?
What does God want?
Do you look at the future?
Does God guide
and direct?
Does he care?
Don't I just flounder
as a blind man
groping my way
and just feel
my way along
and I don't know
what I'm supposed to do
and why I'm alive?
Listen,
I want you to know this
that from the depth
of my soul
I believe
God does lead
and he guides you
and he directs you.
He is hopelessly
and gloriously
involved in your life.
There's never a moment
of any day
that he doesn't guide you.
You may say,
well,
where's the evidence?
And I would mention
in the third place
is that God leads you
to love
and he leads you
to be loved,
doesn't he?
Love is a marvelous thing,
isn't it?
You may say,
who am I going to marry?
Talk about love again.
God made us male
and female,
didn't he?
Yes,
sex was a beautiful thing.
That's the way
God made us.
And yet love again
was to use sex
that it might be used
to God's glory.
I like to define love.
Love is that
which is left
when sex
has been satisfied.
Isn't it strange
that maybe some of you
already have experienced
that God has led you
to love somebody else?
It's a thrilling thing,
isn't it?
But you say,
why do I love so and so?
Somebody else may say to you,
well,
how can you love her?
And they say to you,
because how can you love him?
And you say,
but I do.
And again,
he may be homely again,
all the things
that may be wrong,
but something about love
to one person.
And isn't it the joy of life
to be loved,
to know that somebody cares?
As one man says,
the joy of my life
is this,
to know that somebody cares
whether I get home
for supper on time.
God does lead you.
And may I assure you
that when God leads you
and guides you
in this thing of love
and you find someone
that you'd love to live with
and he with you
and you can consummate it
in matrimony,
God will lead you.
That life can be beautiful
because,
listen,
your home,
God would want it such.
It ought to be
a veritable foretaste
of heaven.
Bear in mind,
it doesn't depend upon
how much money
you're going to make.
It doesn't depend upon
the name you make in life.
But when God Almighty
leads your life
and directs it
and he is hopelessly involved
and gloriously so,
God will lead your life
that your home
can be a bit of heaven
on earth.
And if it isn't,
it's because you didn't
let God guide you
and you didn't let him
lead you.
There was little Esther,
yes,
the little Jewish girl
and orphan girl
and exile.
She may have said
to herself over
and over again,
and I,
a little Jewish girl,
should become the queen,
the queen of the king
of Persia.
Oh, you know,
about this man,
Ahasuerus,
he desperately loved her.
He must have adored
the ground she walked on.
They were married
for five years
when she walked in that day
and he held out
the scepter to her.
Again,
there was something
about her
that he loved
and as history goes on,
again,
he was followed
by his son,
her stepson,
and that was,
again,
Artaxerxes
and he was the man
that sent Nehemiah
over to rebuild Jerusalem
and build the wall
and to fortify the city.
What a place
Esther had
in the plan of God.
You may say,
well,
what did it mean
that she was the one
that saved the Jewish race
from extermination?
Young friends,
don't forget
Christ came from
the Jewish race.
What would have happened
had on that day
in Persia,
had there been
simply an extermination
and over in Palestine
because Persia ruled
the world
that every Jewish man
and woman
and child
would have been killed.
Jesus came from,
again,
the chosen people,
the Jew.
God used
a little slave girl,
Estrelita,
and she saved the nation.
And today,
the Jew still celebrates
the Feast of Purim.
The word pure
means,
again,
a lot.
Heman cast a lot
on the day
when he was going
to exterminate the Jew.
And they celebrate
the Feast of Purim,
which commemorates
the time
when God used
little Estrelita
to save a nation
that Christ came
from the Jewish line,
the Lord and Savior.
I hope you go out
of church this morning,
high school friends,
knowing this,
that as you face
the future,
God does lead you.
He does direct you.
He guides you.
He is hopelessly,
gloriously involved
in your life.
And I hope you go out
with grateful hearts
that as you surrender
to his will,
you can thank God
that he really is
that much concerned
about you.
And I hope also
that you will thank God
that you live in a nation
where you can allow
God to lead
and you can do
as God leads.
You realize what it means
that America is
our native land.
Yesterday was Memorial Day
when again we honored
our soldier dead,
the men and the women
who have given
of their lives
that this nation
could be free,
of the people
and by the people
and for the people
should not perish
from the earth.
Let me tell you,
you've got to get out
of this nation
a little bit
in order to appreciate it.
When I was behind
the Iron Curtain
and in nations again
where a man wasn't free,
when I came back
to America,
I was ready
to get down
on my knees
and kiss the ground.
That's what it meant.
You can't appreciate it
until you get out of here.
If you don't like
this nation,
this is the greatest
under heaven,
let me assure you.
And as young citizens,
listen,
go out and know this,
that in this land
that it's so great
and that's so marvelous
that you can fulfill
your mission in life
and God can lead you
and you can fulfill it.
Then stand on tiptoe
and wait and see
what is in store for you.
Last Friday night,
you remember,
President Johnson
was down in his hometown
in Texas
and he gave the
commencement address
at the little high school
from which he graduated.
Do you remember
the thing that he said
over and over again?
And he just,
he was amazed.
He said this
in that speech
before that small group.
He said,
40 years ago,
I was graduated
from this high school
and he said,
I just can't believe,
I just can't believe
that the path
has led from this high school
to the White House.
You see what he was acknowledging,
how God had directed
and guided his life
from that little high school
in Texas
to the White House
to become President
of the United States.
Go out of church
this morning
and remember Esther,
Estrelita,
little star.
Let her restore faith
in you
that God Almighty
who runs the universe,
he is hopelessly involved
in your life.
He leads you
and he guides you
as you go along
the glory road.
I hope that you surrender
to your Lord
and that you say,
I'm going to let God guide
and I'm going to walk
with Jesus Christ.
That you can sing
on the glory road
the hymn
that you've sung so often,
living for Jesus,
a life that is true,
striving to please him
in all that I do,
yielding allegiance,
glad-hearted and free.
This is the pathway
of blessing for me.
God bless you.
Amen.
The peace of God
which passeth
all human understanding,
keep and unite
your hearts and minds
in Christ Jesus
unto life everlasting.
Thank you.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
thank you.
Thank you.