Let us be unto you and peace from God our Father and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written in the gospel according to St. Matthew, the second chapter, verses 1 and 2.
Now when Jesus was born in Bethlehem of Judea in the days of Herod the king,
behold there came wise men from the east of Jerusalem saying,
Where is he that is born King of the Jews?
For we have seen his star in the east and are come to worship him.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer. Amen.
In Christ Jesus, the manger child of Bethlehem,
dear friends, you who are here in God's house this morning,
and you also Christian friends who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Today we are celebrating the festival of Epiphany.
We are also taking note of the fact that this is the first Sunday of a new year.
The word Epiphany means a manifestation or a showing forth,
and this festival commemorates the manifestation of Jesus as the Savior to the wise men.
The festival of Epiphany is also called the Gentile Christmas
because the wise men were not Jews, they were non-Jews,
or as we call them, Gentiles.
The festival of Epiphany is also called the festival of the 12th day
because it always comes on January the 6th,
which would be Wednesday of this week,
12 days after the regular Christmas of December the 25th.
Epiphany is the oldest festival in the Christian church,
for it was celebrated even before the Christmas of December the 25th.
So many of the Eastern Christian churches will celebrate their Christmas
this coming Wednesday,
and they did not celebrate on December the 25th when we celebrated Christmas.
We may say the festival of Epiphany,
the coming of the wise men from the East,
they who were Gentiles coming and finding the Christ child.
We may say this morning what happened after Jesus was born in the manger.
Well, we know that on the 8th day in Bethlehem,
he was circumcised, as were all Jewish boys and given the name Jesus.
32 days later, Mary and Joseph took him,
which means he was 40 days old at the time.
They took him from Bethlehem,
and they went to Jerusalem to the temple.
And there they found, as we heard last Sunday,
they found Simeon the seer who blessed the Christ child,
and Anna the prophetess was there also.
Then Mary and Joseph with the child came back to Bethlehem,
there to live, and it was some time after that
when the wise men came from the East.
And as these wise men came from the East,
they came to Jerusalem, and they asked the question,
where is he that is born King of the Jews?
Seemingly, Jerusalem knew nothing about his birth.
But this morning, as we celebrate the Epiphany Festival,
we are interested in what the wise men had to say
about this Christ child.
And we asked them this morning,
wise men, what do you say about this child Jesus?
And their answer is this,
what child is this?
He is no less, they would tell you and me,
than the King of the Jews and more.
He is the King of the Jews,
but he is more than the King of the Jews.
He is also the King of the Gentiles as well.
He is not only the Savior of the Jew,
he is also the Savior of the non-Jewish world,
both Jew and Gentile.
He is the King of all men.
That's the answer of the wise men
today on this Festival of Epiphany.
And you and I, as we celebrate it,
we may look at this child again
and listen to the statement of the wise men,
this is the King of the Jews and more,
because they came,
they who were not Jews,
they who were Gentiles,
and they came and worshipped him as their King.
We may say,
but is there any conclusive evidence
that Jesus was the King of the Jews and more,
that he was also the King of non-Jews,
Gentiles as you and I are?
Is there any evidence?
In the first place,
I would offer this this morning.
There is the evidence of the wise men themselves.
How intriguing when we hear the story of the wise men.
Oh, they came later, as we know,
because Herod ordered the slaughter of the infants
from two years and under.
It may have been a year or more later
after the birth of Jesus,
when the wise men came.
But we wonder, who were they?
How many were there?
You know, we talk about the three wise men,
do we not?
But the word of God doesn't tell us that there were three.
Tradition says there were three.
Now, when I use the word tradition,
understand that means it's not in scriptures,
but again,
it has grown up as part of the story.
Perhaps the most obvious reason
why we talk about three wise men
is because they presented three kinds of gifts,
gold and frankincense and myrrh.
And so again,
the world has said there were three.
We do not know how many there were.
It was quite a large entourage
because they traveled a long way.
And we ask ourselves,
where did they come from?
What do you mean from the east?
Well, Bible scholars feel
that that is not too difficult a thing to answer,
to know where they came from.
If you remember some of your Jewish history,
you recall that in the year 586 before Christ,
Nebuchadnezzar came out of Babylon
and came and destroyed the southern kingdom
and he carried the Jews away
into captivity down in Babylon.
And then after 70 years,
they were allowed to come back to their native land,
being in exile that length of time.
But many of the Jews remained in Babylon.
And therefore, it's most obvious to feel
that having Jews living in Babylon
for over 600 years,
Jews who knew of their hope,
who knew of their Messiah,
who spoke of it,
it was very obvious
that the people in Babylon
and many of them
would know about the Jewish hope
and would be looking for that Messiah.
And then just as God,
when Jesus was manifested
to the shepherds who were Jews,
did a miracle,
and God again had an angel appear
and announce Jesus' birth
to the shepherds who were Jews,
and again the angelic choir,
so God again,
in announcing that this Christ child
is going to be the king of the Jews
and more,
king of the Gentiles,
God works a tremendous miracle.
We are told something about a star
that arose in the eastern sky.
Oh yes, astronomers tell us
that back about that time,
there seemingly was a conjunction
of Jupiter and Saturn,
and we say,
does that answer the question?
It was from Chaldea over to Jerusalem
over 600 miles.
God placed a star,
these wise men were astronomers
or astrologers,
using something that they were interested in.
There was a star
that guided these wise men
and their entourage
over 600 miles
through the desert
by day and by night.
Say what we will about the star,
the only obvious answer is this,
that God placed a star.
Whether others saw it or not,
that you and I do not know,
but there was a star.
And the wise men,
as they saw it moving,
they followed it,
believing that this was going to be
the answer to that hope
that the Jew had in his land,
and that here they would find
the Savior for themselves too.
And so the star,
a miraculous miracle of God,
brought them to Jerusalem.
And when they came,
they asked,
where is he that is born
king of the Jews?
And when Herod, of course,
heard about another king,
and Herod thought that his throne,
therefore, was in danger,
Herod wanted to know all about it.
He called the chief priests
and scribes and says,
where is this king to be born?
And they told him rightly
that the prophet had said,
in Bethlehem.
And they quoted Micah's prophecy.
And then again,
these wise men
were certainly men of influence
because they had an interview
with the king.
He called them together privately
and he said,
just when did the star appear?
Herod wanted to know,
how long has it been
since you have seen this star?
He wanted to get an idea,
how old is this child?
And again,
they gave him all the information
they had,
and he told them
to go to Bethlehem.
There is where the king of the Jews
was to be born,
and then to come back
and to tell him about it.
And so they,
again,
they started from Jerusalem,
but bear this in mind,
when you start from Jerusalem,
you go south.
You're no longer going west,
and as they started south,
lo,
the star appeared again,
and we are told
that they were thrilled.
The star appeared,
it was guiding them
to the place
where they wanted to go.
They traveled six miles south,
and they came to Bethlehem.
And the star came,
and it stood over the place
where Jesus was,
and we are told
they went into the house.
Jesus was no longer
in the manger.
He was in the house
at the time,
and Mary was there,
and they went in.
These heathen people,
600 miles from the east
in Babylon,
they had come to Jerusalem,
and here was the king
of the Jews and more.
He was the king
of the Gentiles,
and they bowed down,
and they opened up
their gifts,
and they presented
unto him gifts,
gold and frankincense
and myrrh.
On this epiphany festival,
we ask the wise men,
who is this child?
What child is this?
And their answer,
he is the king
of the Jews and more.
He is the king
of the Jews
and also the king
of the Gentiles.
He is the savior
both of Jew and Gentile,
the savior of the entire
human race.
And here we are today
on the threshold
of a new year.
Would to God
that you and I
would take this king
of the Jews
and more with us
into this year.
I'd like to ask you
straight from the shoulder
this morning,
does it really do any good
in your life and mine
to take him along
with us into a new year?
Do you really see
any difference?
Or is that just stuff
you heard about in church?
Is that just stuff
for nice people?
Or does he make
any difference
in your life?
If you and I
take the king
of the Jews
and more along
with us in this year,
does he make
any difference?
Really now,
does he?
Do you see any difference
in your life?
Does he make
this difference
that when you and I
take him along
as far as I am concerned
to take him along,
that means that
in this year
I am saved
and I am not lost?
Does that mean
anything to you and me?
Has the glitter
of salvation
worn itself thin?
Have you and I
lost the thrill
of being saved?
Not knowing
whether we're ever
going to see
the end of this year
or not.
Not knowing
how soon death
will come.
Does it mean anything
to have Jesus Christ
who is the king
of the Jews
and more
to be saved,
to be rescued
from sin,
from eternal death
and to have heaven?
Does it mean anything?
When Jesus said
it would be better
that that man
speaking about Judas
had never been born,
have you and I
really come to grips
with this
and have said to yourself
it would be better
I'd never been born
than to be without
Jesus Christ
and salvation?
Could we look at it
this morning
in the light
of the wise men?
Salvation must be
something tremendous.
It must be
something hilarious.
If God almighty
by a miracle
picked up some
heathen men
in Babylon
led them over
600 miles of desert
led by a star
brought them to Bethlehem
and said
here is your savior too.
Here is the savior
not only of the Jew
but the savior
of the Gentile world.
If you and I
can take him along
he does make a difference.
It's the difference
between heaven and hell.
between being saved
and being lost.
The festival of epiphany.
Yes,
the coming of the wise men.
And the wise men
tell you and me
when we say
what child is this
wise men?
And they say
this is the king
of the Jews
and more.
Oh yes,
he's the king,
the savior,
the Jews all right
but he's more than that.
He is the savior
of the Gentiles.
He's the savior
of Jew and Gentile,
the savior of the world.
And you and I
may say today
at the beginning
of the new year
is there any evidence?
Oh,
there's the evidence
as I have mentioned
of the wise men
themselves
but how about
the evidence
of prophecy?
Did prophecy say
that this babe
was to be
not only the king
of the Jews
but more
the king
of the Gentile world
too?
The savior of all?
When you look
into prophecy
again,
it's a tremendous
thing.
We go back
to the Garden of Eden.
You know,
it's rather interesting.
We don't know
exactly where
the Garden of Eden
was but
the cradle of humanity
was over in Mesopotamia,
in other words,
in Babylon
where the wise men
had come from.
Somewhere around
in that area
in the world
a God created man
and there was
the Garden of Eden.
And you know,
when we go back
to the Garden of Eden
Adam and Eve
when they had sinned
and there was Satan
you remember
what God said to them
and I will put enmity
between thee
and the woman
between thy seed
and her seed
it shall bruise thy head
and thou shalt bruise his heel.
God promised
the seed of the woman
that again
would be the savior
of Adam and Eve
who in embryo
they again
had the world
within themselves.
There were
no diverse races.
The very first promise
of a savior
the seed of the woman
then
was one
to be a universal savior
not just
for one little group.
Go to the time
of Noah
when Noah
blessed his oldest son
Shem.
He did say
blessed be the Lord
God of Shem
and Shem was again
the progenitor
of the Jewish race
who are the Semitic people.
In other words
this Messiah
this king
would come from Shem
but he also said
to Japheth
who was the second
oldest son
Japheth shall dwell
in the tents of Shem.
Japheth
you shall enjoy
the blessings
that will come
from Shem.
Already
Japheth was again
the forefather
of all Gentile races.
Gentiles
were to share.
You take Abraham
God told Abraham
who was the father
of the Jewish race
he said
Abraham
in thee and in thy seed
shall all the nations
of the earth
be blessed.
Prophecy
never excluded
the Gentile.
Prophecy
in telling
that Jesus
would come
from the Jewish line
nevertheless
always included him
as the savior
of the Jew
but more
the savior
of the Gentiles.
Take that matchless
piece of prophecy
that was our epistle
lesson from Isaiah
the 60th chapter.
Isaiah lived
700 years
before the Christian era
and when he saw it
he says
arise shine
for thy light
has come
and the glory
of the Lord
is risen upon thee
and then he said
for Gentiles
shall come
to thy light
and kings
to the brightness
of thy rising.
Did you ever wonder
why we
again we have
we call them
three wise men
we call them kings
Matthew doesn't say
they were kings
Isaiah says
and Gentiles
shall come
to thy light
and kings
to the brightness
of thy rising.
Our forefathers
believed
that the wise men
companies
were a direct
fulfillment
of Isaiah 60.
That's why
they called them kings
they were the Gentiles
because they presented
unto him gifts
they presented
unto him gold
and frankincense.
So again
we call them kings
because Isaiah said
kings shall come
to thy rising
and so again
prophecy
certainly never
excluded the Gentile world
that's you
and that is I
we are Gentiles
non-Jews
we were never excluded
this babe
was to be the king
of the Jews
to be sure
but more
but then we look
at Jesus
and we say
well how about
Jesus himself
was he a
pure blooded
Jew
according to the flesh
or was there any
Gentile blood
in the veins
of Jesus
when I was in the
Holy Land
in the Middle East
we came to the
ruins of Jericho
and I shall never
forget that experience
seeing again
the ruins
where once stood
the city of Jericho
and several members
of the party
who didn't know
the story that had
occurred
they came up
and said
what happened
at Jericho
would you tell us
about it
what really took
place
well you know
we remember
this about Jericho
do we not
when Moses died
and Joshua
took command
and they crossed
the Jordan
and they came
and they surrounded
the city of Jericho
you know
on the seventh day
they went around
it seven times
and the walls
of Jericho
fell
and that's about
all that some
of us remember
about Jericho
but oh there's
an intensely
interesting thing
that the Bible
tells us
remember Joshua
sent spies
into the city
before they took it
and they went
to the home
of the prostitute
of the city
of Jericho
and her name
was Rahab
remember Rahab
and Rahab
hid the spies
so that they
weren't killed
and then she
was promised
by the spies
that when they
would take
the city of Jericho
that if she
would put a
scarlet cord
in her window
and have her
family in that
house
that the Israelites
would not hurt
her
or her family
the town
prostitute
put a
scarlet cord
in the window
rather strange
isn't it
years ago
a prostitute
put a
red cord
in her window
and to this
day
the places
of ill fame
in cities
and metropolitan
areas
are still called
red light
districts
after the
red cord
and prostitutes
are called
scarlet
women
because
Rahab
years ago
put a
red cord
in her
window
but it's
also
significant
that
the blood
of Jesus
is red
and
that
shed
blood
of Jesus
that
cord
in the
window
as it
saved her
from being
killed
isn't it
wonderful
that the
blood
of Jesus
red
even
makes
prostitutes
and scarlet
women
whiter
than
snow
wonderful
isn't it
that
took place
in ancient
Jericho
where it was my
privilege because
of you to stand
but oh the story
goes on
Salmon a Jew
who married her
he married
Rahab
this prostitute
and they had
a son
and his son's
name was
Boaz
did you ever
hear of Boaz
and Boaz
owned some
ground around
Bethlehem
and then there
came into
Bethlehem
a Gentile
heathen
girl
a Moabitess
by the name
of Ruth
a Jewish
family had
gone to Moab
you remember
a father
and mother
and two sons
and the sons
had married
Moabitess
girls
and then
the men
died
and then
the mother
Neoma
wanted to
come back
to Israel
and the one
daughter-in-law
who was a
Moabitess
a heathen
her name
was Ruth
remember the
story
and Ruth
walked with
her to the
border
and Neoma
told her
goodbye
and to go
back to her
god's
men
this little
Moabitess
young lady
said no
no I'm
going along
Neoma
your people
are going
to be
my people
and your
god
is going
to be
my god
and where
you lodges
that's where
I'm going
to lodge
and where
you rest
that's where
I'm going
to rest
and where
you die
that's where
I'm going
to die
and then
this
Boaz
who was
a Jew
who had
flowing in
his veins
prostitute
blood
of Rahab
a Gentile
married
Ruth
the Moabitess
who was a
Gentile
and then
the word
of God
says that
Boaz
and Ruth
had a son
and his name
was Obed
and Obed
had a son
and his name
was Jesse
and Jesse
had a son
and his name
was David
and Jesus
was from
the family
of David
therefore
in the
very veins
of the
son of
God
according
to flesh
there flowed
not only
Jewish
blood
but there
flowed
Gentile
blood
the blood
of Rahab
the scarlet
woman
of Jericho
and the
blood
of Ruth
the Moabitess
who had
embraced
the true
God
I ask
you this
morning
in the
mercy of
God
could God
have done
something
more beautiful
and noble
to convince
you and me
that his son
yes the
king of the
Jews
but oh
more than
that
the king
of the
Gentiles
non-Jews
the savior
of all
men
could God
in his
mercy
have done
it any
more
beautifully
than just
that
and that's
why this
morning on
the first
Sunday of
a new
year
I ask you
let's take
him along
does he
make any
difference
let's get
down to
brass tacks
does he
make any
difference in
your life
or mine
or do we
just kid
ourselves
I insist
that he
makes a
difference
when you
take him
along
the difference
between being
saved and
being lost
but there's
another thing
it's the
difference between
having peace
of mind and
not having it
I don't care
who you are
or how
intelligent or
educated you
may be
I know this
just as sure
as I'm sure
that God
lives
there isn't
any peace
of mind
outside of
Jesus Christ
if you've
got peace
of mind
apart from
him you're
just deluding
yourself
you don't
have it
it's the
ostrich
complex
you're just
burying your
head
I know this
just as sure
as I'm alive
that the only
peace of mind
that can come
to you is the
only kind
that can come
to me
because I've
got a guilty
conscience
and so have
you
I know that
I'm a sinner
and so do
you
the only way
in the world
to get rid
of a guilty
conscience
is not to
cover it up
and not look
at it
but again
to take
Jesus Christ
and let his
blood wash
it whiter
than snow
and when
again
he washes
your soul
and mine
whiter than
snow
that conscience
no longer
condemns
then you
and I've
got peace
of mind
all troubles
are going
to come
who in the
world is
going to
escape trouble
in this
year
all of us
shall have
troubles
the big thing
is how
shall we
bear them
but I
know this
that if
I've got
him
and I've
got forgiveness
every day
in him
and I belong
to him
that in
spite of
what comes
I know
he's not
punishing
me
I know
that he
is not
angry
with me
I know
that he
loves me
and I
know my
sins are
forgiven
it does
make a
difference
friend
whether you
take him
along or
not it
makes a
tremendous
difference
oh epiphany
that tremendous
ancient festival
of the church
when again
Gentiles said
this is our
Lord too
he's the
king of the
Jews but he's
more than that
he's the
king of the
Gentiles
and we
say is there
any evidence
so not only
the evidence
of the wise
men and not
only the evidence
of prophecy
but the evidence
of Jesus
himself and
his church
when you
stand at the
cross of
Christ did
Jesus ever
say that
again his
salvation that
he was rendering
on the cross
was only for a
certain few
didn't Jesus
say for God
so loved the
world
didn't he
come to be
the world
savior
didn't Christ
as the son
of God
come into the
world and
therefore show
himself
to be big
enough to
die for your
sins and
mine and
also for the
sins of the
Jews as
well as
non-Jews
the tragedy
of it all
is that Jesus
says he came
to his own
and his own
received him
not
oh yes they
don't receive
him but oh
that manger
child he was
the king of
the Jews
but oh thank
God he was
more he was
your king and
mine too
he was the
king for
everybody when
he picked
Saul of
Tarsus on
the Damascus
way he
told Saul
that he was
to be again
his witness
to the
Gentiles and
Paul went
out and he
preached to
the Jew and
he preached to
the Gentile
look at the
Christian church
today predominantly
Gentile this
savior the
savior again the
king of the
Jews but also
the king of the
Gentiles his
church is
absolute evidence
to you and
me that the
babe of
Bethlehem this
one that the
wise men came
to worship why
he is the
king of the
Jews but he's
more he's the
king of the
world yours and
mine the savior
of all men
without exception
my prayer is
today that as
we stand on the
threshold of
65 that we'll
take him along
he does make a
difference really
he does God
pity the man
that doesn't
have him
because if we
take him along
I'm sure this we
don't have to be
afraid of tomorrow
I had two rather
interesting experiences
on the afternoon
of New Year's
Eve I met two
different people
who expressed
themselves about
New Year's
Eve one said I
hate New Year's
Eve I hate it I
like Christmas
Eve but I hate
New Year's Eve
I wondered I
hate New Year's
Eve the other
one said I
don't know why
but I'm very
despondent when
New Year's Eve
comes oh I
get the blues I
don't want to be
alone I want to
be with somebody
I'm going to go
to bed early he
said to get it
over with I
wonder how many
of you this
morning here in
church and how
many listening I
wonder how many
of you are
afraid of tomorrow
did you hate New
Year's Eve did you
hate to think of a
new year what's
coming in the new
year did you I
can tell you this
if you and I
take along this
king of the Jews
that the wise
men saw you
don't have to be
afraid of tomorrow
why I don't care
what tomorrow
brings in your
life and mine I
do know this that
when I have taken
him with me there
isn't anybody going
to take me away
from him against
my will look what
happened the wise
men gave him the
gifts and then in
a dream that night
God appeared to
them and told them
not to go back to
Herod but to go
another way and the
next day when Herod
found out that again
they had fooled him
Herod was simply
filled with vehemence
and with hatred and
he ordered the
soldiers into
Bethlehem and they
killed all the
little boys some two
years and down you
see he played it
wide he thought this
child can't be more
than two years old
we'll kill them all
and then we hear a
prophecy that Rachel
was weeping for
her children I
thought of that when
I was in Rachel's
tomb right outside
of Bethlehem she's
standing for the
mother again of
believers and Rachel
weeping for her
children because they
were dead Rachel of
old who died when
she gave birth to
Benjamin but what
happened that same
night the angel came
to Joseph in a dream
and said get up this
very night and go to
Egypt and again flee
for the child's life
did God take care of
this little babe and
Joseph and Mary got
up to that little babe
and they started for
Egypt now from
again Jerusalem or
Bethlehem down into
Egypt to go down to
Memphis or Heliopolis
it's about 250 miles
you may wonder where
did Joseph get any
money for a trip like
that oh God saw to it
those wise men they
presented him gifts
gold that's where in
the providence of God
God provided the money
that he could go down
to Egypt I was in
Heliopolis I was down
in Cairo I was in a
little shrine where they
tell us that here it
was that Joseph and
Mary came down they
lived in Egypt may have
been there for about a
year until Herod died
but God took care of
that child and again
after that time an angel
came and said Herod is
now dead now you can
return so Joseph and
Mary was the child they
came back intending to
stay in Bethlehem but
they found that Archelaus
Herod's son was on the
throne they were afraid
so they didn't remain in
Bethlehem they went on
up to Nazareth up in
Galilee their hometown
about a hundred miles
from Bethlehem and there
there they stayed God
took care of this king
of the Jews and believe
you me God will take
care of you and he'll
take care of me I
stood in the desert seeing
the sands and the
tremendous heat and I
thought of the wise men
think of it six hundred
miles and you and I can
stand today and say oh
what a God again they
knew this king king of the
Jews and we can sing we
three kings of Orient are
bearing gifts we traverse
afar field and fountain
moored and mountain
following yonder star oh
star of wonder star of
night star with royal beauty
bright westward leading
still proceeding guide us to
thy perfect light he is the
light of the world take him
along friend when you've got
him with you you don't have
to be afraid of tomorrow and
if we have him with us then
we can wish one another a real
blessed happy new year amen
the peace of God which passeth all
human understanding keep and
unite your hearts and minds in
Christ Jesus unto life
everlasting