Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the Word of God as we find it written in Paul's second letter to Timothy.
Read there in the second chapter, beginning at the eighth verse.
Remember that Jesus Christ, of the seed of David, was raised from the dead according to my gospel,
wherein I suffer trouble as an evildoer, even unto bonds, but the Word of God is not bound.
Therefore I endure all things for the elect's sakes, that they may also obtain the salvation which is in Christ Jesus with eternal glory.
It is a faithful saying, for if we be dead with him, we shall also live with him.
If we suffer, we shall also reign with him.
If we deny him, he will also deny us.
If we believe not, yet he abideth faithful, he cannot deny himself.
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength and our Redeemer.
Amen.
Good morning, dear friends, in Christ Jesus, you who are here in God's house,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshiping with us by means of the radio.
Today, the second Sunday in May, as you know, is Mother's Day.
Some of you have the honor of having your mother in church with you this morning.
Some of you will visit your mother sometime today.
Some of you will call your mother and speak with her before this day is brought to an end.
Some of you have written to your mother and have expressed your love and your endearment to her.
Others of us today have only mothers of memory.
On this Mother's Day, I ask myself the question,
what shall I say to you today, Christian mother?
What shall be my message to you
when I am assured that our nation's number one problem is this one,
our youth and, again, a growing lawlessness against decency and order?
What shall I say to you this morning, Christian mother,
when I am told that our chief problem is our young people
and growing immorality and the social diseases which go with it?
What shall I say to you this morning?
What shall I say to you this morning when I am told
that our greatest need and our greatest perplexing problem
is our youth and the growing crime rate?
What shall I say to you, Christian mother?
Christian mother, you may be saying this to yourself today.
You may say, I know as a Christian mother,
I've got the word of God that I am to give to my child.
But you may be losing confidence in it.
You may be saying to yourself, if only it had more power,
if only it had more dynamite, if only it had more energy.
It doesn't seem to be adequate.
It doesn't seem to do the job that I am called upon to do with my child or with my children.
You may be losing confidence in the power and the efficacy of that word.
To you, Christian mother, I would like to give Paul's answer
as we find Paul writing in his second letter to Timothy.
If you recall, Paul was in jail in Rome when he wrote these words.
And he wrote to young Timothy and he said to Timothy,
Timothy, remember this, that I have preached the risen Christ.
That's the heart of my gospel.
And then he said, Timothy, because of that, I have endured many hardships.
He says, I have even been put in chains as a common prisoner.
And then he said, but the word of God is not in chains, Timothy.
The word of God is not bound.
It isn't held up.
And Christian mother, today I want to tell you this about the word of God that you have.
It is not in chains.
It is not bound.
It is not held down.
It is not tethered.
That word of God, there's nothing wrong with it.
It is absolutely adequate.
It's got all the power and the energy and the dynamite
so that there is no reason in God's world for your child or children ever to grow up
and to grow up for a life of immorality and incest, a life of crime, and a life of disregard for law and for order.
That word of God is not bound, Paul says, thank God.
It is not in chains.
Do you have confidence, Christian mother, in the word of God that it's not bound?
May I assure you it is not in chains.
It is absolutely adequate.
There is nothing lacking because the Holy Spirit works in the word of God.
God, the third person of the Trinity, the word assures us, he works in the word of God and listen, because he does.
There is nothing more that he could do with the word of God than what he does.
Don't lose confidence in the power and the efficacy and the adequacy of the word of God.
I'd like to remind you, Christian mother, in the first place of this fact,
that the Holy Spirit, through the word and water, he still causes your child or children to be born again.
Has baptism somehow or other failed?
Or isn't that a tremendous thing that the Holy Spirit does through the word?
Bear in mind that baptism is still the word of God.
It's the word of God added to water.
And bear in mind when Nicodemus was talking to Jesus that night,
that Jesus told Nicodemus, if you want to get into the kingdom, you've got to be born again.
Just to be born physically is not enough.
And therefore, Christian mother, because your child was born physically, that's not enough.
Jesus says, that which is born of the flesh is flesh.
That's sinful.
And your child, as you know, came into this world subject to death and it was a sinner.
Not that it had done wrong, but it came into the world in a condition of sin.
And yet Jesus says, it must be born again.
Bear in mind that the Holy Spirit, by means of the word of God and lowly water,
causes your child or children to be born again, a spiritual birth, raised from death to life, spiritually speaking.
And that in that baptism that the Holy Spirit had still through the word of God in water,
he kindles faith in your child's heart.
Oh, it's not a conscious faith, but in that faith in Christ, your child's sins are forgiven.
Your child is delivered from eternal death.
Your child has eternal life.
I ask you this morning, Christian mother, could the Holy Spirit do any more than that as he does in baptism?
And then in baptism, because there is a faith in Christ, the Holy Spirit places Christ in the heart of your child or children.
And he watches over that child, that Satan and the fallen angels shall never grasp that soul away from that infant for themselves.
Do you believe in guardian angels?
Don't you realize, Christian mother, that the Holy Spirit through this tremendous word,
when by baptism Christ comes into the heart of your child,
that Christ stands there and he says to Satan,
No, no, you don't.
You leave this soul alone.
This soul belongs to me.
I ask you on Mother's Day,
do you think that the Holy Spirit could do more than that,
than what he does in baptism?
And then let's look at you this morning.
If there is something inadequate,
if we are losing confidence,
if there is something missing,
may I first of all tell you,
have this confidence that it's not in the word.
The word of God is not in chains, Paul said.
It's not bound, it's not tethered, it's not held fast.
When you realize that the word of God,
it's got everything,
therefore that there's no reason why your child or children should ever grow up
for lives of immorality or incest or lawlessness or crime,
then will you see to it
that your child or children are baptized
and that you treat them as baptized children.
In the Old Testament,
the child, the male,
was circumcised on the eighth day.
It was early.
And therefore, again,
it ought to be early in the life of your child,
Christian Mother,
when you bring that child to holy baptism,
when that child is born a second time
of water and the word of God
by means of the Holy Spirit.
When Christ moves into that child's heart,
and Christ holds on,
and Satan doesn't take that soul
and doesn't grasp it away from Jesus.
And then will you see to it
that you treat that child
as a baptized child ought to be treated.
You know, Christian Mother,
it's strange the children that come to me sometimes
and they're starved for love.
Why is it the children come and say,
I've never seen my mother kiss my daddy.
I have never seen daddy kiss my mother.
I don't know what it is
to be kissed by my mother.
I don't know what it means
to be tucked in bed
with a goodnight kiss at night.
I had an adult sit in my office one day
and he cried like a child.
And he said to me,
I'm hearing things I've never heard in my life.
I don't know what a Christian home is.
Believe me, I don't.
He sat there and he sobbed.
I don't know what it is
to have a mother that ever kissed me.
You know, during the Korean conflict
on the cover of Life magazine,
do you remember it?
There was a picture of a Korean refugee,
a little boy
about the size of my oldest grandchild today.
And they said,
the little boy that never smiled.
Can you imagine?
A little boy that could never smile.
Yes, he lost everything.
Father and mother,
sisters and brothers
and a little waif
about five or six years of old.
They gave him ice cream
and they gave him all kinds of candy.
And he couldn't smile
because he didn't know what love meant.
And it took months until finally,
oh, that picture has haunted me,
to find with that little Korean waif,
he learned how to smile.
What kind of soil,
Christian mother,
do you have in your home
for your baptized children
who belong to Christ?
Is it a little bit of heaven on earth
or is it a living hell?
If it's a living hell,
let me tell you this morning,
there isn't anything else
that you can do
that is going to erase
that kind of a background
if your child doesn't have love
and is starved.
Why, even the sunflower,
when the sun shines
with its radiancy and warmth,
it turns to the sun.
Your child,
I'm asking you,
bringing it right down
in your home and mine.
Is there any love?
Is it a little bit of heaven on earth?
Could that be what is lacking?
If it is,
God pity you,
Christian mother.
You say to me,
what can I say
to a Christian mother today
when we are told
the nation's number one problem
is that of youth
and growing immorality
and growing incest
and growing lawlessness
and again,
growing immorality
and crime
and you as a Christian mother
can say,
and here we've got
the word of God
but there seems to be
something lacking.
It doesn't seem to have
what it ought to have.
It doesn't have the zip.
It doesn't have the punch.
It doesn't have the dynamic,
doesn't it?
Paul in jail
told young Timothy,
thank God the word
is not in chains.
It's not bound.
It's not tethered.
Oh,
the word of God's got everything.
Don't lose confidence,
Christian mother,
in the word of God
because the Holy Spirit
works in the word of God.
That means in the second place
have confidence in it
because the Holy Spirit
still through this word
he feeds that faith
of your child
or your children.
Yes,
you see,
you are the one
to teach the child
the word of God.
Do you realize,
Christian mother,
that as you take time
to teach your child
about this Christ
in whose name
your child was baptized,
this Jesus living within him,
that that faith
and that confidence
begins to grow
as you tell him
the story about Bethlehem
and as you still tell him
the story about Jesus
that died on the cross
for him
and as you tell him
the beautiful story
about the resurrection
of Jesus,
you realize that as you,
the great teacher
and the first teacher
that comes to your child,
you realize what the Holy Spirit
does through that word of God
as you teach that child
why the Holy Spirit
working through the word,
he causes that faith
and that confidence
to grow larger and larger
and larger
and tell that child
he grows in love
for Christ
and in love for heaven.
I talked to a little
four-year-old boy one day,
I was making a call
at the home
and he was riding his bicycle
out in the street
and I said,
you better get on the sidewalk,
you may get run over
and you may be killed
and he looked up at me
and all the seriousness
of a four-year-old
and he rather smiled
and he says,
then I would be with Jesus
in heaven,
wouldn't I?
Oh, what a faith.
And Christian mother,
you think there's something
lacking in the word of God?
Do you think that
as you teach this word of God
that there is nothing
that you can do,
that this word is inadequate,
that somehow or other
your child or your children
must grow up
to live lives of immorality
and incest
and lawlessness
and in crime?
Oh, the word of God,
it's not in chains.
What more could
the Holy Spirit do
in the case of your child
or your children
than to have that faith
blossom forth
in a real confidence
that heaven is real?
And to whom is heaven
more real
than to a little child?
Oh, I ask you today
on Mother's Day,
have confidence
and the word of God,
it's not bound,
it is not in chains.
Then and only then
will you be willing
to simply,
you will be willing
to submit
and endure anything
for the salvation
of your child
or your children.
Paul wrote to Timothy
because the word of God
is not bound.
Paul says,
I am willing
to undergo anything
that the cause
of the gospel
that men may know
Christ and eternal life.
I ask you
this morning,
Christian Mother,
how far are you
willing to go
in the price
that your children
will grow
in Jesus Christ?
You know,
we all like to see
animal acts,
don't we,
on television?
And I think
most of you know
I've got a dog
and you may wonder
how come the dogs
can do some of the
wonderful things
that they do.
Do you ever talk
to an animal trainer,
to a dog trainer
and ask him
how this thing happens?
He'll tell you this,
he says,
when you train an animal
or when you train a dog,
there must be
no variations.
It's got to be
the same way
all the time.
My dog's name
is Pumpkin.
I get up early,
far earlier
than most of you,
anywhere from
4.30 to 5,
a little after,
because I can study
in those hours
and you aren't
calling me
at those hours
and I'm not
so much disturbed.
But after studying,
I go down
and I have
a cup of coffee.
My dog,
Pumpkin,
lies there
when I'm drinking
that first cup
of coffee
and he never moves.
But just as soon
as I get up
and pick up that cup
and go for the second cup,
he's up and he's alert!
Why?
Because he knows
at that time
I wake the missus.
And as long
as that routine
never varies,
just as soon
as I pick up
that cup,
Pumpkin knows,
that's the time
to awake the missus.
Have you,
Kristen Mother,
learned to put
first things first?
You know,
in catechism,
I have kids come
and say,
I can't come
to catechism
because I've got
to take a dancing lesson.
We're not arguing
about dancing,
though.
They can't come
because there's
a ball game
or because it's
the swimming lesson
or because
they've got to do this
or they've got
to collect
for their newspapers.
All nice things.
But,
Kristen Mother,
are you willing
to undergo
anything
that you finally
get this thing
straightened out
but first things
come first?
I had an interesting
thing happen
just several months ago.
These kids
that had science displays,
you know,
that they were
to prepare
and some of them
got pretty nice readings
and that meant
some Saturdays.
One of our mothers
told one of the daughters
in the confirmation class
she was not going
on Saturday
because Saturday
was catechism class.
and she was not going
unless
Reverend Hollinson
excused her.
Now,
you may argue,
Mother,
and say,
oh,
that mother was
rather extreme
and that mother
was this or that
but listen,
I'd like to assure you
that there is
a daughter
who for the rest
of her life
will remember
that one day
her mother
taught her
in a great way
that there is
something bigger
than science displays
as well as they are.
I think that young lady
learned something.
Oh,
in case you're interested,
I excused her,
yes.
But I'm just asking you,
Christian mother,
what comes first
in your family?
Is it Christ
when Sunday comes?
Is it the rule in love
that all of you
are in church
and you're worshiping?
or is it
the exception?
And when there is
variation,
are you not
screaming aloud
to your child
in the greatest
letters possible?
You don't have
to go to church.
to hear the word
of God.
It doesn't make
any difference.
I'm asking you,
Christian mother,
are you willing
to pay the bill?
What comes first
in your home
and mother?
Oh,
I mean you do it
in love.
In catechism,
one of the tenacious
things I fight for
is that I assure
those kids I love them.
Regardless of what
happens,
I never embarrass
one child.
I love them.
Why?
Because I know
with it all,
if they don't know
that I love them,
I've lost my influence.
and what's worse
than a minister
to lose influence
with the young kids?
You say,
this is Mother's Day.
What shall I say
to you,
Christian mother,
if again,
the great problem
today in our country
is not communism,
but it's
our young people.
It's a growing
lawlessness,
a growing immorality.
It's a growing
crime wave.
You may say,
how can you
stem the tide?
The Word of God
doesn't seem adequate.
It doesn't seem
to have the zip.
It doesn't have,
again,
the effervescence,
the power,
the dynamic,
doesn't it?
Paul says,
I may be in change,
but thank God
the Word of God
is not in change.
It's not bound.
It's not tethered.
Why don't you know,
Christian mother,
the Holy Spirit
works in the Word of God?
And I would remind you
that means in the third place
that the Holy Spirit
still today,
He sharpens by means
of the Word
that conscience
of your child
or your children.
This thing called
conscience,
you know,
the Bible tells us
that when God created
our first parents,
He wrote in their hearts
His law,
the knowledge of right
and wrong.
That was conscience.
There was the knowledge
already by creation
inherent in them,
and even though
they fell into sin,
there is a remnant
of that knowledge
within all of us.
all of us
have a conscience,
and we are never
to violate that conscience,
but that conscience
needs to be fed.
It needs to be sharpened.
Do you realize,
Christian mother,
that when you
fulfill the role
that is yours
as a teacher,
you are the greatest
teacher your child
will ever have.
You may not be the best,
but you'll be the greatest
because you're there first.
But when you teach
that child,
especially the Ten Commandments,
that the Holy Spirit
through the law
is sharpening
that conscience
and making it
sensitive
to right and wrong.
And when the Holy Spirit
makes that conscience
sensitive,
the Holy Spirit
puts into that heart
of your child
or children
a fear of the Lord,
a dread
of doing something wrong.
I ask you this morning,
what more
do you want
the Holy Spirit
to do
than to put
the fear of the Lord
a sensitive
conscience
by means
of the Word of God
in the heart
of your child
or your children?
You may say,
why isn't it forced?
Because God
doesn't force morality.
God made you
and me
with choice.
You know,
a mother called me
one day.
She wanted me
to remonstrate
with her daughter
and ball her out
and this was the reason.
They decided
on Sunday
that they were going
to go on
a pleasure jaunt.
And the little girl
said,
no,
because I know
that you will not
be going to church
and I'm going
to church.
And the mother
called me
and she says,
I want you
to tell my daughter
who's boss
in this family,
whether she's boss
or whether I'm boss.
Then I said
to that mother,
Mother,
far be it from me
to undermine
your authority
as a mother.
But when you want
me to ball out
your daughter
because your daughter's
conscience said
on Sunday
I go to church
and you told her
not to go to church,
we ought rather
to obey God
rather than man.
Shame on you.
Christian mother,
to ask your child
to go against
her conscience
to do wrong
that you knew
was wrong.
Mother's Day,
boy,
you've got a job,
haven't you?
You've got a
tremendous job,
your role.
I hope today
that I can write it
on your soul
that there's nothing
wrong with the
Word of God.
Paul says,
the Word of God
is not in chains,
it's not bound,
it's not tethered.
There's no reason
in God's world
as far as the
Word of God
is concerned
because the Holy
Spirit works there.
Why your child
or children
must grow up
and live lives
of immorality
or incest
or lawlessness.
Write it on
your soul
to have confidence
in the Word
and when you
have confidence
in the Word
then you will
build a reserve
when the day
of crisis comes
and you won't
be with your kids.
There came
on the campus
of Kappa University
a new professor
in the Sociology
Department.
I had him
for Economics.
We became
quite friendly
and since I remained
for seminary
and we lived
in the same building
we became
quite intimate friends
and then I learned
a bit of his history.
He had been
in the seminary
of his church
and as sometimes
happens
he rebelled
against every bit
of it.
He hated God.
He hated Christ.
He was rid
of all things
that had to do
with religion.
The virgin birth,
the death of Jesus,
resurrection
meant nothing.
He had thrown
it all over
and gone out
as far as the world
was concerned
to live with the world.
But he was
a brilliant chap.
Well,
we used to take
walks at night
because that's
what you do.
You had been
at Camp
where you know
how you can walk
up Drexel abroad
and over to Columbia
and down Columbia
and we used to walk
at night
to get the cobwebs
out of our minds.
We took to singing
a couple of nights
just to be doing
something different.
We sang a number
of hymns
that we sang
and one night
we sang a hymn
that he had learned
as a child
and I had two
in German.
Maybe some of you
know it.
Gott ist die Liebe
er liebt auch mich
drum sag ich
noch einmal
Gott ist die Liebe
er liebt auch mich
God is love
he loves me also.
Well, we sang that
and we'd sing loud
because nobody
was around
and I looked over
at him
and I noticed
he was crying
there were
abundance of tears
coming down
his face
and I looked
over at him
and I said
what's wrong?
And he looked
at me
and he said
you know
he said
I give up
everything
but he said
there's something
that holds me
my mother
taught me
that song
as a kid
and he said
she couldn't
be wrong
she must have
been right
she believed it
and the only
thing that's
keeping me
from throwing
myself headlong
into the world
he said
is what
my mother
taught me
as a kid
God is
die Liebe
er liebt auch mich
oh
you know
the time
is going
to come
you can't
be with
those kids
but oh
God
if you
fulfill
your role
and you
do it
in love
when they
stand up
against the
world
and this
temptation
comes to
lawlessness
and incest
and immorality
and crime
they can
remember
the word
of God
that you
as their
mother
put into
their hearts
and the
Holy Spirit
did his
best
last August
I visited
my mother's
grave
and I
stood there
and naturally
I reminisced
and I went
back and I
said to myself
I can't
remember a
time in my
childhood
but what my
mother told
me I was
going to be
a minister
she literally
prayed me
into the
ministry
I don't
remember the
time but
what she
talked to me
about the
ministry
no one ever
spoke against
the ministry
to my
mother
if you ever
wanted to
tackle the
wrong person
just say
something about
the ministry
to my
mother
and you
had a
fight in
your hands
that you
wished you
had never
started
it was
tenacious
and I've
often thought
to myself
as I did
as I stood
at my
mother's
grave
I wonder
just what
would have
happened to
me if I
hadn't been
prayed into
the ministry
God alone
knows
but Christian
mother listen
if you've
got a home
where there's
love
and you are
fulfilling that
role that God
gave you
the greatest
career in all
the world
this word of
God and you're
teaching it to
your kids
and they have
learned what
love is and
they know how
to sing
oh you've
got it made
kids like
to sing
to their
mothers on
mother's day
and oh what
a joy to
hear them
sing with
love
Jesus loves
me this
I know
for the
Bible tells
me so
little ones
to him
belong
they are
weak but
he is
strong
yes Jesus
loves me
the Bible
tells me
so
Christian
mother
God bless
you in
your confidence
in the word
and a happy
mother's day
to all of
you
amen
the peace
of God
which passeth
all human
understanding
keep and
unite your
hearts and
minds in
Christ Jesus
unto life
everlasting
ding