Grace and peace be unto you, from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ.
The second chapter of the book of Ezekiel.
And the Lord said unto me, Son of man, stand upon thy feet, and I will speak unto thee.
And the Spirit entered into me when he spake unto me, and set me upon my feet,
that I heard him that spake unto me.
And he said unto me, Son of man, I send thee to the children of Israel,
to a rebellious nation that hath rebelled against me.
They and their fathers have transgressed against me, even unto this very day.
For they are impudent children and stiff-hearted.
I do send thee unto them, and thou shalt say unto them, Thus saith the Lord God.
And they, whether they will hear or whether they will forbear, for they are a rebellious house,
yet shall know that there hath been a prophet among them.
And thou, Son of man, be not afraid of them, neither be afraid of their words,
though briars and thorns be with thee, and thou dost dwell among scorpions.
Be not afraid of their words, nor be dismayed at their looks,
though they be a rebellious house.
And thou shalt speak my words unto them, whether they will hear or whether they will forbear,
for they are most rebellious.
But thou, Son of man, hear what I say unto thee.
Be not thou rebellious like that rebellious house.
Open thy mouth, and eat that I give thee.
And when I looked, behold, a hand was sent unto me,
and, lo, a row of a book was therein.
And he spread it before me, and it was written within and without,
and there was written therein lamentations and mourning and woe.
Moreover he said unto me,
Son of man, eat that thou findest.
Eat this row, and go speak unto the house of Israel.
O Lord, open our eyes,
that we may behold wondrous things out of thy word.
Amen.
A wonderful thing is happening today in the life of this congregation,
and in the life of these three men.
You are not only joining the ranks of the clergy today,
not just becoming ordained pastors,
but in many ways you today are joining a company of some very great men.
In a sense, you walk because you will seek in a special way to do his work
in the footsteps of Christ himself.
You also join your feet into the path that has been walked
by the prophets, Ezekiel, Moses, Isaiah.
Into the path walked by missionaries, Paul and Patrick,
and Boniface and Livingston and Cary.
Into the ranks of the martyrs, Peter and Polycarp and John Huss.
The ranks of the preachers,
Chrysostom and Augustine and Bernard and Luther and Wesley.
But most of all today,
you join the ranks of those thousands upon thousands
of plain, ordinary pastors
who without fame and without recognition
have sought to do God's will
where he sent them.
Today, you join their number.
And today, in a very calm and ordinary way,
the same thing is happening to you
that happened to each one of them.
You are being ordained, set apart
for the special work of the Christian ministry.
I'm sure that in your heart
you believe that it is not just the pastors here,
but God himself
who is ordaining you.
And therefore, I ask you
and you people of Emmanuel Lutheran Church
to look at what happened
and what God said
when he ordained one of his other prophets
into the ministry.
Ezekiel.
Although there may seem to be
very few comparisons
between your ordination and Ezekiel's,
there is still, I believe, a great deal
that both you three men
and my good friends
and you, the Christian congregation
that has sent them,
can learn from God
from this text.
I wonder if anybody ever received
a more discouraging call
than Ezekiel.
You know the words,
I send thee to the nation of Israel
to a rebellious house
that have rebelled against me.
They and their fathers
have transgressed against me
to this very day.
They are impudent children
and stiff-hearted
and most rebellious.
How would you feel
if your calls
from Clifton, Illinois
and Warren
and Vickery, Ohio
had been prefaced
with that kind of a statement
about your people?
It isn't that we pastors
want a soft touch.
We're not looking for an easy life.
We know the ministry
is not to be that.
Sometimes danger
and adventure
that even appeals to us
and draws us
but the promise
of pure hard-heartedness
that would be most discouraging.
And the Lord wasn't just
making it sound hard
for Ezekiel
so that he would work hard.
The Lord wasn't just
giving Ezekiel
a good psychological treatment
here at his entry
into the ministry.
Ezekiel's ministry
proved that every word
the Lord spoke
was true.
Ezekiel worked
for 22 years
among the house of Israel
from early morning
till late at night
in the temple
in the streets
at home
sometimes speaking to them
sometimes reproving them
with no words whatsoever
and his whole ministry
if measured by modern standards
of statistics
and conversions
and baptisms
and accessions
and money raised
would have been
labeled a miserable failure
from start to finish.
And yet it was the right
place for Ezekiel.
When the Lord
ordained him
as one of his prophets
the Lord sent him
to the right place.
It was where God
wanted him.
where a strong man
of God
could be used
a man who didn't
depend every day
for his impetus
to do God's work
on a pat on the back
and an encouraging gift
from somebody
who appreciated
what he was doing.
The results show
too that it was
the right place.
God's word
was declared
to those people
even though
it meant judgment.
And so God
sent Ezekiel
to the right place.
Isn't it a wonderful
boost
people of Emmanuel
and John
and Jack
and Dick
to your own
faith in God
to see how often
God
in one way
or another
gets just
the right man
to the right place
at the right time.
You could name
a number of them
in the history
of the church.
I think you've learned
a little of that
in the past
three years.
How did God
get Paul
to Macedonia?
How did he get
William Carey
to India?
How did he get
the very men
who brought you
the gospel
who brought
Jesus Christ
to you
and somehow
helped God
to get him
into your lives
so that
you dedicated
yourselves to him?
How did he get
them to just
the right place
at the right time?
The men who
nurtured you
and the women
here in Sunday school.
They don't have
to be pastors
to be called
by God.
How did they
get right there
at the right time
to produce
this result
today?
It's so common
a thing.
Many of God's
people doing
good work
for God
right where
they are
that we often
forget it.
And we complain
about those pastors
or those people
who don't do
what God
gives them to do.
But isn't this
really what
the divinity
of the call
means?
that God
gets his
people to
where he
wants them
to where
they can
do his
work.
And as you
step into
the ministry
today and
are ordained
by God
that confidence
can fill your
hearts
that of all
the places
in this world
that you
might have
chosen
or where
he might
have sent
you
he wants
John Kerr
among his
people in
Clifton,
Illinois.
He wants
you
Jack
Maxim
among his
people
nowhere else
right now
but in
Warren,
Illinois.
He wants
you
Dick
Williams
not
anywhere
or
everywhere
but he
has a
place
for you
prepared
and ready
where you
can serve
him
in
Victory,
Ohio.
There
is God
and there
are God's
people
and God
has been
making
things ready
not only
those who
are already
his but
those in
those very
places
who haven't
yet heard
his word
he has
been preparing
them for
the ministry
that you
are personally
and specifically
tailored and
prepared by
God to
give.
And with
that confidence
you can
go.
In the
confidence of
the psalmist
who said
the steps
of a good
man are
ordered by
the Lord.
Today you
have to
believe it
but if you
enter into
your ministry
leaning on
God's arm
and counting
on his
promise
the day
will not
be far
off
when you
will not
only have
to believe
it but you
will be able
to see
that it
was so.
That
confidence
unshakable
can be
yours by
looking at
this word
of God
to Ezekiel
when the
Lord ordained
that prophet
and it's
true when he
ordains you.
But Ezekiel
had no sooner
been told
where to go
then the
Lord also
made sure
that Ezekiel
would know
what to
say.
He left
Ezekiel
in no doubt
about what
his message
was to be.
I send
you to
them and
you shall
say to
them
thus saith the
Lord God.
You shall
speak my
words unto
them
all my
words that
I speak
unto you.
receive in
your heart
and hear
with your
ears and
go say
to them
thus saith
the Lord
God.
And then
God gave
Ezekiel a
scroll and
made Ezekiel
eat it.
And Ezekiel
when he ate
it said
that it
was as
sweet as
honey in
his mouth.
not
everyone
who is in
the ministry
of God's
church
knows
clearly and
sounds forth
clearly
the word
that God
means his
people to
hear.
The Scottish
preacher
Alexander
McLaren
tells about
a church
member who
once came
to him
and said
I heard
sermons
in my
home church
every Sunday
of my life
and yet
in spite of
that
thank God
I am still
a Christian.
There are
too many
as long as
there is even
one in the
ministry of
God's church
there is then
one too many
if any of
God's prophets
sound forth
the essential
good news
from God
with an
unclear sound
and as you
stand today
on the
threshold of
your ministry
I think you
are grateful
in your
hearts
that you've
been nurtured
in a church
and prepared
for the
ministry
in a church
where you
have been
taught
that you
are not
to give
people what
happens to
be in your
mind on
every Sunday
morning or
during the
week
but that you
are called
to break
for them
a message
from God
himself
and you
will not
at every
point when
you open
your mouth
in the
ministry
be able
to say
thus saith
the Lord
because a
pastor as
he deals
with his
people
often
gropes
and hunts
as he
seeks
to meet
their needs
but when
you proclaim
God's word
especially
from the
pulpit of
God's church
then as
you have
been taught
you will
be able
to say
and you
will only
be authorized
to speak
for God
when you
know you
can say
thus saith
the Lord
God
think
you three
and Christian
people
for a moment
about what
it means
to be a
pastor
to stand
Sunday
after Sunday
just to talk
about one
part of it
in a pulpit
every week
to have
before you
scores
or hundreds
of people
each one
of whom
expect you
to bring
to him
on that
morning
a word
from God
that will
help to
meet the
needs
of his
own
heart
at that
moment
there will
be the
young
and the
old
the happy
and the
sad
the forsaken
the lonely
the sinful
the repentant
the indifferent
the perplexed
every Sunday
you will be
called upon
to speak
helpful
words
from God
to people
who are
as different
as day
is from
night
and many
of whom
will look
up to you
and expect
you to
say
there is
God
go that
way
here is
God's
word for
you today
anybody
who going
up the
steps of
the pulpit
does not
feel small
and afraid
is audacious
beyond all
description
that's why
Spencer called
the pulpit
that awful
place
and anybody
who covets
such a calling
for himself
or enters
into it
thinking that
he is worthy
that he is
God's gift
to the world
for this
moment
for whom
everybody
has been
waiting
has pride
beyond belief
any normal
man with
the apostle
Paul would
say
who is
sufficient
for these
things
but there
are the
people
and they
are waiting
to be fed
and you
are to bring
them the
food
in such
a situation
it must
be the most
hopeless
and frustrating
thing
imaginable
to have
only
arguments
various
points of
views
my particular
ideas for
that week
to have to
lay before
God's people
if that were
your calling
to bring
forth from
the depth
of your
own soul
every day
every Sunday
something to
give to the
people
then the
most suitable
text on
your ordination
Sunday would
be
God have
mercy on
you
but that's
not your
future
and it's
not mine
and that's
why you
and I
in spite of
what we
are
and in
spite of
our
shortcomings
and often
our lack
of faith
and obedience
why we
have the
audacity
to enter
into the
pulpit
of God's
church
because there
is still
within his
book
the message
that he
puts on
our lips
you have
been living
in it
you have
been eating
the scroll
at many
points you
have found
it too
to be sweet
as honey
although often
as God
prepares you
for it
it also
has bitterness
to it
and it
bites
burns
when it
gets at
some part
in our
lives
that deserves
to be
bitten
and burned
out
but the
word is
there
and it's
much more
than
Ezekiel
saw
often
Christian
people
call
preaching
powerful
when it
denounces
their sins
or when it
rakes them
over the
coals
occasionally
someone will
even say
that's real
gospel preaching
well it
isn't
the gospel
is God's
good news
that you
and I
need
the good
news to
which a
woman pointed
one day
to Alfred
Lord Tennyson
when he was
visiting her
and he said
to her
do you know
any news
and she
says
there's only
one piece
of news
that I
know
Christ
died
for all
men
and Tennyson
replied
that is
old news
and good
news
and new
and it
is for
you
and for
me
that's
what we
find in
the New
Testament
the apostles
and the
men and
women who
were with
Christ
running out
from a
great battle
fought to a
finish at
Calvary
running out
into the
world
over the
hills
and over
the mountains
and wherever
they went
there was on
their lips
this message
we have
good news
good tidings
from a
battle
fought to
a finish
on Calvary
news that
you are
forgiven
news that
your enemy
has been
defeated
news of
God's grace
and comfort
and hope
and presence
in your
lives
news that's
just exactly
tailored for
you
is that
still news
for you
after three
or four
years in
seminary
of turning
it over
and looking
going at
it from
every angle
until it
becomes
well known
to you
is it
still news
Dr.
Schillinger
after 61
years in
God's
ministry
still news
is it
news for
you Christian
people
you've heard
it often
is it
still news
for you
that makes
your heart
leap up
that puts
joy in
your soul
that gives
you a reason
for living
and a hope
in dying
thank God
there have
been days
when men
and women
could hardly
keep their
voices steady
when they
spoke Christ's
name
and talked
about that
good news
that's
your good
news
that's
what you're
called to
proclaim
that's
the news
that God
brings into
men's lives
to make
them over
people his
children
that's
the news
that God
equips you
with as
your message
today when
he ordains
you into
his ministry
saint
bernard
the great
preacher
of the
medieval
age
said that
when he
preached
his own
ideas
people
invariably
praised
him
but when
he preached
that good
news
then sinners
came up
to thank
him
so to
preach
not that
people will
praise you
but so that
sinners will
find the good
news and
thank God
that's your
calling
and a man
doesn't learn
that in
four years
of seminary
he doesn't
learn it in
ten years
of the
ministry
there's no
quick overnight
course in
which you can
learn it
you will be
eating that
scroll for
yourself of
God's gospel
every day
as long as
you live
every week
as you seek
to break the
good news to
God's people
and when you
do that
people will
hear it
as you have
heard it
and you
will know
you do
not have
the option
of believing
it or not
believing it
because you
will hear your
almighty maker
and lord
speaking it
to you
and it will
fill your
heart
and you
will say
thank God
that he
brought into
my life
the good
news
but to
proclaim it
you not
only have to
be in the
right place
where God
sends you
and know
the right
message
it takes a
little bit
more than
that
it needs
the right
kind of a
spirit
people have
a strange
notion
sometimes
even today
about the
ministry
as if the
shy
quiet
unsociable
backward
boy
who likes
books above
all else
and has never
been in a
speck of
trouble in
his life
is the
best
candidate
for the
ministry
if that
were true
I doubt
whether John
or Jack
or Dick
would be
being ordained
today
but people
still get
that idea
don't they
but let
some
robust
live
courageous
gregarious
intelligent
boy come
along
who's in
his share
of trouble
but who has
a good mind
and lots of
ability
and who gives
promise of
being able
to lay up
plenty of
this world's
treasure
and very
few people
will tell
him
son
do you
think
maybe
God
is calling
you
into the
ministry
as if
the ministry
is a refuge
for the
maladjusted
a quiet
sheltered
life for
cowards
a refuge
for those
who can't
succeed
anywhere else
well you
know better
than that
and Ezekiel
surely knew
better than
that
because God
said to
Ezekiel
your task
is difficult
and it
takes a
good man
and like
Jeremiah
and Moses
I'm sure
Ezekiel
protested
and said
Lord I'm
not a
good enough
man
for that
work
and then
the Lord
when he
ordained
Ezekiel
into that
calling
gave to
Ezekiel
the right
spirit
and he
said do
not be
afraid of
them
though
briars
and thorns
are with
you
and you
live with
scorpions
don't be
afraid of
their words
or their
looks
whether they
hear or
don't hear
just remember
whether they
hear or
don't hear
yet they
will know
that there
has been a
prophet among
them
now our
calling isn't
like Ezekiel
you don't
go to a
rebellious house
of whom God
says that
you go to a
Christian congregation
sure there
are hard
hearted people
around
but the
spirit that
God gives
you and me
upon our
entry into
the ministry
or you
his servant
in the work
that he calls
you to do
wherever you
are
is not
first of all
the spirit
of a hard
head
it's the
spirit of a
soft
great heart
and that
spirit
tailored to
your ministry
God also
offers to
you the
holy spirit
you won't
be called
upon like
Ezekiel to
lie on your
left side
for 390
days as a
rebuke to
the people
read Ezekiel
the third
chapter again
sometime and
see what he
was called to
do or to
lie on your
right side
for 40
days or to
stand against
a nation
every one of
whom was
against you
but you'll be
called upon to
weep with those
who weep
and rejoice
with those
who rejoice
to bear with
the weak
to reprove the
hard hearted
to forgive the
sinner even
before he wants
to be forgiven
to be patient
with the
struggling
to help the
blind to see
fearful to
trust
the lazy to
serve
the selfish
to give
to be so
sensitive to
God and to
his people
that you know
when love will
prompt you to
be firm and
unyielding
when love
will prompt
you to
speak and
when love
will seal
your lips
in silence
you'll be
called upon
to the kind
of life
and the
spirit
that will
be able
to discern
when love
makes you
denounce
evil
and when
love causes
you to go
the tenth
mile
and to
turn the
other cheek
where will
you get
that spirit
where do
you get
the spirit
so that in
your ministry
whether they
hear
or refuse
to hear
yet they
will know
that there
has been
a prophet
among them
same place
Ezekiel got
it
same place
everybody has
to get it
so take hold
of the promise
again
you'll need it
over and over
again
every day
every week
in your ministry
like Pastor
Hollinson does
and every other
man who seeks
to do God's work
take hold of the
promise that it's
there
if you
being evil
know how to
give good
gifts to your
children
how much
more will
your heavenly
father give
the Holy
Spirit
to them
that ask
him
and people
of Emmanuel
don't let
these three
men
go out
from your
midst
into the
ministry
and then
forget them
you have a
role in their
ministry
almost as
important as
theirs
how about the
other seven
from Emmanuel
who went into
the ministry
are they being
supported day
by day
and week
by week
with the
prayers of
Emmanuel
they didn't
go into the
ministry for
themselves
you know
they went in
for God
and for you
do you pray
for them
in Sunday
school
do you pray
for them
in church
do you pray
for them
in the privacy
of your own
homes
in your church
organizations
do you support
them by asking
God
Lord we don't
know anything
about their
difficulties
but we know
to be a prophet
of God
takes your
spirit
Lord
whatever their
needs
this week
give them
the measure
of the spirit
they need
to fulfill
it
it's your
ministry
that they
are seeking
to fulfill
do not
renege
on your
part in it
by forgetting
how you
support their
hands
and how you
can help
God's spirit
come into
them
today the
Lord is
ordaining you
as his
prophets
can you
take from
Ezekiel
this
encouragement
he's
sending you
to the
right place
where he
wants you
to speak
his message
and where
he promises
to give you
every bit
of his
spirit
that's needed
to do
what he
gives you
to do
go then
and feed
the flock
of God
go and
preach the
gospel
to every
creature
remembering
the promise
behold I
am with
thee
I will
keep thee
in all
places
whithersoever
thou goest
amen
true
he
ad
at
name
do
you
to
act