Peace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written back in the Old Testament.
The book of Jeremiah, the 8th chapter, beginning at the 4th verse.
Moreover thou shalt say unto them, Thus saith the Lord,
Shall they fall and not arise? Shall he turn away and not return?
Why then is this people of Jerusalem slidden back by a perpetual backsliding?
They hold fast deceit, they refuse to return.
I hearkened and heard, but they spake not aright.
No man repented him of his wickedness, saying, What have I done?
Every one turned to his course as the horse rusheth into the battle.
Yea, the stork in the heaven knoweth her appointed times,
And the turtle and the crane and the swallow observe the time of their coming.
But my people know not the judgment of the Lord.
How do ye say we are wise, and the law of the Lord is with us?
Lo, certainly in vain made he it.
The pen of the scribes is in vain.
The wise men are ashamed, they are dismayed and taken.
Lo, they have rejected the word of the Lord.
And what wisdom is in them?
And now may the words of my mouth and the meditations of our hearts be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength and our redeemer.
Amen.
Good morning, dear friends in Christ Jesus,
you who are here in God's house,
and you also, Christian friends, who are worshipping with us by means of the radio.
The prophet Jeremiah lived about 600 years before Jesus came into the world.
He was the prophet, the preacher that God used for the southern kingdom of Judah.
We may say to ourselves this morning,
what was going on amongst the people in the smaller kingdom,
that of the kingdom of Judah?
Well, it was just like this.
The people in the southern kingdom, for the most part,
had turned away from God,
and they had turned to wickedness.
They had turned to worldly, sinful pleasures,
and they refused to repent.
And the reason was simple.
They were having too much fun in serving the world
in its willful and wicked pleasures.
What kind of a message could God give to people
who had turned against him to the world
and who were enjoying it to the very nth degree?
God told Jeremiah that he was to say this to them,
thus saith the Lord.
He said,
Tell them this.
Will they fall and not arise?
Will he turn away and not return?
In other words,
God said,
Jeremiah, you tell my people this,
and ask them this question.
What do you think about a man who falls down
and who doesn't get up again?
Now, this is a man that falls.
He doesn't hurt himself,
but he falls and he just lies there.
And I'm sure the people of Judah told Jeremiah,
A man that falls down
that doesn't have sense enough to get up
is just plain stupid.
He's a fool.
After all, that's idiotic.
If you fall down and you're not hurt,
you'll get yourself up again.
And then Jeremiah was to say,
What do you think about a man
who gets on the wrong road
and finds out that he's on the wrong road
when he's traveling?
But he refuses to get back on the right road.
And I'm sure that the people of Judah
told Jeremiah when he asked him that question,
Well, any man that's on the wrong road
and knows it,
and there's the right road
and doesn't get back on,
he's just plain foolish.
He's a stupid fool.
That's all you can say for him.
And then Jeremiah said,
And this is what God says to you,
Why then is this people of Jerusalem
slitting back with a perpetual backsliding?
Why do they refuse to return?
In other words, God said,
You tell the people of Judah this,
Jeremiah,
that because they refuse to repent,
because they refuse to turn away from the world
and from the wickedness of sinful pleasures
and come back to me,
you tell them that this is the height of stupidity,
this is the height of foolishness,
this is the height of idiocy.
But they didn't believe it
because they were having too much fun.
And we in the 20th century,
we may say when God brings this message
that he had Jeremiah give to the people
of the southern kingdom
and brings it to us this morning,
we may say to ourselves,
What is our answer?
When God says,
If they fall,
shall they not arise?
And on the basis of that,
you and I would say this to God,
Any fellow that falls down,
isn't hurt,
and just lies there
and stays there
is just a plain stupid fool.
He hasn't got the sense
God gave a jackass.
There's something wrong with him.
There is something.
He's lost these buttons.
There is nonsense in any man
that would fall down and stay there.
And we'd say the same to God.
If God said,
What do you think about a man
who gets on the wrong road
and finds out he's on the wrong road
and doesn't go back?
You and I would say,
Well, that fellow's a stupid fool.
He hasn't got the brains God gave him.
He's lost what few he's got,
wouldn't we?
But when God says to you and me,
If again we refuse to repent
and we have turned away
from Jesus Christ
and we have turned
to the wickedness of the world
to worldly pleasures
and we refuse to repent,
if God says to you and me
this morning,
Therefore,
this is the height of stupidity
on your part.
This is utter foolishness.
This is utter nonsense.
This is unreasonableness.
This is ridiculousness.
At its worst.
Then you and I sort of stop,
don't we?
And we'd say,
Well, I'm not too sure about that.
I don't know whether this is
the height of stupidity.
And we may say,
Maybe this is the height of wisdom.
Like you and of old,
You know,
there's a lot of fun
lying down there
when you think about it
if you're going to connect it
with the way we live.
Why shouldn't I lie down there?
Why shouldn't I stay
on the wrong road?
There's more fun
lying down there.
on the wrong road
than there is
in serving Jesus Christ
as Lord and Savior.
Doesn't God know that?
And yet,
God says to you and me,
If we refuse to repent
and to turn away
from the world
and worldly sinful pleasures,
God says,
This is just as foolish.
It is just as stupid
as the man that falls down
who isn't hurt
and just refuses
to get up again.
Or the man on the wrong road
that knows it
and just refuses
to get on the right road.
And God says
it's the height of stupidity
because God insists
there is more fun,
there is more joy
in following Jesus
than there is
in following
the world.
Do you really believe that?
You may say to me this morning,
That it would be a hard thing,
fellow,
for you to prove
that there's more fun,
more unadulterated joy
in following Christ
than there is
in following
and indulging
in the wickedness
of the world
with its worldly pleasures.
You may say,
You'll have a hard job
proving that to me,
but I'd like to try
because God is convinced
there's more fun
in following Jesus
than in following the world
because in the first place,
God reminds you and me
of that wickedness,
of that worldly sinful desires
and pleasures
do bring joy,
but at best only temporary,
followed by endless,
unsatisfying craving.
I'd be insane myself
to say to you this morning
that there's no fun
in worldliness,
in wickedness.
Why, if there was no fun
in immorality,
if there was no fun
in drunkenness,
in taking LSD
and taking the trip,
then why do millions do it?
Temptation,
when it comes to you and me,
always offers fun
and pleasure
it did to Eve
back in the Garden of Eden.
Satan said,
If you eat of this fruit,
you're going to be like God.
And Adam and Eve
wanted to be like God.
They thought that was a lot of fun.
And therefore,
when the world says,
Here is fun.
Fun's in immorality.
Fun's in getting plastered.
Fun is in taking the trip.
That's true.
There is.
You mean there's no fun
in looking at pictures
of beautiful women
in go-go girls
that are naked
from the waist on up?
Do you mean there's no fun
in adultery?
Do you mean that there's no fun
in fornication?
Why, of course there's fun.
Well, that's why millions
have turned to it.
God doesn't deny that.
But it's only temporary fun.
What about sexuality?
What about immorality?
Let a couple get married
and let it be on the basis
of sexuality
that he is a handsome Greek god
and she is no less than
a beautiful Greek goddess.
And if it's based only on sexuality,
I give them six months at the most.
Because in six months,
the thrill of that kind of joy
is over with.
That's the wife that comes in
after six months and says,
I don't want my husband to touch me.
I have lost all love for him.
There is no joy.
There is no thrill.
And that's the case
when the husband comes in
and says,
somehow or other,
I'm impotent.
Somehow or other,
I've lost my manliness.
I have no joy
in my wife whatsoever.
It's gone.
Why?
Because God made you and me.
That with what the world
has to offer
in sexuality and immorality
and in getting plastered
or in taking a trip,
it brings joy,
but it doesn't last.
There comes, therefore,
the only answer,
promiscuity.
So you've got to go out
and you've got to seek joy
in somebody else.
And on and on it goes.
And what happens
when promiscuity comes in sexuality?
I was in a government
veterans' hospital
not too long ago.
Over 2,000 men there.
And I asked the officer
that I was with,
why are these men here?
Believe it or not,
this was the answer
and it shocked me.
He said,
over 99%
of these more than 2,000
are here
because they have been bad boys.
They have syphilis.
Syphilis has gotten
into their bodies
and it's gotten
into their brains
and there is
softening of the brain.
A locomotor ataxia.
And you doctors
tell me that
in the venereal disease
that a man can have
a syphiletic infection
and he can go out
in promiscuity.
He can get another infection
on top of that one.
And it eats out
a man's mind.
It eats out
his nervous system.
You mean to say
that there's a lot of fun
in sexuality
and immorality?
I had a man
in my office
one day
in this idea
of being drunk
to try to satisfy
this thing
drinking two-fifths a day.
I've never seen
a man more filled
with alcohol
and yet able
to talk.
The representative
of the local AA
told me that
he stands
as a monument.
Nearly a half
a gallon of whiskey
in 24 hours.
And still standing
sober in a body
screaming for more
because it never
satisfies.
And God alone
knows in the
taking of the acid
as it's called
and in this trip
just what comes.
I walked into
the hospital one day
and the nurse
said to me
whispered
don't touch that bed.
That woman has syphilis.
Watch it.
When you go
into some rest homes
and you see
a man 80 years old
and his hands
are tied
to keep him
from playing
with himself
you and I
say to ourselves
what fun
when we look
to the world
and the world
says come on
this is the way
to live.
Let joy
be unconfined
as
Jeremiah
told the people
of Judah
you'll rush
into it
like a horse
going into battle
unbridled.
you mean
to say
there's more
fun
when a woman
called me
one day
and she says
a man
going through
the backyard
and I have
my underwear
on the line
he's showing
my underwear
you say
for God's
sakes
what gets
into men
and men
who can't
keep their
hands off
of their
own children
that's fun
nobody denies
that the world
offers fun
but take it
from God
it's temporary
and it leaves
a craving
that is endless
that's hell
hell is the
endless craving
for the wickedness
of the world
that will never
be satisfied
in hell
then you say
what fun
is there in
Jesus Christ
may I just
say this
the fun
of being rid
and not
having that
the fun
of having
a decent
mind
and a sound
body
the mind
of not
trying to
satisfy
the wants
of the soul
where it
can't be
satisfied
the joy
and the fun
of self
discipline
in Jesus
Christ
the fun
of being
able to
say
no
God
in this
20th century
speaks to you
and me
in the message
that he gave
to Jeremiah
when he said
you ask them
shall they fall
and not arise
what about a man
that falls down
who isn't hurt
and just lies there
he's stupid
he's foolish
he's idiotic
and God says
when you refuse
to repent
and you turn
to the world
and you refuse
to turn away
you're just as stupid
and just as nonsensical
and just as idiotic
as the man
that just lies
there
and doesn't move
but you and I
say
but
I don't know
there's more fun
lying down there
I don't believe
there is
and when God
says
this is the height
of stupidity
this morning
we ought to say
to ourselves
am I one
that has
wandered away
from Jesus Christ
and turned
to the world
and do I
refuse
to return
am I
in the height
of folly
and foolishness
am I that stupid
before we answer
let's know this
it's easy
to be stupid
and the reason
why it's easy
is that you and I
think we're logical
thinking
reasoning
human beings
and that we decide
our moral conduct
on the basis
of logic
let me prove
how wrong we are
the best investigation
and I'm not here
to talk about
cigarettes as being wrong
there's nothing
in the word of God
that says it's wrong
but I know
and you know
that men who have
gone into research
about cigarettes
and lungs
tell us
that the cigarette
smoker has a greater
incidence to lung cancer
it brings on
again emphysema
that there's no doubt
about it
there is a direct
connection
now that's what
medicine said
you would think
then if you and I
ran our life
on the basis
of our head
and not on emotion
that there would be
such a drop
in smoking cigarettes
that they'd almost
go out of business
and yet they're up
greater sales
in cigarettes
why
because
the greatest
scientist
who can put
astronauts
on the moon
who are so
scientific
can tell you
about a hole
in a cigarette
the point is
that you and I
don't decide
our moral way
of life
by the head
by logic
you and I
decided by
feeling
don't you ever
kid yourself
that you aren't
emotional
we smoke
because we like
it
we exempt
ourselves
the man that
turns to the world
he isn't logical
he is stupid
why
you can see it
with the guy
lying on the ground
when it comes home
to you and me
we are
like again
a little speck
of reason
in an ocean
of emotion
it's the heart
and the heart
again
you can't trust
it's feeling
and because of that
again
that's what God
says
we rush in
like a horse
unbridled into battle
and we ought to
realize
that the head
doesn't decide
in your case
and mine
nearly as much
as the heart
or the emotion
the way we feel
what do we care
about logic
or about reasoning
and thus again
we ought to realize
this
that you can't
predict
what you and I
will do
in these choices
when the world
beckons
God
says to Jeremiah
you tell the people
of Judah
that the stork
knows her season
talking about
migratory birds
you can predict
what a migratory bird
is going to do
when it comes
spring
the migratory bird
is going to go
one day way
and when it comes
fall
he's going to go
another
and that is
instinct
and he follows
that pattern
and you don't
stop him
but God
says
yes
they know
their seasons
but my people
do not know
the ordinances
of the Lord
you and I
are the most
unpredictable
beings
that God
has created
who knows
what you're
going to do
next
or I
in this matter
of moral
conduct
oh it's
simply
unpredictable
women were
at a bridge
club
one afternoon
just to show
you what
happens
and so they
decided
each one
would take
a paper
and pencil
and they
would decide
what would
you do
in this
case
you have
found out
that your
husband
has another
woman on
the string
now here's
the gun
you're going
to shoot
somebody
whom would
you shoot
rather strange
the answers
came
one woman
said she'd
shoot her
husband
and kill
him
another one
said she'd
kill the
other woman
another one
said no
she'd kill
herself
another one
said she'd
kill her
husband
and the
other woman
and then
kill herself
another one
said again
that she
would kill
those
and commit
suicide
for herself
or again
she would
just kill
the other
woman
there was
no rhyme
or reason
to the
answers
why
it's
thoroughly
unpredictable
that's why
one of you
said to me
you like
to be around
animals
more than
around
human beings
because you
can predict
what an
animal is
going to
do
I can
tell what
my dog
is going
to do
under
certain
circumstances
but you
and I
don't know
what we're
going to
do
because
the head
doesn't run
your life
or mine
nearly
like the
heart
how do
you feel
God
says it's
the height
of stupidity
is it
God says
when you
and I
turn away
from him
it's the
height
of stupidity
and you
and I
say well
I can
see when
this guy
is lying
down there
he's sure
a stupid
fool
not to
get up
but when
you hook
it up
it's pretty
nice down
there
I see
a lot
more fun
in serving
the world
a lot
more fun
in going
out for
worldly
pleasures
but
God
says
there's
more fun
and God
is convinced
of it
in following
Christ
and in
following
the world
do you
believe it
I think
in the
second place
God
reminds you
and me
that whenever
we follow
the world
we bring
sorrow
and we
bring
heartache
on others
I don't
I don't think
I ever
have a
funeral
when I
have
buried
somebody
who
has
thrown
his
life
away
that
somebody
from the
family
will come
up and say
it's too
bad about
so and so
rather sad
but he only
hurt himself
he only hurt
himself
there is no
bigger lie in all
the world
do you think
you and I
live in an
island
do you think
you and I
can live as
we please
and go to
the world
and drink
in everything
from A to
Z
without hurting
somebody else
since when
in this
society
life
when we
are so
inseparably
connected
with one
another
it is
impossible
for any
man
to go
to the
world
and to
live to
the world
without
hurting
deeply
somebody
they
love
when the
family is
broken up
talk to
the kids
who come
from broken
homes
something's
wrong
they're
marked
children
for the
rest of
their lives
why
God
never
intended
children
to be
raised in
a broken
home
but when
we turn
to the
world
and the
breaks up
our
home
what
happens
and then
how about
the
illegitimate
children
oh when
an illegitimate
child comes
yes
the mother
who isn't
married
can say
I love
my child
enough
that I'm
going to
put my
child out
for adoption
I'm going
to see
that my
child gets
a name
I'm going
to see
that my
child gets
a home
and a
father and
mother who
will love
my child
who will
give my
child an
opportunity
that is
good
and I
compliment you
for that
but is that
the end of
the story
is that
the end of
the story
I have
placed any
number of
adopted
children in
homes
and may I
testify to
you parents
with adopted
children
the love
and the joy
that you
have
and again
the care
that you
share
sometimes is
greater than
you'd ever
show on
your own
but what's
the other
side of
the story
when the
adopted
child comes
in to
see me
as a
young lady
did not
long ago
and says
did my
mother really
love me
so much
that she
gave me
away
was I
a child
of love
or was it
just plain
lust
was it
just this
that my
mother was
out on
a fling
and she
got tight
was that
all it
was
am I
nothing
who was
my mother
what kind
of a woman
was she
what was
my father
like
was my
mother a
tramp
I'd like
to know
what she's
like
if she
was a
tramp
then I'm
a tramp
then no
one cares
I'll throw
my life
away
and I don't
care how
I live
and I don't
care
what I
do
don't you
and I
ever kid
ourselves
that when
we turn
away from
Jesus Christ
and turn
to the world
we hurt
only ourselves
that's a
lie
that's
the lie
the age
more fun
in Jesus
Christ
the fun
what
of right
living
you may
say what
fun is
there in
right
living
and may
I just
say this
the word
of God
says
that right
living is
joyful
living
the beauty
of holiness
I wonder
if you
and I
don't forget
this
and maybe
that's
the fault
of the
pulpit
that when
we think
of Jesus
and his
sufferings
on the
cross
we forget
that his
was the
happiest
life
that was
ever lived
don't forget
that
the grandest
the happiest
the most
joyous
effervescing
life
that was
ever lived
was that
of Jesus
of Nazareth
in spite
of the cross
why
because it
was a
holy life
John Milton
says
virtue has
its own
reward
in other
words
he says
the joy
of right
living
is right
and only
those who
live right
experience
the joy
of peace
in Jesus
Christ
if Christ
was the
happiest
life
then there
is more
happiness
in following
Jesus
Christ
than in
any fun
that the
world may
offer
that is only
temporary
you know
sometimes we
may say to
ourselves
why is it
wrong right
why didn't
God make
wrong right
so we can
go out
and live to
the world
and drink
in immorality
in drunkenness
and go out
and take
the trip
and go out
like a horse
that rides
unbridled
in the battle
why can't
we do that
why didn't
he do it
didn't God
want us to
have a good
time
I think the
first thing
we've got to
say is this
God is holy
and God
says that's
the happiest
life
but we forget
something about
sin we forget
that sin is not
only an offense
against God
but it's got a
sinfulness
connected with it
we forget the
sinfulness of sin
that sin brings
the result
that whenever
wrong is done
it isn't only
a wrong done
but it has
results
and it brings
sorrow
heartache
and it makes
people say
why was I
ever born
when innocent
people suffer
when we live
for the world
and when you
and I believe
that God says
listen
the man that
turns away
from Jesus
Christ and
lives to the
world because
there's more
fun
is stupid
just as foolish
and stupid
and insane
he's lost
what little
he's got
just as stupid
as the man
that falls
down and
doesn't have
sense enough
to get up
when he falls
down
or the man
that's on
the wrong
road that
doesn't have
sense enough
to get to
the right
road
God Almighty
assures you
and me
again
that there's
more fun
in following
Christ
and we say
is there
because in
the third
place
let's know
this
that God
reminds you
and me
that when
we live
for the
world
there comes
a dread
of God
and the
judgment
don't kid
yourself
the man
that has
sown his
life to
the world
who has
turned his
back on
Jesus Christ
and God
calls and
refuses to
go back
when again
the years
come and the
years roll
and he sees
the regret
that has
come
and the
sorrow that
his life
has brought
to himself
and to
others that
he's loved
he's afraid
to die
that's why
oh sometimes
there's a
braggadocia
that's the
guy that
says
oh when
I die
bury me
in a
Jewish
cemetery
it's the
last place
God will
look for
me
ha ha ha
that's
supposed to
be funny
you know
yeah God
will find
or the
fellow says
I want
my body
cremated
there may
be a lot
of legitimate
reasons for
cremation
but many a
man wants
it burned
up to
dust
hoping that
God won't
have the
power to
put it
back together
again
how stupid
can we
get
to be
afraid
and to
dread
the
judgment
day
and in
contrast
to that
following
Christ
to have
him as
our
companionship
and then
to know
that there
is an
eternity
in the
fullness
of joy
in heaven
awaiting
us
people say
what will
heaven be
like
heaven
will be
holiness
and some
say oh
shoot
who wants
to go
to heaven
if it's
going to
be holiness
but heaven
is fullness
of joy
what that
means I
don't know
except I
know this
what that
joy is going
to be like
but in heaven
with Christ
who has gone
to prepare a
place for us
it means joy
to the very
nth degree
it means no
craving for
anything but
what it will be
satisfied
it will be
the absolute
joy
it must be
wonderful
although God
can't even
describe it in
human language
because my
Lord came
into the
world and
died on
the cross
so that I
might have
that fullness
of joy
he rose from
the dead to
assure me
that he had
bought it
for me
and he
gloriously
returned to
heaven and
he prepares
a place for
you and
for me
and for all
who love
him it
must be
tremendous
and oh
to God
that you
and I
would just
not be
so stupid
as again
to say that
it can't be
joy and to
miss it
I don't want
to miss it
fullness of
joy to me
that's worth
waiting for
which simply
means this
bringing it
right down
in your pew
and right up
here into
you who are
listening
when God
says if we
have turned
away and we
refuse to
repent we
are as stupid
as a man
that falls
down who
isn't hurt
and refuses
to get up
God says
again why
don't you
repent and
why don't
you come
back
perhaps some
of us would
say I'd
like to go
back to
Jesus Christ
I'd like to
repent and
return to him
I've had
enough of
this
I found
out that
it isn't
all is not
gold that
glitters
and we may
say but what
kind of a
reception do
you get from
heaven
we may say
to ourselves
yeah I'll go
back and God
says what
time what
time you're
coming back
I thought you
would I
thought you'd
go out and
live your life
the way you
want to live
and then you
come back
expect me to
take you back
and you and
I may say
I don't want
that kind of
a reception
don't you know
what kind of a
reception you and
I get when we
come back
Jesus told a
story once
there's no
secret
as to the
kind of reception
Jesus told a
story about a
younger man you
know that went
away from home
and he went
out and boy he
lived it up there
wasn't anything
that he hadn't
done
just like the
mother that
came in and
told me about
her 14 year old
girl she said
Reverend
Hansen my
daughter's 14
years old and
there isn't
anything she
hasn't done
she's run the
gamut of sin
from one end
to the other
you can't name
it imagine
14 years
old 14
years old
everything that
was wrong
this young
son of this
father went
out and did
the same
and then finally
he got to the
end of his
robe didn't
he and
everything was
gone and
this longing
and this
yearning there
was no more
fun in anything
and he decided
to go home
and he wondered
too what kind
of reception
will I get
will my
father say
why don't you
stay home
like your
older brother
then you'd
amounted to
something
now you're
coming back
you've spent
everything that
I gave
you
why don't
he says
I'm going
home
I don't
know what
I'm going
to get
I'll not
plead that
I want to
be a son
again if
you just
let me be
a servant
but he
didn't know
started back
remember
and oh
God when he
started back
remember that
there was a
father waiting
the father
saw him
before he
ever saw
the father
there was a
father out
looking
and he saw
some in the
distance
and the
father said
I believe
that's my
boy
I think
it is
it looks
like
oh he's
dirty
and he's
I believe
that's
my son
and he
went on
it is
and he ran
and he
threw his
arms around
that boy
and he
said
oh my
son that
was
lost
is found
my son
that was
dead
is alive
again
you know
that boy
he wondered
what kind
of reception
he never
got it out
of his
mouth
he never
said
father
I'm not
worthy
to be
your son
just make
me a
hired
he never
got that
out
father said
come on
we're going
to give
you a bath
we're going
to put
on a
clean
roll
we're going
to put
a ring
on your
finger
we're going
to kill
the fat
at death
that was
the reception
if you want
to make
heaven happy
when you
and I
think we're
at the end
of the line
we say
this isn't
fun
this is
hell
I'm going
back to
Jesus
oh what
a reception
the bells
of heaven
ring
there's no
secret as
to the
reception
you see
it is
no secret
what God
can do
what he's
done for
others
he'll do
for you
with arms
wide open
he'll
pardon you
it is
no secret
what God
can do
if we
have
fallen
shall we
not
rise
again
let's
don't be
stupid
it's
no secret
what God
will do
amen