Grace be unto you, and peace from God our Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Let us hear the word of God as we find it written back in the Old Testament.
In the book of Psalms, the 110th Psalm, beginning at the first verse.
The Lord said unto my Lord, Sit thou at my right hand, until I make thine enemies thy footstool.
The Lord shall send the rod of thy strength out of Zion, rule thou in the midst of thine enemies.
Thy people shall be willing in the day of thy power.
In the beauties of holiness from the womb of the morning, thou hast the dew of thy youth.
The Lord hath sworn, and will not repent, thou art a priest forever, after the order of Melchizedek.
And now may the words of my mouth, and the meditations of our hearts, be acceptable in thy sight.
O Lord, our strength, and our Redeemer. Amen.
Good morning, dear friends in Christ Jesus, you who are here in God's house, and you also of our radio audience.
It is good to have you in God's house this morning.
It is fine, radio friends, to have you worshiping with us also.
I assume that all of you have fought and have won the battle of the change of time, and you are here in God's house today.
If you glanced at your calendar for this week, you noticed that this coming Thursday, May the 4th,
is marked on your church calendar as Ascension Day.
It is the 40th day after Easter.
You may say to yourself, what does it mean, Ascension Day?
Well, Jesus arose on Easter, as we know, and in this 40-day period, from Easter to Ascension,
he showed himself alive to his followers, convincing them beyond the shadow of a doubt that he who died was alive again.
And they went out and they gave their lives for him, because they knew that he was alive.
On Easter Sunday, you recall, he appeared to Mary Magdalene.
She saw him alive, then the other women.
And in the afternoon, the two disciples on the way to Emmaus saw him and spoke of them.
There was a private appearance to Peter that afternoon.
That night, Jesus appeared, Easter Sunday night, to the disciples when Thomas was not present.
The following Sunday night, you remember, he appeared when Thomas was present, that Thomas got to see him.
Then the disciples went up into Galilee, and there they had fished one night, and early one morning, Christ was on the shore.
Seven of them were fishing, and they came to the shore, as you recall,
ate breakfast with the living Christ when Peter was reinstated into the Apostolate.
Then there was another great appearance of Jesus on a mountaintop in Galilee,
and he had told them about that prior to his death, that they were to meet him there.
Paul mentions that about 500 gathered together at one place.
Evidently, this was it, when about 500 followers plus the Apostles saw the living Christ
when he gave the great missionary command to go out and make disciples of all nations.
Then there was a private appearance to his brother James, of which we know nothing except the fact.
Then on the 40th day after Easter, on Ascension Day, Jesus made his last appearance to the 11th.
They walked up the slope of the Mount of Olives, past the Garden of Gethsemane,
and when they came to the top of the Mount of Olives, and Bethany was there right in the brief distance,
Jesus raised his hands and began to bless them, and as he did, something happened.
He started to go up, and the 11th stood there, and they looked up, and they gazed into heaven,
watching him as he was going up, and a cloud finally received him out of their sight.
And when that happened, there were two men standing by them in white apparel,
two angels that said, Ye men of Galilee, why are you standing, gazing into heaven?
That same Jesus that you have seen go into heaven is going to come in the same way someday.
He's going to return.
And we may say to ourselves, well, what did it mean?
He went back to heaven.
The text that I read in the Old Testament, by inspiration of God, David wrote it,
and he said, The Lord said unto my Lord, Sit thou at my right hand.
David, who lived a thousand years before Christ, understood the ascension.
These words of the 110th Psalm apply to Jesus,
because Jesus in his earthly ministry applied them to himself.
David said a thousand years before ascension, The Lord said unto my Lord,
In other words, My God said unto my Lord, the Messiah, my Son, that would come from me.
God the Father said to God the Son, Sit thou at my right hand.
David saw it in prophecy.
Therefore on the ascension day, what a tremendous thing that must have been.
Jesus had finished his work on earth.
He goes to heaven, and there 10,000 times 10,000 angels, 100 million angels,
and the saints of God, they greeted him.
And God the Father said, Son, sit at my right hand.
God the Father never became a human being.
He has no right hand.
Therefore, this is an expression that means the place of honor.
In other words, God the Father said to Jesus on ascension day,
Son, sit at my right hand.
Sit at the highest place of honor in heaven.
Occupy the greatest, highest place of glory.
The grand place of distinction.
Sit there, my son.
This is reserved for you.
What a tremendous homecoming.
And you and I may say, what does it all mean?
That he sits in the highest place of honor in heaven?
Why, it ought to be a source of comfort.
It ought to be a source of courage.
It ought to be a source of joy for you and me.
It ought to be a real spiritual shot in the arm, if there ever is anything that should give it to us.
We say, ascension, a spiritual shot in the arm.
Jesus seated at the right hand of God.
Seated in the highest place of honor.
But we may say to ourselves, but, oh, it's hard to feel that it's a spiritual shot for me.
That it's a source of courage for me in this world.
I feel that it's sort of a forsakenness.
That when he went to heaven, that he left me behind.
That he's forsaken me.
I feel sort of abandoned in this world of sin.
Since he returned to heaven, and he is seated in the highest place of honor.
But Christian friends, ascension ought to be a spiritual shot in the arm for you and me.
The fact that our Christ sits at the right hand of God.
Because it wasn't an abandonment.
It wasn't a leaving you and me behind.
It wasn't a brush off.
He is seated in that highest place of honor.
And his greatest concern is you and me.
Do you realize that seated in that place of glory,
that Christ's greatest concern is you.
That he has the greatest concern for you as though you were the only one living on the face of the earth.
But he has an equal concern for me.
And for all of his children.
As though we were the only ones that he had to be concerned about.
That's the spiritual shot in the arm.
Because seated at the right hand of majesty,
he has you and me in his heart.
Oh, what a thrilling thing it ought to be to know that our Christ has as his chief concern,
his chief interest, his chief care.
You and me.
We may say to ourselves, does he?
Why, in the first place, let's know this.
Christ, the God-man, he's seated at the right hand of God as our king.
David saw it in prophecy and he said,
The Lord said unto my Lord,
Sit thou at my right hand,
and shall I make thine enemies thy footstube.
The Lord shall send the rod of strength out of Zion.
Rule thou in the midst of thine enemies.
Christ came into the world, didn't he, to be a king.
And it was to be a kingdom far different than any kingdom the world had ever known previously.
Recall, he said to Pontius Pilate,
My kingdom is not of this world.
Don't think of my kingdom as a worldly kingdom, Pilate.
He said,
Else would my soldiers fight.
At one other time, he says,
The kingdom of God doesn't come with observation.
You can't say,
There it is,
or here it is.
He says,
The kingdom of God is within you.
And you and I say,
Well, if he came to be the king of a kingdom,
what kind of a kingdom is it?
Every Sunday in church,
when we say the Apostles' Creed,
we say,
I believe in the Holy Christian Church,
the communion of saints.
That's the kingdom.
In other words,
we say,
I believe that there exists in this world,
even though I can't see it with my naked eye,
the kingdom of God,
the Holy Christian Church,
the communion of saints.
What is this kingdom?
This kingdom is the kingdom that exists right now here on earth,
that is made up of every true believer in Jesus Christ as Lord and Savior.
It makes no difference what your denominational handle may be.
Whether you are a Lutheran or a Roman Catholic or a Methodist or a Baptist or an Episcopalian,
if you have come to a living faith in Jesus Christ as your Lord and your Savior,
you are a member of the kingdom of the saved.
That's the kingdom,
tremendous,
wonderful,
that your king and mine came to establish.
And when the kingdom was established,
the kingdom of the saved,
the kingdom of those who have come to faith in him,
he went to heaven,
seated at the right hand of God,
and he still serves as king.
In the power that is his,
he watches that there is no power on earth or under the earth,
no power of Satan,
no power of the fallen angels,
that can never be so great that it can destroy that kingdom.
That kingdom is an invincible and eternal kingdom.
And therefore,
as he sits as our king,
when you and I pray to him,
he, the God-man,
guarantees you and me
that will never be kidnapped
from that kingdom.
Today is also Rogation Sunday,
or Rogate,
prayer Sunday.
And as you and I pray to him
who is seated in the throne of majesty on high,
there comes this guarantee,
because he is king.
No power shall ever
kidnap you and me
from the kingdom of God.
Even though you and I are unconscious,
even though you and I
are in the weakness of body,
may not be able to collect our thoughts,
Satan shall never,
never be able to have the power
to snatch you and me
from Jesus Christ,
to kidnap us against our will.
There will never come a time
when the powers of hell
can never rescue you and me
from Jesus Christ.
He sits and rules
in the midst of his enemies.
And as the Oriental potentate,
when he would conquer a king,
would have that king get down
and put his foot on his neck
or his head,
Jesus as king,
he rules in the midst
of his enemies.
And as David said,
the Lord said unto my Lord,
sit thou at my right hand
and tell them,
make thine enemies thy footstool.
The enemies of the kingdom of God
are the footstool of Jesus Christ,
given evidence from the fact
that the kingdom of God
still stands
and it will remain forever and ever.
You and I may say to ourselves,
what about those in Vietnam?
Will they ever torture my son?
And can he be kidnapped
from the kingdom of God?
Can again adversity
and troubles come
that will be so great
that they can pluck my child,
my son, my husband, my daughter
from the kingdom of God?
No!
That will never happen.
Oh, if you and I could only live
in the spirit of the ascension,
to know that it isn't abandonment,
it isn't this,
that he left us to ourselves,
he is seated at the right hand of God.
What a spiritual treat
and what a spiritual shot
in the arm it ought to be.
You are his chief concern,
as though you were the only one alive
on earth and so am I.
Each individual in his kingdom
is his chief concern
and if we lived in the light
of the ascension,
then we would pray with boldness
and with confidence
and with enthusiasm
and we would put tomorrow
into his hands.
We may shiver and be afraid
of tomorrow
and wonder what is coming,
but Paul knew this,
that because Christ rules as king,
he was able to say,
for I reckon and I know this
and I am convinced
that neither death nor life
nor angels nor principalities
nor powers
nor things present
nor things to come
nor height nor depth
nor any other creature
shall be able to separate us
from the love of God
which is in Christ Jesus.
And you and I can say it too.
Nothing will snatch you and me
from the kingdom of God
because seated at the right hand
of God is again
our Christ as king,
the God-man.
You know when he went to heaven
on Good Friday afternoon
in death,
his body stayed here.
But when he went to heaven
on the ascension,
he took his body with him
and I love to think of him
as a man on the throne
as well as God.
He says,
I know it's tough down there.
I spent 33 years on earth.
I know what adversity means.
I sat where you sat.
I know what troubles mean
and I know what powers
militate against you
and because he's a man,
he understands.
You and I have a man
on the throne,
seated in the grandest
and the most glorious place
in heaven.
You and I are the apple
of his eye.
He is seated there
and he has you and me
in his heart.
Oh, to live in the light
of the ascension.
Jesus Christ again,
seated at the right hand
of God,
said David.
The Lord said unto my Lord,
sit thou at my right hand.
Oh, the place of honor,
the place of distinction,
the highest place
of glory in heaven.
And again,
seated there,
you and I,
ought to find
a tremendous spiritual shot
in the arm
because you are
his greatest concern
and so am I.
Oh, that's true
because Christ,
the God-man,
is seated at the right hand
of God
also as our priest.
He came into the world
not only to be a king
but he came to be a priest too.
You and I may say
he came as a high priest.
He was a different kind
of a priest.
He was not from
the family of Aaron.
Aaron's family gave
the high priest
but Jesus was not
a descendant of Aaron.
Aaron was a Levite
and the Levite
furnished the priest.
Christ was from
the tribe of Judah
and Judah had no priest.
The priest didn't come
from the tribe of Judah.
He was to be different
but he came into the world
and he was a different priest.
Aaron and all
the Old Testament
high priests,
they offered
for the sins of the world
the blood of goats
and the blood of lambs.
They offered animals
but one great priest
came into the world,
our high priest,
and he offered
not the blood of goats
and of lambs
but his own blood.
John the Baptist
you recall
looked at him
and pointed one day
behold the Lamb of God.
Christ the Lamb of God
our high priest
became the sacrifice
and he as the Lamb of God
at Calvary
did something tremendous
for you and me
on earth.
It was by that
sufferings and death
that he met the justice
of his heavenly Father.
He took on himself
our guilt
and our punishment
and he bore
the equal of an eternity
in hell
for you and me.
He bore an exemption ticket
from hell
for you and for me.
Do you know
of any greater concern
than one that would do that?
And he scored
and earned
an admission ticket
to heaven
for you and me
and for all men.
He is the Lamb of God
who bore it
in his own flesh
upon the cross.
That's what he did
and now that he is in heaven
we are assured
that he sits
in the highest place
of honor
as our high priest
and David said
God has said
I have sworn
and I will not repent
thou art a priest
forever after
the order of Melchizedek
and you say
what did David mean by that?
A thousand years
before David lived
about two thousand years
before Christ
Abraham lived
and you remember
when Abraham left
the land of Ur
or the Chaldees
and he came over
into the land of Canaan.
In the land of Canaan
people had forgotten
anything about
the true God
it was heathenism
at its worst
but when he got
into the land of Canaan
one day
in the ancient city
of Jerusalem
the city of Salem
he met a man
by the name
of Melchizedek
and Melchizedek
was a priest
and king
of the most high God.
How Melchizedek
ever knew about God
and became a priest
and king
of the living God
nobody knows
there is no genealogy
given as regards
Melchizedek
we're not told
where he was born
or when
we are not told
about his death
and Melchizedek
becomes a symbol
of an eternal priesthood
and therefore again
just as he is a symbol
of an endless priesthood
your Christ and mine
seated at the right hand
of God
is an eternal priest
like Melchizedek
which in simple language
means this
his sacrifice
will never run out
the time will never come
that God will say
I'm sorry
I've got to throw
everybody out of heaven
because the sacrifice
of my son
ran out
with its efficacy
the time will never come
that God will say
no more sinners
can come into the kingdom
and come to life eternal
because the efficacy
of the Lamb of God
in his suffering
has run out
he is a priest forever
talk about a shot
in the arm
and that means
that when you and I
pray to this God man
as our high priest
he gladly
and willingly
and enthusiastically
forgives you and me
our sins every day
oh to go to this king
and to this high priest
who sits on the throne
and to go to him
every day
and confess our sins
of ignorance
he says
oh thank you for coming
I'm glad to forgive you
when you and I
go to him every day
in prayer
and say my sins
of weakness
these are the things
I didn't want to do
but I did them anyhow
they are gladly forgiven
and he says
thank you for coming
I'm so glad to forgive you
and take your guilt
and your punishment away
it is all a privilege
he tells you
I'd rather forgive you
than eat
and if we come to him
with our sin again
of willfulness
where we have gone
against him
and we know better
and we are out of grace
and we go in
asking for forgiveness
he thanks us
for coming
and saying
thank you
I am glad to forgive you
and to reinstate you
and if you and I
have wandered away
from him for a long time
if we have persisted
in deliberate sin
if we have left him
and dethroned him
then we come back
we may say
what kind of a reception
do we get
why this king
that sits at the right hand
of God
is also our priest
and he says
I've been praying
for you
that you'd come back
I've been asking
the father
to keep giving you life
and not to take your life
and thank God
you're back
and gladly
and willingly
I forgive you
and I reinstate you
that's what ascension means
and if you and I
would say
today I'm going to live
in the light
of the ascension
I'm going to live
in the light
that the God man
there's a man
on the throne
and he is seated
in the place
of highest honor
and distinction
in heaven
and he has me
in his heart
I am his greatest
concern
and so is everyone
else
his greatest concern
if we lived in the light
of the ascension
then we would pray
with boldness
and confidence
and with enthusiasm
and we would go to him
again
if we're ashamed
of yesterday
how many of us
simply look back
at yesterday
again
at some sin
and we say to ourselves
I've gone to the throne
of grace
hundreds of times
and I've asked
for forgiveness
and then adversity comes
and then we plague
ourselves in addition
by saying
I'm being punished
I know I'm being punished
for something that I've done
not only do you have
the sickness
or the adversity
but that horrible
guilty conscience
where we condemn ourselves
and we say
I'm being punished
but when we turn
to this great one
at the throne of grace
who is our high priest
and you and I say
forgive me this thing
that haunts my memory
when we have been there
before Jesus
says to you and me
you must be
what are you talking about
I don't know
what sin you're talking about
oh you brought that sin
to me long ago
and repented
and I drowned it
in the depths of the sea
don't you remember
I took it away from you
as far as the east
is from the west
I have blotted it out
off of your record
I don't even remember it
you'll have to tell me
about it
I have blotted it eternally
from my mind
that's the kind of a Christ
then he says
if you think you're being
punished for sin
you're not
that's my love
how could I punish you
for a sin
that I have obliterated
from my mind eternally
because I remember
your sins no more
and when we can come
to the throne of grace
and have a Christ like that
then he says
don't you want the joy
of starting to forgive yourselves
or if we just start
to forgive ourselves
when he has long ago
forgiven us
and obliterated
even the memory of it
from his mind
oh what joy
there could be
and enthusiasm
in your life
and mine
if we lived in the light
of the ascension
our Christ
yes
he is seated
at the right hand
of God
David saw him
his Lord
and his son
and Jesus
quoted those words
he was talking about
the Messiah
and because
this Christ
is seated
at the right hand
of God
he is seated there
not only as our king
not only as our high priest
but also as our prophet
he came into the world
did he not
became flesh
to be a prophet
to be a teacher
and oh what a teacher
he was
he came into the world
not only to teach us
right and wrong
but you know
one day he said
to the world
I am the light
of the world
by that he meant this
did you ever realize
he meant
I am the one
that brings light
into the world
if I didn't come
the world would never
have light
the light of life
in other words
in me there is
eternal life
and without me
there isn't
everything is hopelessness
everything is lost
everything is darkness
forever and ever
that's what he taught
he taught men
that he was the light
of the world
then he went to heaven
and he is still
serving as our prophet
he went to heaven
and he moved men
to write down
what he had said
you have Matthew
Mark Luke and John
who have given us
the memoirs
of the life of Jesus
that you and I
know what he taught
he moved men
not only to write
the gospels
Matthew Mark Luke and John
but we have Acts
and Romans
and 1st and 2nd Corinthians
and Galatians
and Ephesians
and Philippians
and Colossians
and 1st and 2nd Thessalonians
and 1st and 2nd Timothy
and Titus
and Philemon
and Hebrews
and James
and 1st and 2nd Peter
and 1st and 2nd 3rd John
and Jude
and Revelation
that's the written word
and he is still protecting it
as a teacher
with the translations
that are coming out
you know it's tremendous
no age
has ever seen
the translations
of the word of God
that our age is seeing
men attempting
to make Christ
speak 20th century English
no longer can anybody
in the sound of my voice
this morning
never say
I don't read the scriptures
because I can't understand them
oh yes you can
if you can read and write
you can understand
some of the new translations
of the New Testament
they're right down your throat
he is the prophet
on the throne
and that prophet
assures you and me
that when we pray to him
for a stronger faith
in his word
that he's coming again
and that when he comes again
that will be an end
of every adversity
and of everything
that troubles us
oh the men
stood there of Galilee
gazing into heaven
and they were told
he's coming back
and in the word of God
he says
I'm coming back
and when I come back
all the adversities
and the troubles
that sometimes
make life so miserable
they're going to come to an end
that which is eternal
shall be joy
and when we have
that assurance
when we turn to him
the assurance in his word
is coming back
this Christ
who will sit
at the right hand of God
it's not been a brush off
it's not been an abandonment
it's not a forsakenness
oh what a spiritual
shot in the arm
to live in the light
of the ascension
and when you and I
can live in the light of it
knowing again
the worthy apple of his eye
that you and I
are his greatest concern
as though he had
no one else to care about
except you
as though he had
no one else in the world
to care about
except me
with that concern
having us in his heart
when you and I
can realize that
then if we're living
in the light of the ascension
we will want to share
this Christ
with those who feel
abandoned
left behind
with those who feel
so forsaken
we said
what's wrong
in this world
we seem to be
coming apart
at the seams
especially on our
college campuses
what's wrong
men burning draft cards
rioting
again
college students
turning away
from
everything that you and I
seemingly think
is worthwhile
this unrest
what's wrong
on the campus
Dr. Joyce
brothers
I think you have
probably seen her
on television
a noted psychologist
made a study
of college students
and it's rather
revealing
she tells us this
the second largest
cause of death
among college students
can you imagine
what it is
the first largest
cause of death
among college students
is accidents
the greater number
of college students
that die
die by accident
34%
of college students
that die
that's one
in every three
college students
that die
Dr. Joyce
brothers
tells us
they die
by taking
their own life
suicide
one out of
three
college students
die by their own
hand
of those
that die
34%
you know
we've been
worshipping
at the shrine
of science
haven't we
we are learning
that Christ
is right
that man
doesn't live
by bread alone
our college
students
without Jesus
Christ
may know
a lot of
things
but without
Jesus Christ
there comes
that feeling
of abandonment
that's what's
wrong with them
that feeling
of forsakenness
why am I alive
who wants
to be alive
for this kind
of a world
it's time
to get off
we are told
that 90,000
college students
every year
threaten suicide
there will be
1,000 suicides
amongst college
students this year
one in ten
of the 90,000
actually
attempted
and tried
to
carry it
out
man doesn't
live by
bread alone
if there's
ever a need
for Jesus
Christ
parents
it's now
there lives
in this
seven county
area of
Marion County
there lives
a woman
who
one Sunday
morning
was alone
in her kitchen
she pulled
down the
shades
she walked
over to
her gas
stove
and she
turned on
the raw
gas
it so
happened
by the
providence
of God
that on
that Sunday
morning
her radio
was on
and it
happened to be
on for
WMRN
and by the
providence of God
Emmanuel Lutheran
Church
happened to be
on
and the
preacher at
Emmanuel Lutheran
Church
that morning
by the
providence
of God
was talking
about
suicide
and the
feeling of
abandonment
and uselessness
and that
in Christ
Jesus
every man
is precious
and every man
is useful
she had
the radio
on
just to
break up
the loneliness
and we
happened
into that
kitchen
that morning
men
sobbing
and in
weeping
she got
up
and decided
that one
or the
other
had to be
turned off
and she
walked over
to the
gas stove
thank God
and she
turned off
the gas
stove
because
from the
little radio
there had
come the
message
that
all men
in the
sight of
Jesus
Christ
are precious
there's no
need for
hopelessness
a sense
of abandonment
she thanked
me later
that the
word of
God
came in
does it
pay to
share
the
ascended
Lord
our
king
high
priest
our
prophet
oh
when you
think the
world is
down
and you
think
there's
no reason
for living
why don't
you come
early to
church
and just
sit and
look at
these windows
they're
priceless
there aren't
any finer
stained glass
windows in
this part of
the country
believe me
they're not
excelled in
any church
in this
community
you can
just sit
down with
your thoughts
and there
he is
this king
concerned
about you
no one
will ever
kidnap you
against your
will
the middle
window
there he is
as your
great high
priest
assuring you
that when
you call
on him
he's just
tickled to
death
to forgive
you
and to
claim you
as his
own
and here
he is
as
prophet
assuring
you
hold on
son
I'm
coming
again
and when
I come
again
it's going
to be
the end
of all
suffering
oh no
adversity
is ever
going to
come
in your
life and
mine
even though
that boy
may be
tortured
on
Vietnam
no
adversity
don't you
ever believe
otherwise
will ever
come
that will
snatch
your loved
one
away from
Jesus
Christ
against
his will
it just
won't
happen
because
there's
a God
man
on the
throne
a man
who's
been
through
the mill
who's
been
through
it all
who
understands
who says
I've got
you in
my heart
can't we
go out
of church
on the
festival
of the
ascension
and walk
the glory
road
with joy
and sing
again
to this
Jesus
he leadeth
me
oh
blessed
thought
oh
words
with
heavenly
comfort
fraught
whate'er
I do
where
e'er
I be
still
tis
God's
hand
that
leadeth
me
he leadeth
by his
own
hand
he leadeth
me
his faithful
follower
I will
be
for by
his hand
he leadeth
me
yes he
does
let's
let him
lead
let's go
on
enthusiastically
because
he is
seated
at the
right hand
of God
in the
place of
honor
you are
his
greatest
concern
and so
am I
he has
you and
me
in his
heart
that's
ascension
a lord
worth
knowing
amen
the peace
of God
which passeth
all human
understanding
keep and
unite your
hearts and
minds in
Christ Jesus
unto life
everlasting
speech
the peace
sea
the embaixo
of the
universe
and
peace